	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Alessandro_Volta  Count Alessandro Giuseppe Antonio Anastasio Volta (February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827) was an Italian physicist known especially for the development of the first known electric battery in 1800.   

How much of the population is of white European descent?	Approximately 88% of its population are of prevalently white European descent.	S08/data/set2/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'more than 5000', u'CARDINAL'], [u'10000', u'CARDINAL']]
The population is estimated at no more than 5000 to 10000.

What is the largest ethnic minority in Romania?	Hungarians	S08/data/set2/a7

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Romania', u'GPE'], [u'Romania', u'GPE'], [u'Southeastern Europe', u'LOC']]
Romania  Romania ( , ) is a country in Southeastern Europe.

Who also discovered that less than three percent of kangaroos exposed to the virus developed blindness ?	Veterinarians	S08/data/set1/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'less than three', u'CARDINAL']]
Veterinarians also discovered that less than three percent of kangaroos exposed to the virus developed blindness.  

What may be called Volta's Law of the electrochemical series?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u"Volta's Law", u'LAW']]
This may be called Volta's Law of the electrochemical series.

Why are penguins countershaded?	for camouflage	S08/data/set1/a3

All penguins are countershaded - that is, they have a white underside and a dark (mostly black) upperside.

Do female polar bears weight more than the male?	No	S08/data/set1/a4

yes

How much weight do female polar bears gain during pregnancy?	They double their weight during pregnancy	S08/data/set1/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: []
What You Can Do to Protect Polar Bears"

What caused Wilson to ask Congress to declare war on the Central Powers?	World War I	S08/data/set3/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Congress', u'ORG'], [u'the Central Powers', u'LOC']]
Subsequently he asked Congress to declare war on the Central Powers.

What happened with a bromide emulsion in two sheets of very thick black paper?	the plate does not become clouded upon being exposed to the sun for a day	S08/data/set4/a9

re photographic plate

What is the poulation of Egypt?	78 million people	S08/data/set2/a6

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Egypt', u'GPE'], [u'Egypt', u'GPE'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Kemet', u'PERSON'], [u'Coptic', u'NORP'], [u'  ', u'ORG'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Arab Republic', u'ORG'], [u'North Africa', u'GPE'], [u'the Sinai Peninsula', u'LOC'], [u'Asia', u'LOC']]
Egypt  Egypt (Egyptian: Kemet; Coptic:  Kīmi;   ; Egyptian Arabic: ), officially the Arab Republic of Egypt, is a country in North Africa that includes the Sinai Peninsula, a land bridge to Asia.

Where did the expression "a sitting duck" come from?	In many areas, wild ducks of various species (including ducks farmed and released into the wild) are hunted for food or sport, by shooting, or formerly by decoys.	S08/data/set1/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: []
From this came the expression "a sitting duck", which means "an easy target".

When did he die?	1908 	S08/data/set3/a6

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Grover Cleveland', u'PERSON'], [u'Stephen Grover', u'PERSON'], [u'Cleveland', u'GPE'], [u'March 18 1837', u'DATE'], [u'June 24 1908', u'DATE'], [u'the twenty-second and', u'DATE'], [u'twenty-fourth', u'DATE'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1885 1889 and 1893 1897', u'DATE']]

What happened in 1867?	Canada was formed as a federal, semi-autonomous polity	S08/data/set2/a8

Canada  Canada ( ) is a country occupying most of northern North America, extending from the Atlantic Ocean in the east to the Pacific Ocean in the west and northward into the Arctic Ocean.

Have there been other US presidents that have visited Cuba?	no	S08/data/set3/a9

QUESTION TYPE: 4
His most publicized veto was of a bill that would have increased legislators' pay by 50%.

What is a collective noun for kangaroos?	Mob, troop, or court	S08/data/set1/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: []
The collective noun for kangaroos is a mob, troop, or court.

What Roman province was Liechtenstein part of?	Raetia	S08/data/set2/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u"Vaduz Liechtenstein's", u'GPE'], [u'October 1921', u'DATE']]
The Government building in Vaduz Liechtenstein's current constitution was adopted in October 1921.

What happened from black river academy , vermont?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

Greenberg, 1–7  John Calvin Coolidge Jr. was born in Plymouth, Windsor County, Vermont, on July 4 1872, the only U.S. President to be born on the fourth of July.

In what ways was Adams opposed by Anderw Hamilton?	Hamilton wanted to control the army differently than Adams	S08/data/set3/a1

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Adams was forced to name Washington as commander of the new army, and Washington demanded that Hamilton be given the second position.

Can women legally drive in Qatar?	yes	S08/data/set2/a3

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Women can legally drive in Qatar, whereas they may not in Saudi Arabia.

What is Finland's economy like?	a highly industrialised, free-market economy	S08/data/set2/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]
Finland  Finland, officially the Republic of Finland "Republic of Finland", or "Suomen tasavalta" in Finnish and "Republiken Finland" in Swedish, is the long protocol name, which is not defined by the law.

Where was James Monroe born?	Westmoreland County, Virginia	S08/data/set3/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Westmoreland County', u'GPE'], [u'Virginia', u'GPE'], [u'Monroe', u'PERSON'], [u'Campbelltown Academy', u'ORG'], [u'the College of William', u'ORG'], [u'Virginia', u'GPE']]
. Born in Westmoreland County, Virginia, Monroe went to school at Campbelltown Academy and then the College of William and Mary, both in Virginia.

When was the first photgraph of lincoln taken?	1846	S08/data/set3/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Rail Candidate', u'GPE'], [u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'1860', u'DATE'], [u'New York Tribune', u'ORG'], [u'Horace Greeley', u'PERSON'], [u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'February 27, 1860', u'DATE'], [u'New York City', u'GPE'], [u'Mathew Brady', u'PERSON'], [u'Cooper Union', u'ORG']]
The Rail Candidate," Lincoln's 1860 candidacy is held up by slavery issue (slave on left) and party organization (New York Tribune editor Horace Greeley on right) Photo of Lincoln taken February 27, 1860 in New York City by Mathew Brady, the day of his famous Cooper Union speech.

Who were the midnight judges?	They were judges formally appointed days before Adams term expired	S08/data/set3/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'John Adams', u'PERSON'], [u'October 30,1735', u'DATE'], [u'July 4, 1826', u'DATE'], [u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1797 1801', u'DATE']]
John_Adams  John Adams, Jr. (October 30,1735  July 4, 1826) was the second President of the United States (1797 1801).

Who is most noted for his contributions to the theory of molarity and molecular weight?	Amedeo Avogadro	S08/data/set4/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: []
He is most noted for his contributions to the theory of molarity and molecular weight.

Forward, erect ears and slightly bristle hackles are a sign of what in wolves?	Dominance	S08/data/set1/a6

QUESTION TYPE: 4
The ears are erect and forward, and the hackles bristle slightly.

Is Calvin Jr. older than John Coolidge?	No	S08/data/set3/a9

yes

What did Jefferson call John Adams?	Colossus of Independence	S08/data/set3/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Adams', u'ORG'], [u'the American Revolution', u'ORG'], [u'Massachusetts', u'GPE'], [u'1776', u'DATE'], [u'Jefferson', u'PERSON']]
Adams, a sponsor of the American Revolution in Massachusetts, was a driving force for independence in 1776; Jefferson called him the "Colossus of Independence".

Why did Roosevelt start Boxing lessons?	To deal with bullies	S08/data/set3/a7

To deal with bullies, Roosevelt started boxing lessons.

Had Monroe racked up many debts during his years of public life ?	yes	S08/data/set3/a2

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Monroe had racked up many debts during his years of public life.

How does a Mallard's tongue work?	It uses short spikes to push struggling prey and other food down its throat	S08/data/set1/a10

duck  Duck is the common name for a number of species in the Anatidae family of birds.

Does Romania share the same language with Moldova?	Practically	S08/data/set2/a7

yes

What has Uruguay done to be competitive in agriculture?	Use low inputs of labour, technology, and capital, which results in lower yields but also opens the door for Uruguay to market its products as "natural" or "ecological"	S08/data/set2/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'the Uruguay River', u'LOC'], [u'\xa1 River', u'LOC'], [u'Uruguay', u'ORG']]
To the southwest is the Río de la Plata, the estuary of the Uruguay River, which forms the western border, and the Paraná River, that does not run through Uruguay itself.   


ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Union', u'ORG'], [u'American', u'NORP'], [u'Civil War', u'EVENT']]
He achieved international fame as the leading Union general in the American Civil War.

What do most recognizable international company and largest employer have in common?	They are Hilti.	S08/data/set2/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'the last few years', u'DATE'], [u'European', u'NORP']]
They are still considered by many to be an easier touch than most, however, they have been steadily improving over the last few years, and are now considered the best of the European "minnows".

Is the Asian elephant larger than the African?	Sometimes	S08/data/set1/a5

yes

How do reservoirs and water relate?	By 2001, there were 19 raw water reservoirs, 9 treatment works and 14 storage or service reservoirs locally to serve domestic needs. 	S08/data/set2/a2


When did James Monroe introduce the Monroe Doctrine?	December 2, 1823	S08/data/set3/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'James Monroe', u'PERSON'], [u'April 28, 1758 \xe2\x80\x93 July 4, 1831', u'DATE'], [u'fifth', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1817-1825', u'DATE']]
James_Monroe  James Monroe (April 28, 1758 – July 4, 1831) was the fifth President of the United States (1817-1825).

Was this study cast into doubt when it was later found that Newton himself wrote the study 's concluding remarks on Leibniz ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a1

yes

Who did James Monroe marry?	Elizabeth Kortright	S08/data/set3/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'James Monroe', u'PERSON'], [u'Elizabeth Kortright', u'PERSON'], [u'February 16, 1786', u'DATE'], [u'the Trinity Church', u'ORG']]
James Monroe married Elizabeth Kortright on February 16, 1786 at the Trinity Church in New York.

Who lost control of his party to the agrarians and silverites in 1896?	Grover Cleveland	S08/data/set3/a6

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'1896', u'DATE']]
He lost control of his party to the agrarians and silverites in 1896.  

He is what?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Amedeo Avogadro  Caricature of Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano Amedeo Carlo Avogadro, Count of Quaregna and Cerreto (August 9, 1776 July 9, 1856) was an Italian savant.

How are Isabelline penguins different from most penguins?	Because they are born with brown rather than black plumage.	S08/data/set1/a3

penguin  A penguin encounters a human during Antarctic summer. Penguins (order Sphenisciformes, family Spheniscidae) are a group of aquatic, flightless birds living almost exclusively in the Southern Hemisphere.

Has Indonesia the world 's largest Muslim population ?	yes	S08/data/set2/a10

QUESTION TYPE: 4

What is the primary item in an otter's diet?	fish	S08/data/set1/a7

ENTITY QUESTION: []
otter  Otters are amphibious (or in one case aquatic) carnivorous mammals.

What is the weather like in summer?	relatively warm	S08/data/set2/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]
Finland  Finland, officially the Republic of Finland "Republic of Finland", or "Suomen tasavalta" in Finnish and "Republiken Finland" in Swedish, is the long protocol name, which is not defined by the law.

What are the two subfamilies of the Native Ghanaian languages?	Kwa and Gur	S08/data/set2/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Native Ghanaian', u'NORP'], [u'two', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Niger', u'GPE']]
Native Ghanaian languages are divided into two linguistic subfamilies of the Niger-Congo language family.

What led Becquerel to investigate the spontaneous emission of nuclear radiation?	phographic plates being fully exposed	S08/data/set4/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Becquerel', u'ORG']]
This discovery led Becquerel to investigate the spontaneous emission of nuclear radiation.

What is a collective noun for a kangaroo?	a mob, troop, or court	S08/data/set1/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: []
The collective noun for kangaroos is a mob, troop, or court.

Do carrion beetles eat dung?	no	S08/data/set1/a8

yes

Why does the phrase 'elephants never forget' have no metaphorical meaning?	Because it refers literally to elephants supposedly having an excellent memory.	S08/data/set1/a5

The phrase 'elephants never forget' has no metaphorical meaning, it refers literally to elephants supposedly having an excellent memory. *

When was Coolidge born?	Plymouth, Windsor County, Vermont	S08/data/set3/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Greenberg', u'ORG'], [u'1\xe2\x80\x937', u'CARDINAL'], [u'John Calvin Coolidge Jr.', u'PERSON'], [u'Plymouth', u'GPE'], [u'Windsor County', u'GPE'], [u'Vermont', u'GPE'], [u'July 4 1872', u'DATE'], [u'U.S.', u'GPE'], [u'fourth of July', u'DATE']]
Greenberg, 1–7  John Calvin Coolidge Jr. was born in Plymouth, Windsor County, Vermont, on July 4 1872, the only U.S. President to be born on the fourth of July.

Who did Massachusetts send in 1774?	John Adams	S08/data/set3/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'1774', u'DATE'], [u'Massachusetts', u'GPE'], [u'the Continental Congress', u'ORG']]
In 1774 Massachusetts sent him to the Continental Congress.

What do well - received and he have in common?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'John Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'July 4 1872', u'DATE'], [u'January 5 1933', u'DATE'], [u'Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1923\xe2\x80\x931929', u'PERSON']]
Calvin Coolidge  John Calvin Coolidge, Jr. (July 4 1872  January 5 1933), more commonly known as Calvin Coolidge, was the thirtieth President of the United States (1923–1929).

Did Grover Cleveland support women's suffrage?	no	S08/data/set3/a6

yes

How heavy was the largest polar bear on record?	He allegedly weighed 1002 kg	S08/data/set1/a4

The largest polar bear on record was a huge male, allegedly weighing 1002 kg (2200 lb) shot at Kotzebue Sound in northwestern Alaska in 1960.  

Is the famous dragon gate at the entrance to the district at the corner of Grant and Bush Street ?	yes	S08/data/set3/a5

no

Why does most of Egypt's population live near the Nile?	The only arable agricultural land is found there	S08/data/set2/a6

About half of Egypt's residents live in urban areas, with the majority spread across the densely populated centers of greater Cairo, Alexandria and other major cities in the Nile Delta.

Why is the giant otter becoming increasingly rare?	poaching, habitat loss, and the use of mercury in illegal alluvial gold mining	S08/data/set1/a7

The giant otter (Pteronura brasiliensis) inhabits South America, especially the Amazon river basin, but is becoming increasingly rare due to poaching, habitat loss, and the use of mercury and other toxins in illegal alluvial gold mining.

What do kangaroos use for "crawl-walking?"	Their hind feet and their tails	S08/data/set1/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: []
Kangaroos are the only large animals to use hopping as a means of locomotion.

How many municipalities is Liechtenstein divided into?	11	S08/data/set2/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Liechtenstein', u'GPE'], [u'11', u'CARDINAL']]
The principality of Liechtenstein is divided into 11 municipalities called gemeinden (singular gemeinde).

What method is used by Kangaroos to travel?	hopping	S08/data/set1/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: []
Eye disease is rare but not new among kangaroos.

What did Aristotle say about elephants?	Aristotle once said the elephant was "the beast which passeth all others in wit and mind."	S08/data/set1/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Aristotle', u'ORG']]
Aristotle once said the elephant was "the beast which passeth all others in wit and mind.

What do beetles eat?	They often feed on plants and fungi, break down animal and plant debris, and eat other invertebrates	S08/data/set1/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: []
They often feed on plants and fungi, break down animal and plant debris, and eat other invertebrates.

What was on March?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]
Ghana  The Republic of Ghana is a country in West Africa.

When did he publish another memoria?	1821	S08/data/set4/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]
Amedeo Avogadro  Caricature of Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano Amedeo Carlo Avogadro, Count of Quaregna and Cerreto (August 9, 1776 July 9, 1856) was an Italian savant.

What did Ghana capture in 1642?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'1637', u'DATE'], [u'Portuguese', u'NORP'], [u'Axim', u'GPE'], [u'1642', u'DATE'], [u'Fort St Anthony)', u'FAC']]
In 1637 they captured the castle from the Portuguese and that of Axim in 1642 (Fort St Anthony).

What is the primary domestic source of water supply?	The primary domestic source of water supply in Singapore is rainfall.	S08/data/set2/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Singapore', u'GPE']]
Without natural freshwater rivers and lakes, the primary domestic source of water supply in Singapore is rainfall, collected in reservoirs or catchment areas.

Is Uruguay very common?	No?	S08/data/set2/a9

yes

What types of unrelated water birds with similar forms are ducks sometimes confused with?	loons or divers, grebes, gallinules, and coots	S08/data/set1/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: []
Ducks are sometimes confused with several types of unrelated water birds with similar forms, such as loons or divers, grebes, gallinules, and coots.

How heavy is a male polar bear?	Most adult males weigh 350-650 kg	S08/data/set1/a4

polar bear  The polar bear (Ursus maritimus) is a bear native to the Arctic.

What happened on plants and fungi?	They are food to beetles.	S08/data/set1/a8

They often feed

Did the media contribute 15.6% to Singapore's GDP in 2001?	no	S08/data/set2/a2

yes

What is now part of Adams National Historical Park?	John Adams' birthplace	S08/data/set3/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Adams National Historical Park', u'ORG']]
His birthplace is now part of Adams National Historical Park.

He became chief engineer in the Department of Bridges and Highways in what year?	in 1894	S08/data/set4/a9

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Henri_Becquerel  Antoine Henri Becquerel (December 15, 1852 ; August 25, 1908) was a French physicist, Nobel laureate, and one of the discoverers of radioactivity.

What does "singa" mean?	lion	S08/data/set2/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Syonan-to', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Syonan', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Light of the South', u'WORK_OF_ART']]
The name Shōnantō was, at the time, romanized as "Syonan-to" or "Syonan", which means "Light of the South".  

What religion do most Uruguayans profess?	Roman Catholic	S08/data/set2/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Uruguayans', u'NORP'], [u'Catholic', u'GPE'], [u'Protestant', u'NORP'], [u'Jewish', u'NORP']]
Although the majority of Uruguayans do not actively practice a religion, they are nominally church members in the Catholic, Protestant and Jewish communities.

Where does the word "otter" derive from?	The word "otter" derives from the Old English word otr, otor or oter. This and cognate words in other Indo-European languages ultimately stem from a root which also gave rise to the English words "water", "wet" and "winter". 	S08/data/set1/a7

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'the Old English', u'LOC']]
The word "otter" derives from the Old English word otr, otor or oter.

Does it have a border with Norway?	Yes	S08/data/set2/a4

no

Have more than five Presidents lived past the age of 90?	no	S08/data/set3/a10

QUESTION TYPE: 4
*Ford is one of only four former Presidents to live to 90 or more years of age.

What is an economic use of a duck?	being farmed for their meat	S08/data/set1/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u' Duck', u'PERSON'], [u'Anatidae', u'PERSON']]
duck  Duck is the common name for a number of species in the Anatidae family of birds.

What type of creatures breathe air and don't lay eggs underwater?	amnoites	S08/data/set1/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: []
Like other amniotes (reptiles, dinosaurs, birds, and mammals), they breathe air and don't lay eggs underwater, though many species live in or around water.

Who is Daffy Duck?	a silly cartoon character	S08/data/set1/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u' Duck', u'PERSON'], [u'Anatidae', u'PERSON']]
duck  Duck is the common name for a number of species in the Anatidae family of birds.

What drives sea otter almost to extinction?	Sea otters have some 200,000 hairs per square cm of skin, a rich fur for which humans hunted them almost to extinction. 	S08/data/set1/a7

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'200,000', u'CARDINAL']]
Sea otters have some 200,000 hairs per square cm of skin, a rich fur for which humans hunted them almost to extinction.

Is Medieval Ghana (4th- 13th Century): The Republic of Ghana is named after the medieval Ghana Empire of West Africa. named after the medieval Ghana Empire of West Africa?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

yes

How many Eagle Scouts were involved in Ford's funeral procession?	About 400	S08/data/set3/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'About 400', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Eagle Scouts', u'ORG']]

Who confirm that he sponsored and helped some Sardinian plotters who were organising a revolution in that island , stopped at the very last moment by the concession of Charles Albert 's statute ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Sardinian', u'NORP'], [u"Charles Albert's", u'PERSON']]
Several historical studies confirm that he sponsored and helped some Sardinian plotters who were organising a revolution in that island, stopped at the very last moment by the concession of Charles Albert's statute.

Were the two in a dispute over optical discoveries at the time ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a1

yes

Has the New Zealand Rugby League featured the Otahuhu Leopards and then the Tamaki Leopards ?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a2

QUESTION TYPE: 4
The New Zealand Rugby League has featured the Otahuhu Leopards and then the Tamaki Leopards.

What is the national currency of Liechtenstein?	Swiss franc	S08/data/set2/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Liechtenstein', u'GPE'], [u'Liechtenstein', u'GPE'], [u'Western Europe', u'LOC'], [u'Switzerland', u'GPE'], [u'Austria', u'GPE']]
Liechtenstein  The Principality of Liechtenstein ( ( , ( ) is a tiny, doubly landlocked alpine country in Western Europe, bordered by Switzerland to its west and by Austria to its east.

How did the supporters of Henry Clay feel about Fillmore in 1848?	angry	S08/data/set3/a3


Is it true that volta entered retirement in spain?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

yes

Who graduated in ecclesiastical law at the early age of 20 and began to practice?	blah	S08/data/set4/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'the early age', u'DATE'], [u'20', u'CARDINAL']]
He graduated in ecclesiastical law at the early age of 20 and began to practice.

Does this not allow retailers of taxable goods under Act 546 to charge a marginal 3 % on their sales and account on same to the VAT Service ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

yes

Did Grant & Perkins not sell harnesses , saddles , and other leather goods and purchase hides from farmers in the prosperous Galena area ?	they did	S08/data/set3/a5

yes

Is it true that volta became professor of physics?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

yes

What shape are the eggs of the larest species of turtle?	spherical	S08/data/set1/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: []
The eggs of the largest species are spherical, while the eggs of the rest are elongated.

What happened with the portuguese in the 15th century?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

Trade with European states flourished after contact with the Portuguese in the 15th century, and the British established a crown colony, Gold Coast, in 1874.

What is the weather like at Lake Volta?	warm and comparatively dry	S08/data/set2/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]
Ghana  The Republic of Ghana is a country in West Africa.

How much do elephants weight at birth?	At birth it is common for an elephant calf to weigh 120 kilograms (265 lb).	S08/data/set1/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Proboscidea', u'GPE'], [u'Mammalia', u'PERSON']]
elephant  Elephants (Elephantidae) are a family in the order Proboscidea in the class Mammalia.

When did Qatar become an independent state?	September 3, 1971	S08/data/set2/a3

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Ottoman', u'NORP'], [u'British', u'NORP'], [u'centuries', u'GPE'], [u'Qatar', u'GPE'], [u'September 3, 1971', u'DATE']]
After domination by the Ottoman and British empires for centuries, Qatar became an independent state on September 3, 1971.

What are the similarities between beetles and grasshoppers?	Beetles have mouthparts similar to those of grasshoppers	S08/data/set1/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: []
beetle  Beetles are a group of insects which have the largest number of species.

Was Adams the first to introduce a bicameral legislature?	yes	S08/data/set3/a1

no

Have most otters fish as the primary item in their diet , supplemented by frogs , crayfish and crabs ?	yes	S08/data/set1/a7

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Most otters have fish as the primary item in their diet, supplemented by frogs, crayfish and crabs.

Is it true that it angered many residents of the thirteen colonies?	yes	S08/data/set2/a8

no

Where was Millard Fillmore born?	in a log cabin in Summerhill, New York	S08/data/set3/a3

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Fillmore', u'PERSON'], [u'Summerhill', u'GPE'], [u'New York', u'GPE'], [u'Nathaniel', u'PERSON'], [u'Phoebe Millard Fillmore', u'PERSON'], [u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u'nine', u'CARDINAL']]
Fillmore was born in a log cabin in Summerhill, New York, to Nathaniel and Phoebe Millard Fillmore, as the second of nine children and the eldest son.  

What do with greenpeace and the natural resources defense council have in common?	They filed lawsuits in California.	S08/data/set1/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: []
The bears sometimes have problems with various skin diseases with dermatitis caused sometimes by mites or other parasites.

Can otters survive in cold water?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a7

QUESTION TYPE: 4
In water as warm as 10°C an otter needs to catch 100 g of fish per hour to survive.

The collective noun romp is sometimes used for a group of what?	Otters	S08/data/set1/a7

QUESTION TYPE: 4
The collective noun romp is sometimes used for a group of otters, being descriptive of their often playful nature.   

What sort of cats are solitary?	Leopards	S08/data/set1/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: []
These cats are solitary, avoiding one another.

(NNP Harding #)(NNP Death )))(PP (IN in )(NP (NP (NN office ))(PP (IN for )(NP (DT a )(JJ full )(NN description )(NNP Vice )(NNP President )(person (NNP Coolidge ))))))))(VP (VP (VBD was )(VP (VBG visiting )(NP (PRP$ his )(NN family )(NN home ))))(, , )(SBAR (WHNP (WDT which ))(S (VP (VBD did )(RB not )(VP (VB have )(NP (NP (NN electricity ))(CC or )(NP (DT a )(NN telephone )))(, , )(PP (IN in )(NP (location (NNP Vermont ))))(SBAR (WHADVP (WRB when ))(S (NP (PRP he ))(VP (VBD received )(NP (NP (NN word ))(PP (IN of )(NP (NP (NNP Harding )(POS 's ))(NN death ))))))))))))))(. . )))	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

QUESTION TYPE: 4
See the main article, Warren Harding#Death in office for a full description Vice President Coolidge was visiting his family home, which did not have electricity or a telephone, in Vermont when he received word of Harding's death.

What unrelated water birds are ducks sometimes confused with?	loons or divers, grebes, gallinules, and coots	S08/data/set1/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: []
Ducks are sometimes confused with several types of unrelated water birds with similar forms, such as loons or divers, grebes, gallinules, and coots.

Which defense mechanism uses colour or shape to deceive potential enemies?	Mimicry	S08/data/set1/a8

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Another defence that often uses colour or shape to deceive potential enemies is mimicry.

Who sits at Osu Castle ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]
Ghana  The Republic of Ghana is a country in West Africa.

When do African elephants lie down?	when they are sick or wounded	S08/data/set1/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'African', u'NORP']]
In fact, African elephants rarely lie down unless they are sick or wounded.

What happened from 1730 to 1744?	He was professor of astronomy at Uppsala University	S08/data/set4/a5

Anders_Celsius Anders Celsius The observatory of Anders Celsius, from a contemporary engraving.

What is the world population of Asian elephants?	The world population of Asian elephants – also called Indian Elephants or Elephas maximus – is estimated to be around 60,000	S08/data/set1/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'three', u'CARDINAL'], [u'African', u'NORP'], [u'Bush Elephant', u'PERSON'], [u'the African Elephant', u'ORG'], [u'the Asian Elephant', u'ORG'], [u'the Indian Elephant', u'ORG']]
There are three living species: the African Bush Elephant, the African Forest Elephant (until recently known collectively as the African Elephant), and the Asian Elephant (also known as the Indian Elephant).

Do turtles lay eggs underwater?	no	S08/data/set1/a9

yes

Are penguins afraid of humans?	no	S08/data/set1/a3

yes

What arrived in Finland?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]
Finland  Finland, officially the Republic of Finland "Republic of Finland", or "Suomen tasavalta" in Finnish and "Republiken Finland" in Swedish, is the long protocol name, which is not defined by the law.

What happened in these positions in english?	These allophones cannot occur there.	S08/data/set2/a3

Qatar  Qatar ( ;  The pronunciation of Qatar in English varies; see List of words of disputed pronunciation for details.

What is the biggest city in Finland?	the cities of the Greater Helsinki metropolitan area	S08/data/set2/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]
Finland  Finland, officially the Republic of Finland "Republic of Finland", or "Suomen tasavalta" in Finnish and "Republiken Finland" in Swedish, is the long protocol name, which is not defined by the law.

Have kangaroos fared well since European settlement?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a1

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Unlike many of the smaller macropods, kangaroos have fared well since European settlement.

What situated in Northern?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]
Finland  Finland, officially the Republic of Finland "Republic of Finland", or "Suomen tasavalta" in Finnish and "Republiken Finland" in Swedish, is the long protocol name, which is not defined by the law.

The Savings and Loans Bank was founded, as was the first cotton-weaving mill in what year?	1861	S08/data/set2/a1

QUESTION TYPE: 4
In 1861, the Savings and Loans Bank was founded, as was the first cotton-weaving mill.

Who did Sir Thomas Stamford Raffles work for?	British East India Company	S08/data/set2/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Singapore', u'GPE'], [u'1991', u'DATE']]
The office of President of Singapore, historically a ceremonial one, was granted some veto powers as of 1991 for a few key decisions such as the use of the national reserves and the appointment of judiciary positions.

Who did Ford nominate for Vice President?	Nelson Rockefeller	S08/data/set3/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'August 20', u'DATE'], [u'Ford', u'ORG'], [u'New York Governor Nelson', u'GPE']]
On August 20 Ford nominated former New York Governor Nelson Rockefeller to fill the vice presidency he had vacated.

If a turtle egg was kept warm, what would likely hatch?	A female turtle	S08/data/set1/a9

QUESTION TYPE: 4
It was found that the liver, lungs and kidneys of a centenarian turtle are virtually indistinguishable from those of its immature counterpart.

What was against William?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Isaac Newton', u'PERSON'], [u'Isaac Newton', u'PERSON'], [u'4', u'CARDINAL'], [u'January 1643 \xe2\x80\x93', u'DATE'], [u'March 31 1727', u'DATE'], [u'December 25 1642 \xe2\x80\x93 March 20 1727', u'DATE'], [u'English', u'NORP']]
Isaac Newton  Sir Isaac Newton FRS ( ) (4 January 1643 – March 31 1727)   OS: December 25 1642 – March 20 1727   was an English physicist, mathematician, astronomer, natural philosopher, and alchemist.

What was the nickname of Theodore Roosevelt's sister Anna?	Bamie	S08/data/set3/a7

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Theodore Roosevelt', u'PERSON'], [u'Theodore Roosevelt', u'PERSON'], [u'October 27 1858', u'DATE'], [u'January 6 1919', u'DATE'], [u'T.R.', u'GPE'], [u'Teddy', u'GPE'], [u'the twenty-sixth President of', u'DATE'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'the Republican Party', u'ORG'], [u'the Progressive Movement', u'ORG']]
Theodore Roosevelt  Theodore Roosevelt, Jr. ( ; October 27 1858  January 6 1919), also known as T.R., and to the public (but never to friends and intimates) as Teddy, was the twenty-sixth President of the United States, and a leader of the Republican Party and of the Progressive Movement.  

Are Gray Wolves native to North America?	No. Current theory suggests that it's from Eurasia	S08/data/set1/a6

no

What caused Calvin Jr.'s death?	Heart attack	S08/data/set3/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'the twenty-ninth Vice President in 1920', u'DATE'], [u'Warren G. Harding', u'PERSON']]
Soon after, he was elected as the twenty-ninth Vice President in 1920 and succeeded to the Presidency upon the death of Warren G. Harding.

What happens when mothers lose a chick?	They sometimes attempt to "steal" another chick.	S08/data/set1/a3

When mothers lose a chick, they sometimes attempt to "steal" another mother's chick, usually unsuccessfully as other females in the vicinity assist the defending mother in keeping her chick.

To what genus does the gray wolf belong?	Canis	S08/data/set1/a6

QUESTION TYPE: 4
While wolf predation on livestock does happen, loss of livestock by wolves makes up only a small percentage of total losses in North America.

What is The Remarkable Millard Fillmore?	In 2007, George Pendle wrote The Remarkable Millard Fillmore, a fake biography based on real events that happened in Fillmore's life	S08/data/set3/a3

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Millard Fillmore', u'PERSON'], [u'Millard Fillmore', u'PERSON'], [u'January 7, 1800  ', u'DATE'], [u'March 8, 1874', u'DATE'], [u'thirteenth', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1850', u'DATE'], [u'1853', u'DATE'], [u'the Whig Party', u'ORG']]

Were the treaties signed in 1947 and 1948 with the Ukraine?	No	S08/data/set2/a4

yes

What did James Monroe's letters not contain?	No letters survive in which he might have discussed his religious beliefs.	S08/data/set3/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: []
Letters that do survive, such as ones written on the occasion of the death of his son, contain no discussion of religion.

Are Count Volta 's original instruments and papers on display there ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

no

Is Volta buried in the city of Como?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

yes

Can larger penguins dive deep in case of need ?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a3

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Larger penguins can dive deep in case of need.

Volta became professor of physics in the Como high school in what year?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Alessandro_Volta  Count Alessandro Giuseppe Antonio Anastasio Volta (February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827) was an Italian physicist known especially for the development of the first known electric battery in 1800.   

What is the MRT?	Mass Rapid Transit system	S08/data/set2/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Singapore', u'GPE'], [u'Singapore', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Singapore', u'GPE'], [u'the Malay Peninsula', u'LOC']]

What thrust him into the national spotlight?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'John Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'July 4 1872', u'DATE'], [u'January 5 1933', u'DATE'], [u'Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1923\xe2\x80\x931929', u'PERSON']]
Calvin Coolidge  John Calvin Coolidge, Jr. (July 4 1872  January 5 1933), more commonly known as Calvin Coolidge, was the thirtieth President of the United States (1923–1929).

Was Coolidge more outspoken?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

yes

Did Roosevelt study biology?	He was strong in biology.	S08/data/set3/a7

yes

What Eves?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Isaac Newton', u'PERSON'], [u'Isaac Newton', u'PERSON'], [u'4', u'CARDINAL'], [u'January 1643 \xe2\x80\x93', u'DATE'], [u'March 31 1727', u'DATE'], [u'December 25 1642 \xe2\x80\x93 March 20 1727', u'DATE'], [u'English', u'NORP']]
Isaac Newton  Sir Isaac Newton FRS ( ) (4 January 1643 – March 31 1727)   OS: December 25 1642 – March 20 1727   was an English physicist, mathematician, astronomer, natural philosopher, and alchemist.

Will oil and gas probably remain the backbone of Qatar 's economy for some time to come ?	Yes	S08/data/set2/a3

QUESTION TYPE: 4
While oil and gas will probably remain the backbone of Qatar's economy for some time to come, the country seeks to stimulate the private sector and develop a "knowledge economy".

Is the most read newspaper in Finland Taloussanomat?	No	S08/data/set2/a4

yes

What emigrated from Cambridge?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'John Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'July 4 1872', u'DATE'], [u'January 5 1933', u'DATE'], [u'Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1923\xe2\x80\x931929', u'PERSON']]
Calvin Coolidge  John Calvin Coolidge, Jr. (July 4 1872  January 5 1933), more commonly known as Calvin Coolidge, was the thirtieth President of the United States (1923–1929).

Who suggested Lincoln grow a beard?	Grace Bedell.	S08/data/set3/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'297', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'1860', u'DATE'], [u'11-year-old', u'DATE'], [u'Grace Bedell', u'PERSON']]
297   While Lincoln is usually portrayed bearded, he first grew a beard in 1860 at the suggestion of 11-year-old Grace Bedell Lincoln's death made the President a martyr to many.

Who has its own political legislature and governor ?	each province	S08/data/set2/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: []
Each province has its own political legislature and governor.

How many species of penguins are there?	Penguin biodiversity varies between 17 and 20 living species, all in the subfamily Spheniscinae.	S08/data/set1/a3

ENTITY QUESTION: []
In the water, however, penguins are astonishingly agile.

What did Alessandro Volta publish in 1800?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10


Where do leopards often hide their kills?	in dense vegetation or in trees	S08/data/set1/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'three', u'CARDINAL']]
Leopards often hide their kills in dense vegetation or take them up trees, and are capable of carrying animals up to three times their own weight this way.

Did Fillmore form a law partnership before or after he founded the private University of Buffalo?	Law partnership founded before University of Buffalo	S08/data/set3/a3

yes

Was his 1800 paper written in French ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

yes

Who is the head of state of Ghana?	John Agyekum Kufuor	S08/data/set2/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]
Ghana  The Republic of Ghana is a country in West Africa.

What trail did Lincoln use a Farmers' Almanac in? 	he defended William "Duff" Armstrong	S08/data/set3/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Lincoln', u'ORG']]
Throughout the election, Lincoln did not campaign or give speeches.

Where was Theodore Roosevelt born?	a four-story brownstone at 28 East 20th Street, in the modern-day Gramercy section of New York City	S08/data/set3/a7

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Theodore Roosevelt', u'PERSON'], [u'11', u'DATE'], [u'Theodore Roosevelt', u'PERSON'], [u'four', u'CARDINAL'], [u'28', u'CARDINAL'], [u'New York City', u'GPE'], [u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u'four', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Theodore Roosevelt', u'PERSON'], [u'Sr', u'GPE']]
Theodore Roosevelt at age 11 Theodore Roosevelt was born in a four-story brownstone at 28 East 20th Street, in the modern-day Gramercy section of New York City, the second of four children of Theodore Roosevelt, Sr.

How do qatar and the wider region relate?	Qatar is aiming to become a role model for economic and social transformation in the region. Large scale investment in all social and economic sectors will also lead to the development of a strong financial market.	S08/data/set2/a3

Qatar  Qatar ( ;  The pronunciation of Qatar in English varies; see List of words of disputed pronunciation for details.

Where do sea otters live?	The sea otter lives actually in the sea. 	S08/data/set1/a7

ENTITY QUESTION: []
Otters do not depend on their specialized fur alone for survival in the cold waters where many live: they also have very high metabolic rates.

Is Canada bilingual?	Yes, it is.	S08/data/set2/a8

yes

Is it true that anecdotal evidence connected the akans to this empire?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

yes

Is Uruguay located in the northwesten part of Africa?	no	S08/data/set2/a9

yes

Who boasted a sizeable community of 100,000 by 1869?	British India office	S08/data/set2/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Singapore', u'GPE'], [u'Singapore', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Singapore', u'GPE'], [u'the Malay Peninsula', u'LOC']]

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Ford', u'ORG'], [u'1941', u'DATE'], [u'Michigan', u'GPE']]
Ford graduated from law school in 1941, and was admitted to the Michigan bar shortly thereafter.

What is the largest city in Romania?	Bucharest	S08/data/set2/a7

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Romania', u'GPE'], [u'Romania', u'GPE'], [u'Southeastern Europe', u'LOC']]
Romania  Romania ( , ) is a country in Southeastern Europe.

Felis pardus was what?	One of the many species described in Linnaeus's 18th-century work, Systema Naturae	S08/data/set1/a2

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Felis pardus was one of the many species described in Linnaeus's 18th-century work, Systema Naturae.

What is Canada's national unemployment rate?	In October 2007, Canada's national unemployment rate is 5.9%.	S08/data/set2/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'as of October 2007', u'DATE'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'5.9% is its', u'PERCENT'], [u'33 years', u'DATE']]
While as of October 2007, Canada's national unemployment rate of 5.9% is its lowest in 33 years.

What was Canada's most important industry until the 1800s?	The fur trade	S08/data/set2/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'North America', u'LOC'], [u'the Atlantic Ocean', u'LOC'], [u'the Pacific Ocean', u'ORG'], [u'the Arctic Ocean', u'LOC']]
Canada  Canada ( ) is a country occupying most of northern North America, extending from the Atlantic Ocean in the east to the Pacific Ocean in the west and northward into the Arctic Ocean.

Do wolves leave their pack?	They leave their birth pack when they reach sexual maturity	S08/data/set1/a6

yes

What did James Monroe do before being elected governor?	He practiced law	S08/data/set3/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: []
Nor did his friends, family or associates write about his beliefs.

What did Finland join in 1995?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the European Union', u'ORG'], [u'1995', u'DATE']]
Finland joined the European Union in 1995.   

What resembles that of the similarly-sized cougar in the Americas?	The leopard's ecological role	S08/data/set1/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Americas', u'ORG']]
Its ecological role resembles that of the similarly-sized cougar in the Americas.

When did Coolidge meet and marry Grace Anna Goodhue?	In 1905	S08/data/set3/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'1905', u'DATE'], [u'Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'Grace Anna Goodhue', u'PERSON'], [u'Vermonter', u'NORP']]
In 1905 Coolidge met and married Grace Anna Goodhue, a local schoolteacher and fellow Vermonter.

Who was on the committee with Adams to draft  a Declaration of Independence?	Thomas Jefferson, Benjamin Franklin, Robert R. Livingston and Roger Sherman	S08/data/set3/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Thomas Jefferson', u'PERSON'], [u'Benjamin Franklin', u'PERSON'], [u'Robert R. Livingston', u'PERSON'], [u'Roger Sherman', u'PERSON'], [u'Declaration of Independence', u'ORG']]
He was appointed on a committee with Thomas Jefferson, Benjamin Franklin, Robert R. Livingston and Roger Sherman, to draft a Declaration of Independence.

Are there many Roma in Romania?	no	S08/data/set2/a7

yes

How do elephants communicate over long distances?	By producing and receiving low-frequency sound (infrasound)	S08/data/set1/a5

Bruce Bagemihl, Biological Exuberance: Animal Homosexuality and Natural Diversity, St. Martin's Press, 1999; pp.427-430  Elephants communicate over long distances by producing and receiving low-frequency sound (infrasound), a sub-sonic rumbling, which can travel through the ground farther than sound travels through the air.

Is Adams' birthplace part of a national park?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a1

no

What did Uruguay win in 1828?	Its independence	S08/data/set2/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Uruguay', u'ORG'], [u'1828', u'DATE'], [u'three', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Spain', u'GPE'], [u'Argentina', u'GPE'], [u'Brazil', u'GPE']]
Uruguay won its independence in 1828 following a three-way struggle between Spain, Argentina and Brazil.

Is the Adephaga suborder larger than the Polyphaga suborder?	yes	S08/data/set1/a8

no

Is there a becquerel crater on the moon and a becquerel crater on mars?	yes	S08/data/set4/a9

no

Do all ducks "quack"?	No	S08/data/set1/a10

yes

Does a large proportion of the population speak Swedish as its mother tongue?	No	S08/data/set2/a4

yes

Different species of kangaroos eat what?	different diets	S08/data/set1/a1

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Different species of kangaroos eat different diets.

When did John Adams serve as Vice President?	1789-1797	S08/data/set3/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'America', u'GPE'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'1789 1797', u'DATE']]
He also served as America's first Vice President (1789 1797).

Four years after opening his shop , Watt began what?	Watt began to experiment with steam after his friend, Professor John Robison, called his attention to it.	S08/data/set4/a2

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Four years after opening his shop, Watt began to experiment with steam after his friend, Professor John Robison, called his attention to it.

How many living species of African Elephants are there?	The African Elephant genus contains two (or, arguably, three) living species.	S08/data/set1/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: []
*Elephants are a species which many other organisms depend on.

During what period was Akhenaten a Pharaoh?	The New Kingdom	S08/data/set2/a6

QUESTION TYPE: 4
The Thirtieth Dynasty was the last native ruling dynasty during the Pharaonic epoch.

Where is Qatar's telecommunication system centered?	Doha	S08/data/set2/a3

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Qatar', u'GPE'], [u'Telecommunication', u'ORG'], [u'Doha', u'GPE']]
Qatar has a modern Telecommunication system centered in Doha.

What completed in November?	the Kunstmuseum Liechtenstein	S08/data/set2/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Liechtenstein', u'GPE'], [u'Liechtenstein', u'GPE'], [u'Western Europe', u'LOC'], [u'Switzerland', u'GPE'], [u'Austria', u'GPE']]
Liechtenstein  The Principality of Liechtenstein ( ( , ( ) is a tiny, doubly landlocked alpine country in Western Europe, bordered by Switzerland to its west and by Austria to its east.

Has this inspired genetic researchers to begin examining the turtle genome for longevity genes ?	yes	S08/data/set1/a9

QUESTION TYPE: 4
This has inspired genetic researchers to begin examining the turtle genome for longevity genes.

What land animal has the largest brain?	The elephant	S08/data/set1/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: []
The largest areas in elephant brain are those responsible for hearing, smell and movement coordination, and a large portion of the brain has to do with trunk management and sensitivity.  

Name four related articles for the article on turtles.	Triassic, Ernst Haeckel, Kunstformen der Natur, Animal	S08/data/set1/a9

QUESTION TYPE: 4
turtle  Turtles are reptilians of the Order Testudines (all living turtles belong to the crown group Chelonia), most of whose body is shielded by a special bony or cartilaginous shell developed from their ribs.

Who did President Lincoln promote of major general in the regular army, effective July 4?	Grant	S08/data/set3/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'Grant', u'ORG'], [u'July 4', u'DATE']]
For this victory, President Lincoln promoted Grant to the rank of major general in the regular army, effective July 4.

When do wolves molt?	late spring or early summer	S08/data/set1/a6

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'late spring', u'DATE'], [u'early summer', u'DATE']]
Wolves molt in late spring or early summer.

What is Monroe Doctrine?	In it, Monroe proclaimed the Americas should be free from future European colonization and free from European interference in sovereign countries' affairs. It further stated the United States' intention to stay neutral in European wars and wars between European powers and their colonies, but to consider any new colonies or interference with independent countries in the Americas as hostile acts toward the United States. 	S08/data/set3/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'James Monroe', u'PERSON'], [u'April 28, 1758 \xe2\x80\x93 July 4, 1831', u'DATE'], [u'fifth', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1817-1825', u'DATE']]
James_Monroe  James Monroe (April 28, 1758 – July 4, 1831) was the fifth President of the United States (1817-1825).

What was founded by the Spanish in the early 18th century as a military stronghold?	Montevideo	S08/data/set2/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Montevideo', u'GPE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'the early 18th century', u'DATE']]
Montevideo was founded by the Spanish in the early 18th century as a military stronghold.

Is it true that newton saw god as the master creator?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a1

yes

How much do wolves weigh?	between 32 and 68 kilograms 	S08/data/set1/a6

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'the Arabian Wolf', u'ORG'], [u'as little as', u'PERCENT']]
The smallest wolves come from the Arabian Wolf subspecies, the females of which may weigh as little as 10 kg (22 lb) at maturity.

Name an animal that is growing in number due to recent conservation efforts	Golden Eagle	S08/data/set2/a4

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Tourism is an expanding industry in Finland and in recent years has become a significant aspect of its economy.

The unification of Italy did what?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

QUESTION TYPE: 4
The unification of Italy did not happen during the life time of Avogadro.

What is the life expectancy for men in Finland?	75 years	S08/data/set2/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]
Finland  Finland, officially the Republic of Finland "Republic of Finland", or "Suomen tasavalta" in Finnish and "Republiken Finland" in Swedish, is the long protocol name, which is not defined by the law.

Is the leopard an Old World mammal?	.	S08/data/set1/a2

yes

Who spend half of their life on land and half in the oceans?	Penguins	S08/data/set1/a3

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'half', u'CARDINAL'], [u'half', u'CARDINAL']]
They spend half of their life on land and half in the oceans.

What traps a layer of air, and keeps them dry and warm under water?	Long guard hair	S08/data/set1/a7

ENTITY QUESTION: []
This traps a layer of air, and keeps them dry and warm under water.   

Adams ' opponents were what?	Democratic Republicans	S08/data/set3/a1

QUESTION TYPE: 4
The rift between Adams and the High Federalists (as Adams's opponents were called) grew wider.

Are kangaroos and wallabies adept swimmers?	yes	S08/data/set1/a1

no

What happened in 1811?	Monroe returned to the Virginia House of Delegates and was elected to another term as governor of Virginia	S08/data/set3/a2

James_Monroe  James Monroe (April 28, 1758 – July 4, 1831) was the fifth President of the United States (1817-1825).

What dwindled and eventually died out, starting with the Hartford Convention?	The Federalist Party	S08/data/set3/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'James Monroe', u'PERSON'], [u'April 28, 1758 \xe2\x80\x93 July 4, 1831', u'DATE'], [u'fifth', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1817-1825', u'DATE']]
James_Monroe  James Monroe (April 28, 1758 – July 4, 1831) was the fifth President of the United States (1817-1825).

What is the national language of Singapore?	The national language of Singapore is Malay.	S08/data/set2/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Singapore', u'GPE'], [u'Singapore', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Singapore', u'GPE'], [u'the Malay Peninsula', u'LOC']]

Where is the largest gray wolf population thought to be found?	Kazakhstan	S08/data/set1/a6

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'North America', u'LOC']]
After that the gray wolf is thought to have become the prime canine predator in North America.  

Where is Adams buried?	United First Parish Church	S08/data/set3/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'John Adams', u'PERSON'], [u'October 30,1735', u'DATE'], [u'July 4, 1826', u'DATE'], [u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1797 1801', u'DATE']]
John_Adams  John Adams, Jr. (October 30,1735  July 4, 1826) was the second President of the United States (1797 1801).

Is Indonesia a monarchy with a presidential system?	No	S08/data/set2/a10

yes

How many days did it take the Imperial Japanese Army to win the Battle of Singapore?	6 days	S08/data/set2/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Singapore', u'GPE'], [u'175', u'CARDINAL']]

What happened with $ its invention?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

Alessandro_Volta  Count Alessandro Giuseppe Antonio Anastasio Volta (February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827) was an Italian physicist known especially for the development of the first known electric battery in 1800.   

What allows a duck to filter water out of the side of their beaks and keep food inside?	tiny rows of plates called lamellae like a whale's baleen	S08/data/set1/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: []
These let them filter water out of the side of their beaks and keep food inside.

What is spoken natively by a 5.5 percent minority?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]
Finland  Finland, officially the Republic of Finland "Republic of Finland", or "Suomen tasavalta" in Finnish and "Republiken Finland" in Swedish, is the long protocol name, which is not defined by the law.

Is Egypt in Asia?	No.	S08/data/set2/a6

yes

Was one of the most productive composers of popular music Toivo Kärki , and the most famous singer Olavi Virta -LRB- 1915 -- 1972 -RRB- ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

no

Did Wilson's father own slaves?	Yeah	S08/data/set3/a8

no

Why did Grant think that war was unjust?	He accepted the theory that it was designed to gain land open to slavery.	S08/data/set3/a5

Some contestants thought it was a trick question.

Was Monroe anticlerical?	no	S08/data/set3/a2

yes

He later what?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Calvin Coolidge  John Calvin Coolidge, Jr. (July 4 1872  January 5 1933), more commonly known as Calvin Coolidge, was the thirtieth President of the United States (1923–1929).

What is the estimated population of Egypt?	78 million	S08/data/set2/a6

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Egypt', u'GPE'], [u'Egypt', u'GPE'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Kemet', u'PERSON'], [u'Coptic', u'NORP'], [u'  ', u'ORG'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Arab Republic', u'ORG'], [u'North Africa', u'GPE'], [u'the Sinai Peninsula', u'LOC'], [u'Asia', u'LOC']]
Egypt  Egypt (Egyptian: Kemet; Coptic:  Kīmi;   ; Egyptian Arabic: ), officially the Arab Republic of Egypt, is a country in North Africa that includes the Sinai Peninsula, a land bridge to Asia.


ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Cleveland', u'GPE'], [u'only one', u'CARDINAL']]
Cleveland's administration might be characterized by his saying: "I have only one thing to do, and that is to do right".

Where was Grover Cleveland married?	in the Blue Room in the White House	S08/data/set3/a6

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Grover Cleveland', u'PERSON'], [u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the White House', u'ORG'], [u'June 2, 1886', u'DATE'], [u'Cleveland', u'GPE'], [u'Frances Cornelia Folsom', u'PERSON'], [u'Blue Room', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'White House', u'ORG']]
Grover Cleveland was the second President married in office, and the only President married in the White House itself On June 2, 1886, Cleveland married Frances Cornelia Folsom, the daughter of his former law partner, in the Blue Room in the White House.

Who or what vary greatly in form within the coleoptera?	Antennae.	S08/data/set1/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Coleoptera', u'ORG']]
Antennae vary greatly in form within the Coleoptera, but are often similar within any given family.

What percentage of Liechtenstein's population is foreign-born?	67%	S08/data/set2/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Liechtenstein', u'GPE'], [u'sixth', u'ORDINAL']]
Liechtenstein is the sixth-smallest independent nation in the world, by land area.

What is the most densely populated independent country in the world?	Monaco	S08/data/set2/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'704.0', u'CARDINAL'], [u'272', u'CARDINAL'], [u'one', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Southeast Asia', u'LOC']]
At 704.0 km² (272 sq mi), it is one of the few remaining city-states in the world and the smallest country in Southeast Asia.

Where is old Ghana in relation to present Ghana?	500 miles north of the present Ghana, and occupied the area between Rivers Senegal and Niger	S08/data/set2/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]
Ghana  The Republic of Ghana is a country in West Africa.

What consists of a low, barren plain, covered with sand?	Much of the country.	S08/data/set2/a3

ENTITY QUESTION: []
Much of the country consists of a low, barren plain, covered with sand.

Are Native Ghanaian languages divided into two linguistic subfamilies of the Niger-Congo language family ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

yes

Is it a winter sports resort?	Yes	S08/data/set2/a1

no

Have a number of live theatrical plays based on Tesla 's life been produced and staged worldwide ?	yes.	S08/data/set4/a3

QUESTION TYPE: 4
A number of live theatrical plays based on Tesla's life have been produced and staged worldwide. *

Who helped to fund Roosevelt's African safari?	Andrew Carnegie	S08/data/set3/a7

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Theodore Roosevelt', u'PERSON'], [u'Theodore Roosevelt', u'PERSON'], [u'October 27 1858', u'DATE'], [u'January 6 1919', u'DATE'], [u'T.R.', u'GPE'], [u'Teddy', u'GPE'], [u'the twenty-sixth President of', u'DATE'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'the Republican Party', u'ORG'], [u'the Progressive Movement', u'ORG']]
Theodore Roosevelt  Theodore Roosevelt, Jr. ( ; October 27 1858  January 6 1919), also known as T.R., and to the public (but never to friends and intimates) as Teddy, was the twenty-sixth President of the United States, and a leader of the Republican Party and of the Progressive Movement.  

Has it been created with a long term perspective to support the development of Qatar and the wider region , develop local and regional markets , and strengthen the links between the energy based economies and global financial markets ?	Yes	S08/data/set2/a3

QUESTION TYPE: 4
It has been created with a long term perspective to support the development of Qatar and the wider region, develop local and regional markets, and strengthen the links between the energy based economies and global financial markets.

Who was born precisely at midnight during an electrical storm , to a Serbian family in the village of Smiljan near Gospić , in the Lika region of the Croatian Krajina in Military Frontier ( part of the Austrian Empire ) , in the present-day Croatia . ?	Nikola Tesla	S08/data/set4/a3

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Tesla', u'GPE'], [u'midnight', u'TIME'], [u'Serbian', u'NORP'], [u'Smiljan', u'GPE'], [u'Gospi\xc4\x87', u'GPE'], [u'Lika', u'GPE'], [u'the Croatian Krajina', u'LOC'], [u'the Austrian Empire)', u'GPE'], [u'Croatia', u'GPE']]
According to legend, Tesla was born precisely at midnight during an electrical storm, to a Serbian family in the village of Smiljan near Gospić, in the Lika region of the Croatian Krajina in Military Frontier (part of the Austrian Empire), in the present-day Croatia.

In what year were the "Games of the XV Olympiad" held?	1952	S08/data/set2/a4

QUESTION TYPE: 4

What suborder of turtles is extinct?	Paracryptodira	S08/data/set1/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Australian', u'NORP']]
Aquatic respiration in Australian freshwater turtles is currently being studied.

HWhat happened at the electromotive force -LRB- emf -RRB- of a galvanic cell?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

QUESTION TYPE: 4
That is, if the electrodes have emfs \mathcal{E}_{1,2} , then the net emf is \mathcal{E}_{2}-\mathcal{E}_{1} .

What is the smallest suborder of turtles?	Pleurodira	S08/data/set1/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'the Order Testudines', u'ORG'], [u'Chelonia', u'GPE']]
turtle  Turtles are reptilians of the Order Testudines (all living turtles belong to the crown group Chelonia), most of whose body is shielded by a special bony or cartilaginous shell developed from their ribs.

Did Millard Fillmore die on March 8, 1974?	no	S08/data/set3/a3

yes

Is the old ghana 500 miles?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

yes

What sort of turtles are ectothermic?	all of them	S08/data/set1/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: []
Like other reptiles, turtles are ectothermic (or "cold-blooded" Reptile blood isn't necessarily cold, as reptiles sun themselves and take other measures to stay warm. ).

Is the genius of the average the most convincing proof of $ his strength?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

no

What ac phaenomenis inde pendentibus?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Count Alessandro', u'PERSON'], [u'February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'1800', u'DATE']]
Alessandro_Volta  Count Alessandro Giuseppe Antonio Anastasio Volta (February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827) was an Italian physicist known especially for the development of the first known electric battery in 1800.   

When were the Great Sphinx and the Pyramids of Giza built?	During the Old Kingdom	S08/data/set2/a6

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Pyramids', u'DATE'], [u'Giza', u'GPE'], [u'Egypt', u'GPE']]
The Great Sphinx and the Pyramids of Giza, built during the Old Kingdom, are modern national icons that are at the heart of Egypt's thriving tourism industry.

What may a leopard be mistaken for?	A cheetah or a jaguar	S08/data/set1/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'One', u'CARDINAL']]
One of many spotted cats, a leopard may be mistaken for a cheetah or a jaguar.

Was Newton outraged , and went about the work to uncover anything about Chaloner ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a1

yes

What are a rumors that he remained a virgin?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: []
There are a rumours that he remained a virgin.

Who assassinated Lincoln?	John Wilkes Booth	S08/data/set3/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Abraham Lincoln', u'PERSON'], [u'Abraham Lincoln', u'PERSON'], [u'February 12, 1809', u'DATE'], [u'April 15, 1865', u'DATE'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'March 4, 1861', u'DATE']]

When did Adams graduate from college?	1755	S08/data/set3/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'John Adams', u'PERSON'], [u'October 30,1735', u'DATE'], [u'July 4, 1826', u'DATE'], [u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1797 1801', u'DATE']]
John_Adams  John Adams, Jr. (October 30,1735  July 4, 1826) was the second President of the United States (1797 1801).

What did Cleveland die from?	a heart attack	S08/data/set3/a6

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Grover Cleveland', u'PERSON'], [u'the Cleveland Family Papers', u'ORG'], [u'New Jersey', u'GPE']]
An early, undated photograph of Grover Cleveland from the Cleveland Family Papers at the New Jersey Archives.

Is it true that this contained the beginnings of the laws of motion?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a1

yes

Who did Wilson win in 1917?	Irish Americans	S08/data/set3/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'1917', u'DATE'], [u'Liberty', u'ORG'], [u'the War Industries Board', u'ORG']]
On the home front he began the first effective draft in 1917, raised billions through Liberty loans, imposed an income tax, set up the War Industries Board, promoted labor union growth, supervised agriculture and food production through the Lever Act, took over control of the railroads, and suppressed anti-war movements.

What carried with it a tacit recognition of Qatar's status as distinct from Bahrain?	The British Protectorate (per Colonel Lewis Pelly) asking to negotiate with a representative from Qatar after Bahrain's violation of the 1820 Anglo-Bahraini Treaty.	S08/data/set2/a3

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Qatar', u'GPE'], [u'Qatar', u'GPE'], [u' The', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Qatar', u'GPE'], [u'English', u'LANGUAGE']]
Qatar  Qatar ( ;  The pronunciation of Qatar in English varies; see List of words of disputed pronunciation for details.

Had his thermometer 100 for the freezing point of water and 0 for the boiling point ?	Yes it had	S08/data/set4/a5

QUESTION TYPE: 4
His thermometer had 100 for the freezing point of water and 0 for the boiling point.

Is Uruguay the smallest soverign nation in South America?	No	S08/data/set2/a9

yes

Why polar bear is a special species?	The World Conservation Union listed polar bears as a vulnerable species, one of three sub-categories of threatened status, in May 2006. Their latest estimate is that 7 out of 19 subpopulations are declining or already severely reduced.	S08/data/set1/a4

The polar bear is a vulnerable species at high risk of extinction.

What became one of the most important commercial and military centres of the British Empire?	Singapore	S08/data/set2/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'one', u'CARDINAL'], [u'the British Empire', u'ORG']]
It became one of the most important commercial and military centres of the British Empire.

Did Wilson support desegregation?	Not in the slightest.	S08/data/set3/a8

yes

What established a trading post on the island in 1819?	British East India Company 	S08/data/set2/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'1819', u'DATE']]
The British East India Company established a trading post on the island in 1819.

Where did Orang Laut people live?	Several hundred indigenous Orang Laut people also lived around the coast, rivers and smaller islands.	S08/data/set2/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'hundred', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Orang Laut', u'PERSON']]
Several hundred indigenous Orang Laut people also lived around the coast, rivers and smaller islands.

How do india and latin america relate?	Uruguay exports architectural services to India and Latin America	S08/data/set2/a9

Uruguay  Uruguay (official full name in ; pron.

What happened from tuberculosis?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

Calvin Coolidge  John Calvin Coolidge, Jr. (July 4 1872  January 5 1933), more commonly known as Calvin Coolidge, was the thirtieth President of the United States (1923–1929).


ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u' ', u'CARDINAL'], [u'the United States', u'GPE']]
It is the world's second largest country by total area,  and shares land borders with the United States to the south and northwest.

When is the first record of settlement in Singapore?	The first records of settlement in Singapore are from the second century AD.	S08/data/set2/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Singapore', u'GPE'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'Singapore', u'GPE'], [u'the second century', u'DATE']]
The Downtown Core of Singapore at dusk   The first records of settlement in Singapore are from the second century AD.  

Was Liechtenstein completed in November 2000?	No	S08/data/set2/a1

yes

What is actually black in color?	A polar bear's skin.	S08/data/set1/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Ursus', u'GPE'], [u'Arctic', u'LOC']]
polar bear  The polar bear (Ursus maritimus) is a bear native to the Arctic.

What was an Italian savant?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]
Amedeo Avogadro  Caricature of Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano Amedeo Carlo Avogadro, Count of Quaregna and Cerreto (August 9, 1776 July 9, 1856) was an Italian savant.

Was Woodrow Wilson the thirtieth President of the United States?	No	S08/data/set3/a8

yes

Where was Woodrow Wilson born?	Staunton, Virginia	S08/data/set3/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Thomas Woodrow Wilson', u'PERSON'], [u'Staunton', u'GPE'], [u'Virginia', u'GPE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'third', u'ORDINAL'], [u'four', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Joseph Wilson', u'PERSON'], [u'1822\xe2\x80\x931903', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Janet Woodrow', u'PERSON']]
Thomas Woodrow Wilson was born in Staunton, Virginia in 1856 as the third of four children to Reverend Dr. Joseph Wilson (1822–1903) and Janet Woodrow (1826–1888).

Why did Coolidge not attend law school?	cost	S08/data/set3/a9

The Vice Presidency did not carry many official duties, but Coolidge was invited by President Harding to attend cabinet meetings, making him the first Vice President to do so.

Who is the autonomous Åland Islands , where Finnish is not compulsory due to Swedish being the sole official language of the province . ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Islands', u'PERSON'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Swedish', u'NORP'], [u' ', u'GPE']]
The exception is the autonomous Åland Islands, where Finnish is not compulsory due to Swedish being the sole official language of the province.  

What are the largest and politically dominant ethnic group?	the Javanese	S08/data/set2/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Indonesia', u'GPE'], [u'The Republic of Indonesia', u'GPE'], [u'Southeast Asia', u'LOC']]
Indonesia  The Republic of Indonesia ( ) ( ), is a nation in Southeast Asia.

What happened in 1833?	blah blah blah	S08/data/set4/a8

Amedeo Avogadro  Caricature of Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano Amedeo Carlo Avogadro, Count of Quaregna and Cerreto (August 9, 1776 July 9, 1856) was an Italian savant.

The coastline is what?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

QUESTION TYPE: 4
The climate is tropical.

How much time to penguins spend on land?	They spend half of their life on land.	S08/data/set1/a3

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'half', u'CARDINAL'], [u'half', u'CARDINAL']]
They spend half of their life on land and half in the oceans.

How many species of beetles are there?	about 350,000	S08/data/set1/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'about 350,000', u'CARDINAL']]
There are about 350,000 species of beetles.

Did Mainland Nova Scotia not come under British rule with the Treaty of Utrecht    (: ; ?	no!	S08/data/set2/a8

yes

What is Monroe's daughter's name?	Maria Hester Monroe Gouverneur	S08/data/set3/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'James Monroe', u'PERSON'], [u'April 28, 1758 \xe2\x80\x93 July 4, 1831', u'DATE'], [u'fifth', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1817-1825', u'DATE']]
James_Monroe  James Monroe (April 28, 1758 – July 4, 1831) was the fifth President of the United States (1817-1825).

Is the electrolyte sulphuric acid?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

yes

How many square kilometres of continental land is Uruguay?	176,214 square kilometres	S08/data/set2/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Uruguay', u'GPE']]
The main sport in Uruguay is football.

How did newspapers respond to Roosevelt inviting Brooker T. Washington to dinner at the White House?	They outraged.	S08/data/set3/a7

Roosevelt pondered with his wife, Edith, how best to respond, not wanting to show up in Buffalo and wait on McKinley's death.

Was Grant's father-in-law a Democrat?	yup	S08/data/set3/a5

yes

Where was the League of Nations created?	Paris	S08/data/set3/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Paris', u'GPE'], [u'1919', u'DATE'], [u'the League of Nations', u'ORG'], [u'Treaty', u'LOC'], [u'Versailles', u'GPE']]
He went to Paris in 1919 to create the League of Nations and shape the Treaty of Versailles, with special attention on creating new nations out of defunct empires.

What was Roosevelt's justification for supporting desegregation of schools in New York?	that his children had been educated with other races and there was nothing wrong with it	S08/data/set3/a7

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u"Theodore Roosevelt's", u'PERSON'], [u'the Hidatsa Indians', u'ORG'], [u'today', u'DATE'], [u'the New York State Assembly', u'ORG']]
Some notable events in Theodore Roosevelt's life included: *Developing a close relationship with the Hidatsa Indians that is maintained today in the oral tradition of the tribe.  *Openly supporting a bill in the New York State Assembly which allowed desegregation of schools in the state, personally noting that his children had been educated with other races and there was nothing wrong with it.  

Where is the leopard distributed?	southern Eurasia and Africa, from Korea to South Africa and Spain	S08/data/set1/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Eurasia', u'GPE'], [u'Africa', u'LOC'], [u'Korea', u'GPE'], [u'South Africa', u'GPE'], [u'Spain', u'GPE'], [u'Africa', u'LOC']]
Once distributed across southern Eurasia and Africa, from Korea to South Africa and Spain, it has disappeared from much of its former range and now chiefly occurs in subsaharan Africa.

Is the capital city helsinki?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

no

When did organized agriculture appear in the Nile Valley?	About 6000 BC	S08/data/set2/a6

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'6000', u'CARDINAL'], [u'BC', u'ORG']]
By about 6000 BC, organized agriculture and large building construction had appeared in the Nile Valley.

What happened in moravia , lower austria , silesia , and styria , though in all cases , these territories were held in fief under other more senior feudal lords?	The Liechtenstein Dynasty acquired vast swaths of land	S08/data/set2/a1

Through the centuries, the dynasty acquired vast swathes of land, predominantly in Moravia, Lower Austria, Silesia, and Styria, though in all cases, these territories were held in fief under other more senior feudal lords, particularly under various lines of the Habsburg family, to whom several Liechtenstein princes served as close advisors.

When did James Monroe graduate from William and Mary?	1776	S08/data/set3/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'William', u'PERSON'], [u'Mary', u'PERSON'], [u'1776', u'DATE'], [u'Monroe', u'PERSON'], [u'the Continental Army', u'ORG'], [u'Trenton', u'GPE']]
After graduating from William and Mary in 1776, Monroe fought in the Continental Army, serving with distinction at the Battle of Trenton, where he was shot in his left shoulder.

What is the largest religious group in Canada?	Christian	S08/data/set2/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'North America', u'LOC'], [u'the Atlantic Ocean', u'LOC'], [u'the Pacific Ocean', u'ORG'], [u'the Arctic Ocean', u'LOC']]
Canada  Canada ( ) is a country occupying most of northern North America, extending from the Atlantic Ocean in the east to the Pacific Ocean in the west and northward into the Arctic Ocean.

These projections , called papillae , have what?	a rich blood supply	S08/data/set1/a9

QUESTION TYPE: 4
These projections, called "papillae", have a rich blood supply, and serve to increase the surface area of the cloaca.

What is the official language of Liechtenstein?	German	S08/data/set2/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Liechtenstein', u'GPE'], [u'Liechtenstein', u'GPE'], [u'Western Europe', u'LOC'], [u'Switzerland', u'GPE'], [u'Austria', u'GPE']]
Liechtenstein  The Principality of Liechtenstein ( ( , ( ) is a tiny, doubly landlocked alpine country in Western Europe, bordered by Switzerland to its west and by Austria to its east.

What does a citizen use to propose changes to the Constitution?	Plebiscite	S08/data/set2/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Uruguayan', u'NORP'], [u'Parliament', u'ORG'], [u'Constitution', u'LAW'], [u'Plebiscite', u'PERSON']]
The Uruguayan constitution allows citizens to challenge laws approved by Parliament by use of a Referendum, or to propose changes to the Constitution by the use of a Plebiscite.

Of what state was Coolidge governor?	Massachusetts	S08/data/set3/a9

QUESTION TYPE: 4
In 1897, Coolidge was admitted to the bar.

Which nation invaded Singapore during World War II?	During World War II, the Imperial Japanese Army invaded Malaya, culminating in the Battle of Singapore.	S08/data/set2/a2

QUESTION TYPE: 4
During World War II, the Imperial Japanese Army invaded Malaya, culminating in the Battle of Singapore.

What are prey of various animals including birds and mammals?	Beetles.	S08/data/set1/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: []
Some species are prey of various animals including birds and mammals.

Has Urbanization eliminated many areas of former primary rainforest , with the only remaining area of primary rainforest being Bukit Timah Nature Reserve ?	Yes	S08/data/set2/a2

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Urbanization has eliminated many areas of former primary rainforest, with the only remaining area of primary rainforest being Bukit Timah Nature Reserve.

What was Adams' political party?	Federalist	S08/data/set3/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'John Adams', u'PERSON'], [u'October 30,1735', u'DATE'], [u'July 4, 1826', u'DATE'], [u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1797 1801', u'DATE']]
John_Adams  John Adams, Jr. (October 30,1735  July 4, 1826) was the second President of the United States (1797 1801).

How long was Lincoln's legal Career?	23 years	S08/data/set3/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Donald', u'PERSON'], [u'1995', u'DATE'], [u'150', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'more than 5,100', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Illinois', u'GPE']]
Donald (1995), 150-51 Lincoln was involved in more than 5,100 cases in Illinois alone during his 23-year legal career.

What did Isaac Newton place at 3 April, AD 33, which agrees with one traditionally accepted date?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Jesus Christ', u'PERSON'], [u'3 April', u'DATE'], [u'33', u'CARDINAL'], [u'one', u'CARDINAL']]
He also placed the crucifixion of Jesus Christ at 3 April, AD 33, which agrees with one traditionally accepted date.

What did Roosevelt do to improve his physical condition?	He started boxing	S08/data/set3/a7

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Roosevelt', u'PERSON']]
During his presidency, Roosevelt tried but did not succeed to advance the cause of simplified spelling.

When was Liechtenstein's current constitution adopted?	October 1921	S08/data/set2/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u"Vaduz Liechtenstein's", u'GPE'], [u'October 1921', u'DATE']]
The Government building in Vaduz Liechtenstein's current constitution was adopted in October 1921.

When did Islam become the dominant religion in Java and Sumatra?	by the end of the 16th century	S08/data/set2/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Ricklefs', u'PERSON'], [u'1991', u'DATE'], [u'3', u'CARDINAL'], [u'14', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Indonesia', u'GPE'], [u'Islam', u'ORG'], [u'Java', u'GPE'], [u'Sumatra', u'GPE'], [u'the end of the 16th century', u'DATE']]
Ricklefs (1991), pages 3 to 14 Other Indonesia areas gradually adopted Islam which became the dominant religion in Java and Sumatra by the end of the 16th century.

What happened in 1745?	The scale was reversed	S08/data/set4/a5

Anders_Celsius Anders Celsius The observatory of Anders Celsius, from a contemporary engraving.

What is used to protect a vehicale from a Kangaroo?	roo bars	S08/data/set1/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'23', u'CARDINAL']]
Scientists are interested in the possibility of transferring the bacteria responsible from kangaroos to cattle, since the greenhouse gas effect of methane is 23 times greater than that of carbon dioxide.

Do they prefer forested areas?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a5

no

Which election did Grover Cleveland win?	1884 and 1892 presidential elections	S08/data/set3/a6

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Cleveland was elected again in 1892, thus becoming the only President in U.S. history to be elected to a second term which did not run in succession to the first.  

Was Lee Kuan Yew a successful leader of Singapore?	Yes.	S08/data/set2/a2

no

What are some economic uses for duck?	being farmed for their meat, eggs, feathers, (particularly their down)	S08/data/set1/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u' Duck', u'PERSON'], [u'Anatidae', u'PERSON']]
duck  Duck is the common name for a number of species in the Anatidae family of birds.

What is the study of beetles called?	coleopterology	S08/data/set1/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'the Melbourne Museum', u'ORG'], [u'Australia', u'GPE']]
Beetle collection at the Melbourne Museum, Australia The study of beetles is called coleopterology, and its practitioners are coleopterists.

How many times has Uruguay won the World Cup?	On two or more occasions.	S08/data/set2/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Uruguay', u'ORG'], [u'14', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Argentina', u'GPE']]
The Uruguay national team has also won the Copa América 14 different times, a record it shares with Argentina.

Did he not die at the age of 55 in Le Croisic ?	Yes he died at the age of 55	S08/data/set4/a9

yes

How much do sea otters weigh?	30 kg (about 65 pounds)	S08/data/set1/a7

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'1', u'CARDINAL'], [u'3', u'CARDINAL'], [u'5', u'CARDINAL'], [u'15 kg', u'QUANTITY'], [u'10 to 30', u'CARDINAL']]
They grow to 1 m (3 to 4 feet) in length and weigh from 5 to 15 kg (10 to 30 pounds).

How old was Lincoln in 1816?	seven	S08/data/set3/a4

Life of Abraham Lincoln, Colonel Ward H. Lamon, 1872 - portions reprinted in Chapter VIII: Abraham Lincoln, Deist, and Admirer of Thomas Paine, From the book Religious Beliefs of Our Presidents by Franklin Steiner (1936) Lincoln was just seven years old when, in 1816, the family was forced to make a new start in Perry County (now in Spencer County), Indiana.

What shape are a leopard's black rosettes in East Africa?	circular	S08/data/set1/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'East Africa', u'GPE'], [u'Africa', u'LOC']]
They are circular in East Africa but tend to be square in southern Africa. .

When was the Six Day War?	1967	S08/data/set2/a6

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Egypt', u'GPE'], [u'Egypt', u'GPE'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Kemet', u'PERSON'], [u'Coptic', u'NORP'], [u'  ', u'ORG'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Arab Republic', u'ORG'], [u'North Africa', u'GPE'], [u'the Sinai Peninsula', u'LOC'], [u'Asia', u'LOC']]
Egypt  Egypt (Egyptian: Kemet; Coptic:  Kīmi;   ; Egyptian Arabic: ), officially the Arab Republic of Egypt, is a country in North Africa that includes the Sinai Peninsula, a land bridge to Asia.

How many municipalities are within Oberland?	6	S08/data/set2/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Fifteen', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Oberland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Upper Country', u'ORG'], [u'ten', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Lower Country', u'ORG']]
Fifteen members are elected from the "Oberland" (Upper Country or region) and ten members are elected from the "Unterland" (Lower Country or region).

What do all turtles and tortoises breathe?	air	S08/data/set1/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: []
Even though many turtles spend large amounts of their lives underwater, all turtles and tortoises breathe air, and must surface at regular intervals to refill their lungs.

Where do sea turtles lay their eggs?	holes dug into mud or sand	S08/data/set1/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: []
Sea turtles lay their eggs on dry sandy beaches.

What European countries established states in Ghana?	Portugual, France, Britain, Netherlands	S08/data/set2/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'European', u'NORP'], [u'Portuguese', u'NORP'], [u'the 15th century', u'DATE'], [u'British', u'NORP'], [u'Gold Coast', u'PERSON'], [u'1874', u'DATE']]
Trade with European states flourished after contact with the Portuguese in the 15th century, and the British established a crown colony, Gold Coast, in 1874.

Who determined the dependence of the boiling of water with atmospheric pressure?	Anders Celsius	S08/data/set4/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: []
He determined the dependence of the boiling of water with atmospheric pressure (in excellent agreement with modern data).

Does the economy not depend heavily on exports refining imported goods , especially in manufacturing ?	No	S08/data/set2/a2

yes

What was controlled by Sundiata in 1240 AD, and absorbed into the larger Mali Empire?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Sundiata', u'GPE'], [u'1240', u'DATE'], [u'Mali Empire', u'ORG']]
It was controlled by Sundiata in 1240 AD, and absorbed into the larger Mali Empire.

Where do joeys complete postnatal development?	A pouch called a marsupium	S08/data/set1/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Macropodidae', u'PERSON']]
kangaroo  A kangaroo is a marsupial from the family Macropodidae (macropods, meaning 'large foot').

What is responsible for converting the hydrogen byproduct of fermentation into acetate?	The digestive system of a kangaroo	S08/data/set1/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Macropodidae', u'PERSON']]
kangaroo  A kangaroo is a marsupial from the family Macropodidae (macropods, meaning 'large foot').

Can polar bears be seen under infrared photography?	Only their breath and muzzles can be easily seen	S08/data/set1/a4

QUESTION TYPE: 4
The thick undercoat does, however, insulate the bears: they overheat at temperatures above 10 °C (50 °F), and are nearly invisible under infrared photography; only their breath and muzzles can be easily seen.

Where did Wilson attend law school?	University of Virginia	S08/data/set3/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Link, Wilson I:5', u'ORG'], [u'Wilson Papers', u'PERSON'], [u'130', u'CARDINAL'], [u'245', u'CARDINAL'], [u'314', u'CARDINAL'], [u'1879', u'DATE'], [u'Wilson', u'PERSON'], [u'University of Virginia', u'ORG']]
Link, Wilson I:5-6; Wilson Papers I: 130, 245, 314 In 1879, Wilson attended law school at University of Virginia for one year but he never graduated.

What does a polar bear's fur provide?	A polar bear's fur provides camouflage and insulation	S08/data/set1/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: []
A polar bear's fur provides camouflage and insulation.

Who was the first to perform and publish careful experiments aiming at the definition of an international temperature scale on scientific grounds ?	Anders Celsius	S08/data/set4/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'first', u'ORDINAL']]
Anders Celsius was the first to perform and publish careful experiments aiming at the definition of an international temperature scale on scientific grounds.

What is the Arabic word for municipalities?	baladiyah	S08/data/set2/a3

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Qatar', u'GPE'], [u'Qatar', u'GPE'], [u' The', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Qatar', u'GPE'], [u'English', u'LANGUAGE']]
Qatar  Qatar ( ;  The pronunciation of Qatar in English varies; see List of words of disputed pronunciation for details.

Who was the elder of two children of John Calvin Sr and Victoria Coolidge?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'John Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'July 4 1872', u'DATE'], [u'January 5 1933', u'DATE'], [u'Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1923\xe2\x80\x931929', u'PERSON']]
Calvin Coolidge  John Calvin Coolidge, Jr. (July 4 1872  January 5 1933), more commonly known as Calvin Coolidge, was the thirtieth President of the United States (1923–1929).

Who was, by later reports of his contemporaries, thoroughly unhappy with the work?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: []
He was, by later reports of his contemporaries, thoroughly unhappy with the work.

Where was Commodore Matthew C. Perry sent to open Japan to Western trade?	Commodore Matthew C. Perry send to Japan	S08/data/set3/a3

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'August 6, 1850', u'DATE'], [u'Congress', u'ORG'], [u'Texas', u'GPE'], [u'New Mexico', u'GPE']]
On August 6, 1850, he sent a message to Congress recommending that Texas be paid to abandon its claims to part of New Mexico.

What shares land borders with Papua New Guinea, East Timor and Malaysia?	Indonesia	S08/data/set2/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Papua New Guinea', u'ORG'], [u'East Timor', u'ORG'], [u'Malaysia', u'GPE']]
The country shares land borders with Papua New Guinea, East Timor and Malaysia.

Who asked a nearby local what the creatures were called?	Captain James Cook and naturalist Sir Joseph Banks	S08/data/set1/a1

ENTITY QUESTION: []
They asked a nearby local what the creatures were called.

Who dismantled partisan and sectional coalitions ?	many congressmen	S08/data/set3/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'James Monroe', u'PERSON'], [u'April 28, 1758 \xe2\x80\x93 July 4, 1831', u'DATE'], [u'fifth', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1817-1825', u'DATE']]
James_Monroe  James Monroe (April 28, 1758 – July 4, 1831) was the fifth President of the United States (1817-1825).

How many years after Cleveland left office did the U.S. win the Spanish-American War?	one	S08/data/set3/a6

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'U.S.', u'GPE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'1898', u'DATE'], [u'one year', u'DATE']]
His administration is credited with the modernization of the United States Navy that allowed the U.S. to decisively win the Spanish-American War in 1898, one year after he left office.

How many children did Grover Cleveland have?	Six.	S08/data/set3/a6

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Fareed Zakaria', u'ORG'], [u'Cleveland', u'GPE'], [u'U.S.', u'GPE']]
As Fareed Zakaria argued, "But while Cleveland retarded the speed and aggressiveness of U.S. foreign policy, the overall direction did not change."  

What expression is part of a conceptual framework for testing computer systems?	Quacks like a duck	S08/data/set1/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Duck', u'PERSON']]
The expression is part of a conceptual framework for testing (see Duck test) of some computer systems.

Which Russian army general conquered Finland in 1809?	Alexander I	S08/data/set2/a4

QUESTION TYPE: 4
On March 29 1809, after being conquered by the armies of Alexander I of Russia in the Finnish War, Finland became an autonomous Grand Duchy in the Russian Empire until the end of 1917.

What is a hybrid animal resulting from a union between a leopard and a puma?	A pumapard	S08/data/set1/a2

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Pumapard, Rothschild Museum', u'ORG'], [u'Tring A', u'ORG']]
link title   Pumapard, Rothschild Museum, Tring A pumapard is a hybrid animal resulting from a union between a leopard and a puma.

What period of rapid economic growth did the United States experience during Coolidge's presidency?	the "Roaring Twenties"	S08/data/set3/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Grace', u'ORG']]
Grace's reply was "Did you marry me to darn your socks?"

Do penguins have a better than average sense of hearing for birds?	No	S08/data/set1/a3

yes

What did Canada adopt in 1965?	The Maple Leaf Flag	S08/data/set2/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'Maple Leaf Flag', u'FAC'], [u'1965', u'DATE']]
Canada adopted its current Maple Leaf Flag in 1965.

What happened in 1764?	Adams married Abigail Smith	S08/data/set3/a1

John_Adams  John Adams, Jr. (October 30,1735  July 4, 1826) was the second President of the United States (1797 1801).

Who was first apprenticed to a fuller to learn the cloth-making trade?	millard fillmore	S08/data/set3/a3

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'first', u'ORDINAL']]
He was first apprenticed to a fuller to learn the cloth-making trade.

What do turtle eggs preared to eat consist mainly of?	Yolk	S08/data/set1/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'the Order Testudines', u'ORG'], [u'Chelonia', u'GPE']]
turtle  Turtles are reptilians of the Order Testudines (all living turtles belong to the crown group Chelonia), most of whose body is shielded by a special bony or cartilaginous shell developed from their ribs.

Sea otters eat what?	Shellfish and other invertebrates	S08/data/set1/a7

QUESTION TYPE: 4
For example Eurasian otters must eat 15% of their body-weight a day, and sea otters, 20 to 25%, depending on the temperature.

What is one of the challenges of re-establishing a population of Eurasian otters in the UK?	Roadkill deaths have become one of the significant threats to the success of their re-establishment. 	S08/data/set1/a7

ENTITY QUESTION: []
otter  Otters are amphibious (or in one case aquatic) carnivorous mammals.

Is it true that he married louise désirée lorieux in 1890?	yes	S08/data/set4/a9

no

What is Jakarta?	Indonesia's special capital region	S08/data/set2/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Indonesia', u'GPE'], [u'The Republic of Indonesia', u'GPE'], [u'Southeast Asia', u'LOC']]
Indonesia  The Republic of Indonesia ( ) ( ), is a nation in Southeast Asia.

What economic uses to ducks have?	They can be farmed for meat, eggs, and feathers	S08/data/set1/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: []
Most ducks have a wide flat beak adapted for dredging.

What insulate it against the cold?	Its think blubber and fur.	S08/data/set1/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Ursus', u'GPE'], [u'Arctic', u'LOC']]
polar bear  The polar bear (Ursus maritimus) is a bear native to the Arctic.

What field did Woodrow Wilson leave law practice to study?	Government	S08/data/set3/a8

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Wilson', u'PERSON'], [u'about 12 years old', u'DATE']]
Wilson did not learn to read until he was about 12 years old.

What animals are related to otters?	weasels, polecats, and badgers	S08/data/set1/a7

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Native American', u'NORP']]
In some Native American cultures, otters are considered totem animals.

Oxygen is what?	One kind of gas obtained via a tracheal system.	S08/data/set1/a8

QUESTION TYPE: 4
beetle  Beetles are a group of insects which have the largest number of species.

A semi-aquatic marine mammal , the polar bear has what?	It has adapted for life on a combination of land, sea, and ice.	S08/data/set1/a4

QUESTION TYPE: 4
A semi-aquatic marine mammal, the polar bear has adapted for life on a combination of land, sea, and ice, and is the apex predator within its range.

Did James Monroe attend the College of William and Mary?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a2

no

What do turles use to breathe in the water?	Papillae	S08/data/set1/a9

ENTITY QUESTION: []
The turtles can take up dissolved oxygen from the water using these papillae, in much the same way that fish use gills to respire.

What does the word duck mean?	to bend down low as if to get under something	S08/data/set1/a10

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u' Duck', u'PERSON'], [u'Anatidae', u'PERSON']]
duck  Duck is the common name for a number of species in the Anatidae family of birds.

Are Kangaroos Shy?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a1

no

Is it true that he appointed stone to the supreme court?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

yes

Is it true that the portuguese came to ghana in the 15th century?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

yes

What is the dominant religion in Ghana?	christian	S08/data/set2/a5

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]
Ghana  The Republic of Ghana is a country in West Africa.

Have coleopterists formed organisations to facilitate the study of beetles ?	Yes.	S08/data/set1/a8

QUESTION TYPE: 4
Coleopterists have formed organisations to facilitate the study of beetles.

Why are side-necked turtles called side-necked turtles?	The way they withdraw their heads into their shells.	S08/data/set1/a9

The Pleurodira are sometimes known as the side-necked turtles, a reference to the way they withdraw their heads into their shells.

When did Lincoln begin his political career?	1832.	S08/data/set3/a4

ENTITY QUESTION: [[u'Abraham', u'PERSON'], [u'1832', u'DATE'], [u'age 23', u'DATE'], [u'the Illinois General Assembly', u'ORG'], [u'the Whig Party', u'ORG']]
Young Abraham Lincoln Lincoln began his political career in 1832, at age 23, with an unsuccessful campaign for the Illinois General Assembly, as a member of the Whig Party.

Did John Adams get along with Alexander Hamilton?	no	S08/data/set3/a1

yes

How has Canada helped UN peacekeeping efforts?	Canada has played a leading role in UN peacekeeping efforts. During the Suez Crisis of 1956, Lester B. Pearson eased tensions by proposing the inception of the United Nations Peacekeeping Force. Canada has since served in 50 peacekeeping missions, including every UN peacekeeping effort until 1989	S08/data/set2/a8

In February 2007, Canada, Italy, Britain, Norway, and Russia announced their funding commitments to launch a $1.5 billion project to help develop vaccines they said could save millions of lives in poor nations, and called on others to join them. "
