Did Lincoln sign the National Banking Act of 1863?	yes	S08/data/set3/a4

no

Did Lincoln sign the National Banking Act of 1863?	Yes.	S08/data/set3/a4

no

How many long was Lincoln's formal education?	18 months	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'2', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'about 18 months', u'DATE']]

How many long was Lincoln's formal education?	18 months.	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'2', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'about 18 months', u'DATE']]

When did Lincoln begin his political career?	1832	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'Abraham', u'PERSON'], [u'1832', u'DATE'], [u'age 23', u'DATE'], [u'the Illinois General Assembly', u'ORG'], [u'the Whig Party', u'ORG']]

When did Lincoln begin his political career?	1832.	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'Abraham', u'PERSON'], [u'1832', u'DATE'], [u'age 23', u'DATE'], [u'the Illinois General Assembly', u'ORG'], [u'the Whig Party', u'ORG']]

What did The Legal Tender Act of 1862 establish?	the United States Note, the first paper currency in United States history	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'1862', u'DATE'], [u'the United States Note', u'GPE'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'United States', u'GPE']]

What did The Legal Tender Act of 1862 establish?	The United States Note, the first paper currency in United States history.	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'1862', u'DATE'], [u'the United States Note', u'GPE'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'United States', u'GPE']]

Who suggested Lincoln grow a beard?	11-year-old Grace Bedell	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'297', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'1860', u'DATE'], [u'11-year-old', u'DATE'], [u'Grace Bedell', u'PERSON']]

Who suggested Lincoln grow a beard?	Grace Bedell.	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'297', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'1860', u'DATE'], [u'11-year-old', u'DATE'], [u'Grace Bedell', u'PERSON']]

When did the Gettysburg address argue that America was born?	1776	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'John Wilkes Booth', u'PERSON'], [u'David Herold', u'PERSON'], [u'Lewis Powell', u'PERSON'], [u'George Atzerodt', u'PERSON'], [u'John Surratt', u'PERSON'], [u'Edmund Spangler', u'PERSON'], [u'Gettysburg', u'GPE'], [u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'American', u'NORP'], [u'1789', u'DATE'], [u'1776', u'DATE'], [u'Liberty', u'ORG']]

When did the Gettysburg address argue that America was born?	1776.	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'John Wilkes Booth', u'PERSON'], [u'David Herold', u'PERSON'], [u'Lewis Powell', u'PERSON'], [u'George Atzerodt', u'PERSON'], [u'John Surratt', u'PERSON'], [u'Edmund Spangler', u'PERSON'], [u'Gettysburg', u'GPE'], [u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'American', u'NORP'], [u'1789', u'DATE'], [u'1776', u'DATE'], [u'Liberty', u'ORG']]

Did Lincoln beat John C. Breckinridge in the 1860 election?	yes	S08/data/set3/a4

no

Did Lincoln beat John C. Breckinridge in the 1860 election?	Yes.	S08/data/set3/a4

no

Did Lincoln start his political career in 1832?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a4

no

Did Lincoln start his political career in 1832?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a4

no

Which county was Lincoln born in?	Hardin County	S08/data/set3/a4

Robert Todd Lincoln was born in Springfield, Illinois on 1 August, 1843.

Which county was Lincoln born in?	Southeast Hardin County, Kentucky	S08/data/set3/a4

Robert Todd Lincoln was born in Springfield, Illinois on 1 August, 1843.

When did Lincoln first serve as President?	March 4, 1861	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'Abraham Lincoln', u'PERSON'], [u'February 12, 1809', u'DATE'], [u'April 15, 1865', u'DATE'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'March 4, 1861', u'DATE']]

When did Lincoln first serve as President?	March 4, 1861	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'Abraham Lincoln', u'PERSON'], [u'February 12, 1809', u'DATE'], [u'April 15, 1865', u'DATE'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'March 4, 1861', u'DATE']]

Who assassinated Lincoln?	John Wilkes Booth	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'Abraham Lincoln', u'PERSON'], [u'February 12, 1809', u'DATE'], [u'April 15, 1865', u'DATE'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'March 4, 1861', u'DATE']]

Who assassinated Lincoln?	John Wilkes Booth	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'Abraham Lincoln', u'PERSON'], [u'February 12, 1809', u'DATE'], [u'April 15, 1865', u'DATE'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'March 4, 1861', u'DATE']]

Did Lincoln win the election of 1860?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a4

no

Did Lincoln win the election of 1860?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a4

no

Who was the general in charge at the Battle of Antietam?	General McClellan	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'Abraham Lincoln', u'PERSON'], [u'February 12, 1809', u'DATE'], [u'April 15, 1865', u'DATE'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'March 4, 1861', u'DATE']]

Who was the general in charge at the Battle of Antietam?	John Alexander McClernand	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'Abraham Lincoln', u'PERSON'], [u'February 12, 1809', u'DATE'], [u'April 15, 1865', u'DATE'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'March 4, 1861', u'DATE']]

Why did Lincoln issue the Emancipation Proclamation?	To free slaves 	S08/data/set3/a4

He introduced measures that resulted in the abolition of slavery, issuing his Emancipation Proclamation in 1863 and promoting the passage of the Thirteenth Amendment to the Constitution in 1865.

Why did Lincoln issue the Emancipation Proclamation?	The goal was to weaken the rebellion, which was led and controlled by slave owners.	S08/data/set3/a4

He introduced measures that resulted in the abolition of slavery, issuing his Emancipation Proclamation in 1863 and promoting the passage of the Thirteenth Amendment to the Constitution in 1865.

Do scholars rank lincoln among the top three presidents?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a4

no

Do scholars rank lincoln among the top three presidents?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a4

no

Did lincoln have 18 months of schooling?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a4

no

Did lincoln have 18 months of schooling?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a4

no

Was Lincoln chosen as a presidential candidate in 1860?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a4

no

Was Lincoln chosen as a presidential candidate in 1860?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a4

no

How old was Lincoln in 1816?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a4

Life of Abraham Lincoln, Colonel Ward H. Lamon, 1872 - portions reprinted in Chapter VIII: Abraham Lincoln, Deist, and Admirer of Thomas Paine, From the book Religious Beliefs of Our Presidents by Franklin Steiner (1936) Lincoln was just seven years old when, in 1816, the family was forced to make a new start in Perry County (now in Spencer County), Indiana.

How old was Lincoln in 1816?	seven	S08/data/set3/a4

Life of Abraham Lincoln, Colonel Ward H. Lamon, 1872 - portions reprinted in Chapter VIII: Abraham Lincoln, Deist, and Admirer of Thomas Paine, From the book Religious Beliefs of Our Presidents by Franklin Steiner (1936) Lincoln was just seven years old when, in 1816, the family was forced to make a new start in Perry County (now in Spencer County), Indiana.

When was the first photgraph of lincoln taken?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'Rail Candidate', u'GPE'], [u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'1860', u'DATE'], [u'New York Tribune', u'ORG'], [u'Horace Greeley', u'PERSON'], [u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'February 27, 1860', u'DATE'], [u'New York City', u'GPE'], [u'Mathew Brady', u'PERSON'], [u'Cooper Union', u'ORG']]

When was the first photgraph of lincoln taken?	1846	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'Rail Candidate', u'GPE'], [u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'1860', u'DATE'], [u'New York Tribune', u'ORG'], [u'Horace Greeley', u'PERSON'], [u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'February 27, 1860', u'DATE'], [u'New York City', u'GPE'], [u'Mathew Brady', u'PERSON'], [u'Cooper Union', u'ORG']]

How long was Lincoln's legal Career?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'Donald', u'PERSON'], [u'1995', u'DATE'], [u'150', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'more than 5,100', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Illinois', u'GPE']]

How long was Lincoln's legal Career?	23 years	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'Donald', u'PERSON'], [u'1995', u'DATE'], [u'150', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Lincoln', u'ORG'], [u'more than 5,100', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Illinois', u'GPE']]

What trail did Lincoln use a Farmers' Almanac in? 	NULL	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'Lincoln', u'ORG']]

What trail did Lincoln use a Farmers' Almanac in? 	he defended William "Duff" Armstrong	S08/data/set3/a4

[[u'Lincoln', u'ORG']]

Did Abraham Lincoln live in the Frontier?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a4

no

Did Abraham Lincoln live in the Frontier?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a4

no

Did Lincoln's Wife's Family support slavery?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a4

no

Did Lincoln's Wife's Family support slavery?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a4

no

Volta became professor of physics in the Como high school in what year?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

  Count Alessandro Giuseppe Antonio Anastasio Volta (February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827) was an Italian physicist known especially for the development of the first known electric battery in 1800.   

What ac phaenomenis inde pendentibus?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

[[u'Count Alessandro', u'PERSON'], [u'February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'1800', u'DATE']]

What may be called Volta's Law of the electrochemical series?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

[[u"Volta's Law", u'LAW']]

Is it true that volta became professor of physics?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

yes

Is it true that volta entered retirement in spain?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

yes

When did he become professor?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

[[u'Count Alessandro', u'PERSON'], [u'February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'1800', u'DATE']]

What did Alessandro Volta publish in 1800?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10


Is Volta buried in the city of Como?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

yes

Is the electrolyte sulphuric acid?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

yes

	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

  Count Alessandro Giuseppe Antonio Anastasio Volta (February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827) was an Italian physicist known especially for the development of the first known electric battery in 1800.   

	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

  Count Alessandro Giuseppe Antonio Anastasio Volta (February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827) was an Italian physicist known especially for the development of the first known electric battery in 1800.   

	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

  Count Alessandro Giuseppe Antonio Anastasio Volta (February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827) was an Italian physicist known especially for the development of the first known electric battery in 1800.   

NOTTTT  FOUND	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

  Count Alessandro Giuseppe Antonio Anastasio Volta (February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827) was an Italian physicist known especially for the development of the first known electric battery in 1800.   

	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

  Count Alessandro Giuseppe Antonio Anastasio Volta (February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827) was an Italian physicist known especially for the development of the first known electric battery in 1800.   

	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

  Count Alessandro Giuseppe Antonio Anastasio Volta (February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827) was an Italian physicist known especially for the development of the first known electric battery in 1800.   

Are Count Volta 's original instruments and papers on display there ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

no

Is Volta buried in the city of Como ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

yes

Was his 1800 paper written in French ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

yes

Are Count Volta 's original instruments and papers on display there ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

no

Did he not realize that the frog 's leg served as both a conductor of electricity -LRB- we would now call it an electrolyte -RRB- and as a detector of electricity ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

no

Does this not make the zinc rod the negative electrode and the copper rod the positive electrode ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

yes

What happened with $ its invention?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

[[u'Count Alessandro', u'PERSON'], [u'February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'1800', u'DATE']]

HWhat happened at the electromotive force -LRB- emf -RRB- of a galvanic cell?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

That is, if the electrodes have emfs \mathcal{E}_{1,2} , then the net emf is \mathcal{E}_{2}-\mathcal{E}_{1} .

What happened in 1800?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a10

[[u'Count Alessandro', u'PERSON'], [u'February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'1800', u'DATE']]

What was an Italian savant?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

What was an Italian savant?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

Who is most noted for his contributions to the theory of molarity and molecular weight?	Amedeo Avogadro	S08/data/set4/a8

[]

Who is most noted for his contributions to the theory of molarity and molecular weight?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

[]

Who is most noted for his contributions to the theory of molarity and molecular weight?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

[]

Who graduated in ecclesiastical law at the early age of 20 and began to practice?	Amedeo Avogadro	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'the early age', u'DATE'], [u'20', u'CARDINAL']]

Who graduated in ecclesiastical law at the early age of 20 and began to practice?	blah	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'the early age', u'DATE'], [u'20', u'CARDINAL']]

Who graduated in ecclesiastical law at the early age of 20 and began to practice?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'the early age', u'DATE'], [u'20', u'CARDINAL']]

When did he publish another memoria?	1821	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

When did he publish another memoria?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

When did he publish another memoria?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

When did he become a professor?	1820	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

When did he become a professor?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

When did he become a professor?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

Is it true that he became a professor in 1820?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

yes

Is it true that he became a professor in 1820?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

yes

Was Lorenzo Romano Amedeo Carlo Avogadro an Italian savant?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

yes

Was Lorenzo Romano Amedeo Carlo Avogadro an Italian savant?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

yes

Was Amedeo Avogadro born in Turin August 9th 1776 to a noble ancient family of Piedmont, Italy?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

yes

Was Amedeo Avogadro born in Turin August 9th 1776 to a noble ancient family of Piedmont, Italy?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

yes

Is he most noted for his contributions to the theory of molarity and molecular weight?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

yes

Is he most noted for his contributions to the theory of molarity and molecular weight?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

yes

	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

 Caricature of Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano Amedeo Carlo Avogadro, Count of Quaregna and Cerreto (August 9, 1776 July 9, 1856) was an Italian savant.

	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

 Caricature of Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano Amedeo Carlo Avogadro, Count of Quaregna and Cerreto (August 9, 1776 July 9, 1856) was an Italian savant.

	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

 Caricature of Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano Amedeo Carlo Avogadro, Count of Quaregna and Cerreto (August 9, 1776 July 9, 1856) was an Italian savant.

	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

 Caricature of Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano Amedeo Carlo Avogadro, Count of Quaregna and Cerreto (August 9, 1776 July 9, 1856) was an Italian savant.

	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

 Caricature of Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano Amedeo Carlo Avogadro, Count of Quaregna and Cerreto (August 9, 1776 July 9, 1856) was an Italian savant.

	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

 Caricature of Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano Amedeo Carlo Avogadro, Count of Quaregna and Cerreto (August 9, 1776 July 9, 1856) was an Italian savant.

Who confirm that he sponsored and helped some Sardinian plotters who were organising a revolution in that island , stopped at the very last moment by the concession of Charles Albert 's statute ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'Sardinian', u'NORP'], [u"Charles Albert's", u'PERSON']]

Who confirm that he sponsored and helped some Sardinian plotters who were organising a revolution in that island , stopped at the very last moment by the concession of Charles Albert 's statute ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'Sardinian', u'NORP'], [u"Charles Albert's", u'PERSON']]

He is what?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

 Caricature of Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano Amedeo Carlo Avogadro, Count of Quaregna and Cerreto (August 9, 1776 July 9, 1856) was an Italian savant.

He is what?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

 Caricature of Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano Amedeo Carlo Avogadro, Count of Quaregna and Cerreto (August 9, 1776 July 9, 1856) was an Italian savant.

The unification of Italy did what?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

The unification of Italy did not happen during the life time of Avogadro.

Was King Victor Emmanuel III there to pay homage to Avogadro ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

yes

Was King Victor Emmanuel III there to pay homage to Avogadro ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

yes

Is Avogadro 's number commonly used to compute the results of chemical reactions ?	yes	S08/data/set4/a8

no

Is Avogadro 's number commonly used to compute the results of chemical reactions ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

no

Is Avogadro 's number commonly used to compute the results of chemical reactions ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

no

Is it approximately 6.0221415 10 23 ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

no

Is it approximately 6.0221415 10 23 ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

no

Did the scientific community not reserve great attention to his theory ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

yes

Did the scientific community not reserve great attention to his theory ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

yes

Does it not allow chemists to determine the exact amounts of substances produced in a given reaction ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

yes

Does it not allow chemists to determine the exact amounts of substances produced in a given reaction ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

yes

Was King Victor Emmanuel III there to pay homage to Avogadro ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

yes

Was King Victor Emmanuel III there to pay homage to Avogadro ?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

yes

Can the title of this famous 1811 paper be roughly translated into english?	yes	S08/data/set4/a8

The title of this famous 1811 paper can be roughly translated into English as "Essay on Determining the Relative Masses of the Elementary Molecules of Bodies".

Can the title of this famous 1811 paper be roughly translated into english?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

The title of this famous 1811 paper can be roughly translated into English as "Essay on Determining the Relative Masses of the Elementary Molecules of Bodies".

Can the title of this famous 1811 paper be roughly translated into english?		S08/data/set4/a8

The title of this famous 1811 paper can be roughly translated into English as "Essay on Determining the Relative Masses of the Elementary Molecules of Bodies".

What happened in french?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

What happened in french?		S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

What happened in 1833?	Avogadro had been recalled to Turin university	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

What happened in 1833?	NULL	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

What happened in 1833?	blah blah blah	S08/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

Who determined the dependence of the boiling of water with atmospheric pressure?	Anders Celsius	S08/data/set4/a5

[]

What is named after him?	The Celsius crater on the Moon	S08/data/set4/a5

[[u' Anders Celsius', u'PERSON'], [u'Anders Celsius', u'GPE']]

When did he publish a collection?	1733	S08/data/set4/a5

[[u' Anders Celsius', u'PERSON'], [u'Anders Celsius', u'GPE']]

Was Anders Celsius (November 27, 1701 April 25, 1744) a Swedish astronomer?	Yes	S08/data/set4/a5

no

Is The Celsius crater on the Moon named after him?	Yes	S08/data/set4/a5

no

Who was the first to perform and publish careful experiments aiming at the definition of an international temperature scale on scientific grounds ?	Anders Celsius	S08/data/set4/a5

[[u'first', u'ORDINAL']]

The Celsius crater on the Moon is what?	named after him	S08/data/set4/a5

The Celsius crater on the Moon is named after him.

Is the Celsius crater on the Moon named after him ?	Yes	S08/data/set4/a5

no

Had his thermometer 100 for the freezing point of water and 0 for the boiling point ?	Yes it had	S08/data/set4/a5

His thermometer had 100 for the freezing point of water and 0 for the boiling point.

Is the Celsius crater on the Moon named after him ?	Yes	S08/data/set4/a5

no

Did he not determine the dependence of the boiling of water with atmospheric pressure -LRB- in excellent agreement with modern data -RRB- ?	Yes he did	S08/data/set4/a5

no

What happened from 1730 to 1744?	He was professor of astronomy at Uppsala University	S08/data/set4/a5

[[u' Anders Celsius', u'PERSON'], [u'Anders Celsius', u'GPE']]

What happened in 1745?	The scale was reversed	S08/data/set4/a5

[[u' Anders Celsius', u'PERSON'], [u'Anders Celsius', u'GPE']]

Are beetles insects?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a8

no

Are beetles insects?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a8

no

Can beetles be found in polar regions?	No	S08/data/set1/a8

Beetles can be found in almost all habitats, but are not known to occur in the sea or in the polar regions.

Can beetles be found in polar regions?	No	S08/data/set1/a8

Beetles can be found in almost all habitats, but are not known to occur in the sea or in the polar regions.

Do beetles antennae function primarily as organs of smell?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a8

no

Do beetles antennae function primarily as organs of smell?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a8

no

What are the three sections of a beetle?	the head, the thorax, and the abdomen	S08/data/set1/a8

[]

What are the three sections of a beetle?	The head, the thorax, and the abdomen	S08/data/set1/a8

[]

Which defense mechanism uses colour or shape to deceive potential enemies?	mimicry	S08/data/set1/a8

Another defence that often uses colour or shape to deceive potential enemies is mimicry.

Which defense mechanism uses colour or shape to deceive potential enemies?	Mimicry	S08/data/set1/a8

Another defence that often uses colour or shape to deceive potential enemies is mimicry.

Which type of beetle is a pest of potato plants?	Colorado potato beetle	S08/data/set1/a8

These include the following: * The Colorado potato beetle, Leptinotarsa decemlineata, is a notorious pest of potato plants.

Which type of beetle is a pest of potato plants?	Colorado potato beetle	S08/data/set1/a8

These include the following: * The Colorado potato beetle, Leptinotarsa decemlineata, is a notorious pest of potato plants.

How can beetle larvae be differentiated from other insect larvae?	their hardened, often darkened head, the presence of chewing mouthparts, and spiracles along the sides of the body	S08/data/set1/a8

Beetle larvae can be differentiated from other insect larvae by their hardened, often darkened head, the presence of chewing mouthparts, and spiracles along the sides of the body.

How can beetle larvae be differentiated from other insect larvae?	By their hardened, often darkened head, the presence of chewing mouthparts, and spiracles along the sides of the body	S08/data/set1/a8

Beetle larvae can be differentiated from other insect larvae by their hardened, often darkened head, the presence of chewing mouthparts, and spiracles along the sides of the body.

What do beetles eat?	Some are generalists, eating both plants and animals. Other beetles are highly specialised in their diet.	S08/data/set1/a8

[]

What do beetles eat?	They often feed on plants and fungi, break down animal and plant debris, and eat other invertebrates	S08/data/set1/a8

[]

What are the similarities between beetles and grasshoppers?	mouthparts	S08/data/set1/a8

[]

What are the similarities between beetles and grasshoppers?	Beetles have mouthparts similar to those of grasshoppers	S08/data/set1/a8

[]

Are certain species of beetles considered pests?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a8

no

Are certain species of beetles considered pests?	yes	S08/data/set1/a8

no

Is a beetle's general anatomy uniform?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a8

no

Is a beetle's general anatomy uniform?	yes	S08/data/set1/a8

no

Are beetles endopterygotes?	yes	S08/data/set1/a8

no

Are beetles endopterygotes?	yes	S08/data/set1/a8

no

How many species of beetles are there?	350,000	S08/data/set1/a8

[[u'about 350,000', u'CARDINAL']]

How many species of beetles are there?	about 350,000	S08/data/set1/a8

[[u'about 350,000', u'CARDINAL']]

When are sperm cells transferred to the female?	during pairing	S08/data/set1/a8

[]

When are sperm cells transferred to the female?	During pairing	S08/data/set1/a8

[]

What is the study of beetles called?	coleopterology	S08/data/set1/a8

[[u'the Melbourne Museum', u'ORG'], [u'Australia', u'GPE']]

What is the study of beetles called?	coleopterology	S08/data/set1/a8

[[u'the Melbourne Museum', u'ORG'], [u'Australia', u'GPE']]

Is the Adephaga suborder larger than the Polyphaga suborder?	yes	S08/data/set1/a8

no

What are prey of various animals including birds and mammals?	Beetles.	S08/data/set1/a8

[]

What was given by Aristotle for the hardened shield like forewings?	The name "Coleoptera".	S08/data/set1/a8

[[u'Coleoptera', u'ORG'], [u'Aristotle', u'ORG']]

Who or what vary greatly in form within the coleoptera?	Antennae.	S08/data/set1/a8

[[u'Coleoptera', u'ORG']]

Are beetles endopterygotes with complete metamorphosis?	Yes.	S08/data/set1/a8

no

Oxygen is what?	One kind of gas obtained via a tracheal system.	S08/data/set1/a8

  Beetles are a group of insects which have the largest number of species.

Have coleopterists formed organisations to facilitate the study of beetles ?	Yes.	S08/data/set1/a8

Coleopterists have formed organisations to facilitate the study of beetles.

Is the study of beetles called coleopterology , and its practitioners are coleopterists ?	Yes.	S08/data/set1/a8

no

May a single female lay from several dozen to several thousand eggs during her lifetime ?	Yes.	S08/data/set1/a8

A single female may lay from several dozen to several thousand eggs during her lifetime.

Can beetles be found in almost all habitats?	Yes.	S08/data/set1/a8

Beetles can be found in almost all habitats, but are not known to occur in the sea or in the polar regions.

What happened on plants and fungi?	They are food to beetles.	S08/data/set1/a8

[]

Was Calvin Coolidge the twenty-ninth vice president?	no	S08/data/set3/a9

yes

When did he drop John from his name?	upon graduating from college	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'Amherst College', u'ORG'], [u'May 18, 2007', u'DATE'], [u'John', u'PERSON']]

When did he drop John from his name?	Upon graduating from college	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'Amherst College', u'ORG'], [u'May 18, 2007', u'DATE'], [u'John', u'PERSON']]

When did Coolidge meet and marry Grace Anna Goodhue?	1905	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'1905', u'DATE'], [u'Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'Grace Anna Goodhue', u'PERSON'], [u'Vermonter', u'NORP']]

When did Coolidge meet and marry Grace Anna Goodhue?	In 1905	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'1905', u'DATE'], [u'Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'Grace Anna Goodhue', u'PERSON'], [u'Vermonter', u'NORP']]

What period of rapid economic growth did the United States experience during Coolidge's presidency?	the Roaring Twenties	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'Grace', u'ORG']]

What period of rapid economic growth did the United States experience during Coolidge's presidency?	the "Roaring Twenties"	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'Grace', u'ORG']]


[]

What did Coolidge do after graduating from Amherst?	Coolidge moved to Northampton, Massachusetts to take up the practice of law	S08/data/set3/a9

[]

Of what state was Coolidge governor?	Massachusetts	S08/data/set3/a9

In 1897, Coolidge was admitted to the bar.

Who appointed Harlan Fiske Stone to the Supreme Court?	Coolidge	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'2:47 a.m. on August 3', u'TIME'], [u'Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'Justice A. A. Hoehling', u'PERSON'], [u'the Supreme Court of', u'ORG'], [u'Columbia', u'ORG'], [u'Washington', u'GPE']]

Who appointed Harlan Fiske Stone to the Supreme Court?	Coolidge	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'2:47 a.m. on August 3', u'TIME'], [u'Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'Justice A. A. Hoehling', u'PERSON'], [u'the Supreme Court of', u'ORG'], [u'Columbia', u'ORG'], [u'Washington', u'GPE']]

Was Coolidge the thirteenth President of the United States?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a9

no

Was Calvin Coolidge Republican?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a9

no

Was Calvin Coolidge Republican?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a9

no

When was Coolidge born?	July 4 1872	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'Greenberg', u'ORG'], [u'1\xe2\x80\x937', u'CARDINAL'], [u'John Calvin Coolidge Jr.', u'PERSON'], [u'Plymouth', u'GPE'], [u'Windsor County', u'GPE'], [u'Vermont', u'GPE'], [u'July 4 1872', u'DATE'], [u'U.S.', u'GPE'], [u'fourth of July', u'DATE']]

When was Coolidge born?	Plymouth, Windsor County, Vermont	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'Greenberg', u'ORG'], [u'1\xe2\x80\x937', u'CARDINAL'], [u'John Calvin Coolidge Jr.', u'PERSON'], [u'Plymouth', u'GPE'], [u'Windsor County', u'GPE'], [u'Vermont', u'GPE'], [u'July 4 1872', u'DATE'], [u'U.S.', u'GPE'], [u'fourth of July', u'DATE']]

Where did Coolidge's grandfather had government offices?	Plymouth	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'New England', u'LOC']]

Where did Coolidge's grandfather had government offices?	The town of Plymouth Notch	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'New England', u'LOC']]

Which state were Coolidge born in?	Plymouth, Windsor County, Vermont	S08/data/set3/a9

Fuess, 7 Most of Coolidge's ancestors were farmers.

Which state were Coolidge born in?	Vermont	S08/data/set3/a9

Fuess, 7 Most of Coolidge's ancestors were farmers.

Did Coolidge get in Amherst College?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a9

no

Did Coolidge get in Amherst College?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a9

no

What caused Calvin Jr.'s death?	heart attack	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'the twenty-ninth Vice President in 1920', u'DATE'], [u'Warren G. Harding', u'PERSON']]

What caused Calvin Jr.'s death?	Heart attack	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'the twenty-ninth Vice President in 1920', u'DATE'], [u'Warren G. Harding', u'PERSON']]


no

What year did Coolidge open his own law office?	1898	S08/data/set3/a9

[]

What year did Coolidge open his own law office?	1898	S08/data/set3/a9

[]

What fraternity was Coolidge a member of?	Phi Gamma Delta	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'1897', u'DATE'], [u'Coolidge', u'PERSON']]

What fraternity was Coolidge a member of?	phi gamma delta	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'1897', u'DATE'], [u'Coolidge', u'PERSON']]

In 1905 Coolidge met and married whom?	Grace Anna Goodhue	S08/data/set3/a9

In 1905 Coolidge met and married Grace Anna Goodhue, a local schoolteacher and fellow Vermonter.

In 1905 Coolidge met and married whom?	Grace Anna Goodhue	S08/data/set3/a9

In 1905 Coolidge met and married Grace Anna Goodhue, a local schoolteacher and fellow Vermonter.

Why did Coolidge not attend law school?	It was too expensive	S08/data/set3/a9

The Vice Presidency did not carry many official duties, but Coolidge was invited by President Harding to attend cabinet meetings, making him the first Vice President to do so.

Why did Coolidge not attend law school?	cost	S08/data/set3/a9

The Vice Presidency did not carry many official duties, but Coolidge was invited by President Harding to attend cabinet meetings, making him the first Vice President to do so.

Have there been other US presidents that have visited Cuba?	No	S08/data/set3/a9

His most publicized veto was of a bill that would have increased legislators' pay by 50%.

Have there been other US presidents that have visited Cuba?	no	S08/data/set3/a9

His most publicized veto was of a bill that would have increased legislators' pay by 50%.

What years were Coolidge's two sons born in?	1906 and 1908	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'Fuess', u'ORG'], [u'7 Most', u'ORG'], [u'Coolidge', u'PERSON']]

What years were Coolidge's two sons born in?	1906 and 1908	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'Fuess', u'ORG'], [u'7 Most', u'ORG'], [u'Coolidge', u'PERSON']]

What thrust him into the national spotlight?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'John Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'July 4 1872', u'DATE'], [u'January 5 1933', u'DATE'], [u'Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1923\xe2\x80\x931929', u'PERSON']]

What to be born on the fourth of July?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'John Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'July 4 1872', u'DATE'], [u'January 5 1933', u'DATE'], [u'Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1923\xe2\x80\x931929', u'PERSON']]

Who was the elder of two children of John Calvin Sr and Victoria Coolidge?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'John Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'July 4 1872', u'DATE'], [u'January 5 1933', u'DATE'], [u'Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1923\xe2\x80\x931929', u'PERSON']]

Who or what placed as high as sixth in the voting?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'Sobel', u'PERSON'], [u'152\xe2\x80\x93153 Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'one', u'CARDINAL'], [u'sixth', u'ORDINAL']]

Is it true that he appointed stone to the supreme court?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

yes

What do well - received and he have in common?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'John Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'July 4 1872', u'DATE'], [u'January 5 1933', u'DATE'], [u'Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1923\xe2\x80\x931929', u'PERSON']]

What did Coolidge address in 1924?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'1924', u'DATE']]

Was Coolidge more outspoken?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

yes

Was Coolidge admitted to the bar?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

yes

What emigrated from Cambridge?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'John Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'July 4 1872', u'DATE'], [u'January 5 1933', u'DATE'], [u'Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1923\xe2\x80\x931929', u'PERSON']]

What graduated from Black?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'John Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'July 4 1872', u'DATE'], [u'January 5 1933', u'DATE'], [u'Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1923\xe2\x80\x931929', u'PERSON']]

What Retrieved on May?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'John Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'July 4 1872', u'DATE'], [u'January 5 1933', u'DATE'], [u'Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1923\xe2\x80\x931929', u'PERSON']]

He later what?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

 John Calvin Coolidge, Jr. (July 4 1872  January 5 1933), more commonly known as Calvin Coolidge, was the thirtieth President of the United States (1923–1929).

They were what?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

 John Calvin Coolidge, Jr. (July 4 1872  January 5 1933), more commonly known as Calvin Coolidge, was the thirtieth President of the United States (1923–1929).

The Republicans retained what?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

The Republicans retained the White House in 1928 in the person of Coolidge's Secretary of Commerce, Herbert Hoover.

(NNP Harding #)(NNP Death )))(PP (IN in )(NP (NP (NN office ))(PP (IN for )(NP (DT a )(JJ full )(NN description )(NNP Vice )(NNP President )(person (NNP Coolidge ))))))))(VP (VP (VBD was )(VP (VBG visiting )(NP (PRP$ his )(NN family )(NN home ))))(, , )(SBAR (WHNP (WDT which ))(S (VP (VBD did )(RB not )(VP (VB have )(NP (NP (NN electricity ))(CC or )(NP (DT a )(NN telephone )))(, , )(PP (IN in )(NP (location (NNP Vermont ))))(SBAR (WHADVP (WRB when ))(S (NP (PRP he ))(VP (VBD received )(NP (NP (NN word ))(PP (IN of )(NP (NP (NNP Harding )(POS 's ))(NN death ))))))))))))))(. . )))	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

See the main article, Warren Harding#Death in office for a full description Vice President Coolidge was visiting his family home, which did not have electricity or a telephone, in Vermont when he received word of Harding's death.

	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

 John Calvin Coolidge, Jr. (July 4 1872  January 5 1933), more commonly known as Calvin Coolidge, was the thirtieth President of the United States (1923–1929).

	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

 John Calvin Coolidge, Jr. (July 4 1872  January 5 1933), more commonly known as Calvin Coolidge, was the thirtieth President of the United States (1923–1929).


yes

Did Coolidge not publish his autobiography in 1929 and write a syndicated newspaper column , `` Calvin Coolidge Says , '' from 1930 -- 1931 ?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

no

Were the more well-known Coolidges , such as architect Charles Allerton Coolidge , and diplomat Archibald Cary Coolidge , descended from other branches of the family that had stayed in Massachusetts ?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

no

Is the genius of the average the most convincing proof of $ his strength?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

no

What happened from tuberculosis?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'John Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'July 4 1872', u'DATE'], [u'January 5 1933', u'DATE'], [u'Calvin Coolidge', u'PERSON'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'1923\xe2\x80\x931929', u'PERSON']]

What happened from black river academy , vermont?	NULL	S08/data/set3/a9

[[u'Greenberg', u'ORG'], [u'1\xe2\x80\x937', u'CARDINAL'], [u'John Calvin Coolidge Jr.', u'PERSON'], [u'Plymouth', u'GPE'], [u'Windsor County', u'GPE'], [u'Vermont', u'GPE'], [u'July 4 1872', u'DATE'], [u'U.S.', u'GPE'], [u'fourth of July', u'DATE']]

Did France cede nearly all of its colonies in Europe in 1763?	Yes.	S08/data/set2/a8

no

Did France cede nearly all of its colonies in Europe in 1763?	yes	S08/data/set2/a8

no

Did France cede nearly all of its colonies in Europe in 1763?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a8

no

Is Canada a member of the OECD?	Yes.	S08/data/set2/a8

no

Is Canada a member of the OECD?	yes	S08/data/set2/a8

no

Is Canada a member of the OECD?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a8

no

Is Canada's official language Zulu?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a8

no

What is one significant non-official language?	Chinese.	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'North America', u'LOC'], [u'the Atlantic Ocean', u'LOC'], [u'the Pacific Ocean', u'ORG'], [u'the Arctic Ocean', u'LOC']]

What is one significant non-official language?	Chinese	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'North America', u'LOC'], [u'the Atlantic Ocean', u'LOC'], [u'the Pacific Ocean', u'ORG'], [u'the Arctic Ocean', u'LOC']]

What is one significant non-official language?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'North America', u'LOC'], [u'the Atlantic Ocean', u'LOC'], [u'the Pacific Ocean', u'ORG'], [u'the Arctic Ocean', u'LOC']]

In addition to Port Royal, where else did Samuel de Champlain establish a settlement?	Quebec City	S08/data/set2/a8

While the Green Party of Canada and other smaller parties do not have current representation in Parliament, the list of historical parties with elected representation is substantial.   

In addition to Port Royal, where else did Samuel de Champlain establish a settlement?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a8

While the Green Party of Canada and other smaller parties do not have current representation in Parliament, the list of historical parties with elected representation is substantial.   

What was the Consitution Act formerly called?	The British North America Act.	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'two', u'CARDINAL'], [u'British', u'NORP'], [u'Upper Canada', u'ORG'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'the British Province of Canada', u'ORG'], [u'1841', u'DATE']]

What was the Consitution Act formerly called?	British North America Act	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'two', u'CARDINAL'], [u'British', u'NORP'], [u'Upper Canada', u'ORG'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'the British Province of Canada', u'ORG'], [u'1841', u'DATE']]

What was the Consitution Act formerly called?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'two', u'CARDINAL'], [u'British', u'NORP'], [u'Upper Canada', u'ORG'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'the British Province of Canada', u'ORG'], [u'1841', u'DATE']]

Which countries established colonies in Canada?	France and Britain.	S08/data/set2/a8

  Canada ( ) is a country occupying most of northern North America, extending from the Atlantic Ocean in the east to the Pacific Ocean in the west and northward into the Arctic Ocean.

Which countries established colonies in Canada?	Fance and Britain	S08/data/set2/a8

  Canada ( ) is a country occupying most of northern North America, extending from the Atlantic Ocean in the east to the Pacific Ocean in the west and northward into the Arctic Ocean.

Which countries established colonies in Canada?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a8

  Canada ( ) is a country occupying most of northern North America, extending from the Atlantic Ocean in the east to the Pacific Ocean in the west and northward into the Arctic Ocean.

How has Canada helped UN peacekeeping efforts?	During the Suez Crisis of 1956, Lester B. Pearson eased tensions by proposing the inception of the United Nations Peacekeeping Force. Canada has since served in 50 peacekeeping missions, including every UN peacekeeping effort until 1989	S08/data/set2/a8

In February 2007, Canada, Italy, Britain, Norway, and Russia announced their funding commitments to launch a $1.5 billion project to help develop vaccines they said could save millions of lives in poor nations, and called on others to join them. "

How has Canada helped UN peacekeeping efforts?	Canada has played a leading role in UN peacekeeping efforts. During the Suez Crisis of 1956, Lester B. Pearson eased tensions by proposing the inception of the United Nations Peacekeeping Force. Canada has since served in 50 peacekeeping missions, including every UN peacekeeping effort until 1989	S08/data/set2/a8

In February 2007, Canada, Italy, Britain, Norway, and Russia announced their funding commitments to launch a $1.5 billion project to help develop vaccines they said could save millions of lives in poor nations, and called on others to join them. "

How has Canada helped UN peacekeeping efforts?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a8

In February 2007, Canada, Italy, Britain, Norway, and Russia announced their funding commitments to launch a $1.5 billion project to help develop vaccines they said could save millions of lives in poor nations, and called on others to join them. "

What percentage of the population don't speak English or French at home?	28%	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'the Green Party of Canada', u'ORG'], [u'Parliament', u'ORG']]

What percentage of the population don't speak English or French at home?	1.5%	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'the Green Party of Canada', u'ORG'], [u'Parliament', u'ORG']]

What percentage of the population don't speak English or French at home?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'the Green Party of Canada', u'ORG'], [u'Parliament', u'ORG']]

Is Canada bilingual?	Yes, it is.	S08/data/set2/a8

yes

Did Canadian soldiers win the Battle of Vimy Ridge in 1917?	No, it did not.	S08/data/set2/a8

yes

Is an official language of Canada German?	No, it is not.	S08/data/set2/a8

no

How many provinces and territories does Canada have?	A federation now comprising ten provinces and three territories	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'the Green Party of Canada', u'ORG'], [u'Parliament', u'ORG']]

How many provinces and territories does Canada have?	Ten provinces and three territories	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'the Green Party of Canada', u'ORG'], [u'Parliament', u'ORG']]

What is Canada's national unemployment rate?	While as of October 2007, Canada's national unemployment rate of 5.9% is its lowest in 33 years. Provincial unemployment rates vary from a low of 3.6% in Alberta to a high of 14.6% in Newfoundland and Labrador. 	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'as of October 2007', u'DATE'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'5.9% is its', u'PERCENT'], [u'33 years', u'DATE']]

What is Canada's national unemployment rate?	In October 2007, Canada's national unemployment rate is 5.9%.	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'as of October 2007', u'DATE'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'5.9% is its', u'PERCENT'], [u'33 years', u'DATE']]

Where is the most densely populated part of Canada?	The most densely populated part of the country is the Quebec City-Windsor Corridor along the Great Lakes and Saint Lawrence River in the southeast.	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'North America', u'LOC'], [u'the Atlantic Ocean', u'LOC'], [u'the Pacific Ocean', u'ORG'], [u'the Arctic Ocean', u'LOC']]

Where is the most densely populated part of Canada?	The most densely populated part of the country is the Quebec City-Windsor Corridor along the Great Lakes and Saint Lawrence River in the southeast.	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'North America', u'LOC'], [u'the Atlantic Ocean', u'LOC'], [u'the Pacific Ocean', u'ORG'], [u'the Arctic Ocean', u'LOC']]

What is the largest country in the world?	Canada is the second largest country in the world, after Russia, and largest on the continent.	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u' ', u'CARDINAL'], [u'the United States', u'GPE']]


[[u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u' ', u'CARDINAL'], [u'the United States', u'GPE']]

What is the largest religious group in Canada?	According to 2001 census, 77.1% of Canadians identified as being Christians; of this, Catholics make up the largest group (43.6% of Canadians). The largest Protestant denomination is the United Church of Canada; about 16.5% of Canadians declare no religious affiliation, and the remaining 6.3% were affiliated with religions other than Christianity, of which the largest is Islam numbering 1.9%, followed by Judaism: 1.1%. 	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'North America', u'LOC'], [u'the Atlantic Ocean', u'LOC'], [u'the Pacific Ocean', u'ORG'], [u'the Arctic Ocean', u'LOC']]

What is the largest religious group in Canada?	Christian	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'North America', u'LOC'], [u'the Atlantic Ocean', u'LOC'], [u'the Pacific Ocean', u'ORG'], [u'the Arctic Ocean', u'LOC']]

When did Canada have one of the largest armed forces in the world?	1944.	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'243,000', u'CARDINAL']]

When did Canada have one of the largest armed forces in the world?	World War II.	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'243,000', u'CARDINAL']]

What have been inhabited for millennia by aboriginal peoples?	The lands	S08/data/set2/a8

[]

European books and maps began referring to this region as Canada in what year?	1545	S08/data/set2/a8

By 1545, European books and maps began referring to this region as Canada.

What was Canada's most important industry until the 1800s?	The fur trade	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'North America', u'LOC'], [u'the Atlantic Ocean', u'LOC'], [u'the Pacific Ocean', u'ORG'], [u'the Arctic Ocean', u'LOC']]

Is it true that it angered many residents of the thirteen colonies?	yes	S08/data/set2/a8

no

How do cuba and declining participation relate?	Canada maintains full relations with both.	S08/data/set2/a8

Canada has nevertheless maintained an independent foreign policy, most notably maintaining full relations with Cuba and declining participation in the Iraq War.

What did Canada adopt in 1965?	The Maple Leaf Flag	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'Maple Leaf Flag', u'FAC'], [u'1965', u'DATE']]

What arrived in Britain?	The first Canadian Army units in WW II	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'North America', u'LOC'], [u'the Atlantic Ocean', u'LOC'], [u'the Pacific Ocean', u'ORG'], [u'the Arctic Ocean', u'LOC']]

Are Canada 's two official languages English and French ?	yes	S08/data/set2/a8

no

Are Canada 's official national sports ice hockey ( winter ) and lacrosse ( summer ) ?	yes	S08/data/set2/a8

no

Did Cartier not use the word ` Canada ' to refer to not only that village , but the entire area subject to Donnacona , Chief at Stadacona ?	yes	S08/data/set2/a8

no

What happened in 1867?	Canada was formed as a federal, semi-autonomous polity	S08/data/set2/a8

[[u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'North America', u'LOC'], [u'the Atlantic Ocean', u'LOC'], [u'the Pacific Ocean', u'ORG'], [u'the Arctic Ocean', u'LOC']]

Are ducks in the Arctic Northern Hemisphere migratory?	Some are	S08/data/set1/a10

no

Are ducks in the Arctic Northern Hemisphere migratory?	yes	S08/data/set1/a10

no

Do all ducks "quack"?	No	S08/data/set1/a10

yes

Do all ducks "quack"?	no	S08/data/set1/a10

yes

What is the name of a specialized species of duck adapted to catch large fish?	the smew	S08/data/set1/a10

[]

What animal attracts the most humor and silliness?	The duck	S08/data/set1/a10

[[u'2002', u'DATE'], [u'Richard Wiseman', u'PERSON'], [u'the University of Hertfordshire (', u'ORG'], [u'year-long', u'DATE'], [u'LaughLab', u'ORG']]

What animal attracts the most humor and silliness?	the duck	S08/data/set1/a10

[[u'2002', u'DATE'], [u'Richard Wiseman', u'PERSON'], [u'the University of Hertfordshire (', u'ORG'], [u'year-long', u'DATE'], [u'LaughLab', u'ORG']]

What is an economic use of a duck?	Meat	S08/data/set1/a10

[[u'Duck', u'PERSON'], [u'Anatidae', u'PERSON']]

What is an economic use of a duck?	being farmed for their meat	S08/data/set1/a10

[[u'Duck', u'PERSON'], [u'Anatidae', u'PERSON']]

Who is Daffy Duck?	A silly cartoon character	S08/data/set1/a10

[[u'Duck', u'PERSON'], [u'Anatidae', u'PERSON']]

Who is Daffy Duck?	a silly cartoon character	S08/data/set1/a10

[[u'Duck', u'PERSON'], [u'Anatidae', u'PERSON']]

What makes it more difficult for a diving duck to fly?	They are heavier	S08/data/set1/a10

[]

What makes it more difficult for a diving duck to fly?	they are heavier	S08/data/set1/a10

[]

What are the reasons for hunting wild ducks?	Meat, eggs, and feathers	S08/data/set1/a10

[]

Do ducks forage underwater?	yes	S08/data/set1/a10

no

Do ducks forage underwater?	Diving ducks and sea ducks forage underwater	S08/data/set1/a10

no

Do all ducks "quack"?	no	S08/data/set1/a10

yes

Do all ducks "quack"?	No	S08/data/set1/a10

yes

Is foie gras often made from ducks?	yes	S08/data/set1/a10

no

Is foie gras often made from ducks?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a10

no

What economic uses to ducks have?	They are farmed for their meat, eggs and feathers. They are also kept and bred by aviculturists and often displayed in zoos.	S08/data/set1/a10

[]

What economic uses to ducks have?	They can be farmed for meat, eggs, and feathers	S08/data/set1/a10

[]

What kind of ducks feed on land?	Dabbling ducks	S08/data/set1/a10

[]

What kind of ducks feed on land?	Dabbling ducks feed on land	S08/data/set1/a10

[]

What unrelated water birds are ducks sometimes confused with?	loons or divers, grebes, gallinules, and coots	S08/data/set1/a10

[]

What unrelated water birds are ducks sometimes confused with?	loons or divers, grebes, gallinules, and coots	S08/data/set1/a10

[]

What does the word duck mean?	It is the common name for a number of species in the Anatidae family of birds.	S08/data/set1/a10

[[u'Duck', u'PERSON'], [u'Anatidae', u'PERSON']]

What does the word duck mean?	to bend down low as if to get under something	S08/data/set1/a10

[[u'Duck', u'PERSON'], [u'Anatidae', u'PERSON']]

What are some common predators of ducks?	Pike, crocodilians, herons, hawks and eagles.	S08/data/set1/a10

[[u'Duck', u'PERSON'], [u'Anatidae', u'PERSON']]

What are some common predators of ducks?	pike, crocodilians, and other aquatic hunters	S08/data/set1/a10

[[u'Duck', u'PERSON'], [u'Anatidae', u'PERSON']]

How does a Mallard's tongue work?	It's tongue is a flat plate, and on the tongue's back end is a short liftable flap with about 18 short spikes for pushing struggling prey and other food down its throat	S08/data/set1/a10

 Duck is the common name for a number of species in the Anatidae family of birds.

How does a Mallard's tongue work?	It uses short spikes to push struggling prey and other food down its throat	S08/data/set1/a10

 Duck is the common name for a number of species in the Anatidae family of birds.

Are diving ducks heavier tha dabbling ducks?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a10

no

Are diving ducks heavier tha dabbling ducks?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a10

no

Are ducks an accepted presence in some populated areas?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a10

no

Are ducks an accepted presence in some populated areas?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a10

no

What types of unrelated water birds with similar forms are ducks sometimes confused with?	loons or divers, grebes, gallinules, and coots	S08/data/set1/a10

[]

What types of unrelated water birds with similar forms are ducks sometimes confused with?	loons or divers, grebes, gallinules, and coots	S08/data/set1/a10

[]

Why are ducklings particularly vulnerable?	Their inability to fly.	S08/data/set1/a10

Ducklings are particularly vulnerable, since their inability to fly makes them easy prey not only for avian hunters but also large fish like pike, crocodilians, and other aquatic hunters, including fish-eating birds such as herons.

Why are ducklings particularly vulnerable?	their inability to fly makes them easy prey	S08/data/set1/a10

Ducklings are particularly vulnerable, since their inability to fly makes them easy prey not only for avian hunters but also large fish like pike, crocodilians, and other aquatic hunters, including fish-eating birds such as herons.

What are some economic uses for duck?	Meat,eggs,feathers	S08/data/set1/a10

[[u'Duck', u'PERSON'], [u'Anatidae', u'PERSON']]

What are some economic uses for duck?	being farmed for their meat, eggs, feathers, (particularly their down)	S08/data/set1/a10

[[u'Duck', u'PERSON'], [u'Anatidae', u'PERSON']]

What allows a duck to filter water out of the side of their beaks and keep food inside?	Tiny rows of plates called lamellae	S08/data/set1/a10

[]

What allows a duck to filter water out of the side of their beaks and keep food inside?	tiny rows of plates called lamellae like a whale's baleen	S08/data/set1/a10

[]

What expression is part of a conceptual framework for testing computer systems?	Quacks like a duck	S08/data/set1/a10

[[u'Duck', u'PERSON']]

What expression is part of a conceptual framework for testing computer systems?	Quacks like a duck	S08/data/set1/a10

[[u'Duck', u'PERSON']]

Where did the expression "a sitting duck" come from?	In many areas, wild duckof various species (including ducks farmed and released into the wild) are hunted for food or sport, by shooting, or formerly by decoys.	S08/data/set1/a10

[]

Where did the expression "a sitting duck" come from?	In many areas, wild ducks of various species (including ducks farmed and released into the wild) are hunted for food or sport, by shooting, or formerly by decoys.	S08/data/set1/a10

[]

Is Egypt bordered by the Gaza Strip?	yes	S08/data/set2/a6

no

Is Egypt bordered by the Gaza Strip?	Yes	S08/data/set2/a6

no

Does Egypt have political influence in the Middle East?	yes	S08/data/set2/a6

no

Does Egypt have political influence in the Middle East?	Yes	S08/data/set2/a6

no

When was the Six Day War?	1967	S08/data/set2/a6

[[u'Egypt', u'GPE'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Kemet', u'PERSON'], [u'Coptic', u'NORP'], [u'  ', u'ORG'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Arab Republic', u'ORG'], [u'North Africa', u'GPE'], [u'the Sinai Peninsula', u'LOC'], [u'Asia', u'LOC']]

When was the Six Day War?	1967	S08/data/set2/a6

[[u'Egypt', u'GPE'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Kemet', u'PERSON'], [u'Coptic', u'NORP'], [u'  ', u'ORG'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Arab Republic', u'ORG'], [u'North Africa', u'GPE'], [u'the Sinai Peninsula', u'LOC'], [u'Asia', u'LOC']]

What religions has Egypt outlawed?	All but Christianity, Islam, and Judaism	S08/data/set2/a6

[[u'Egypt', u'GPE'], [u'Islam', u'ORG'], [u'Christianity', u'NORP'], [u'Judaism', u'ORG']]

What religions has Egypt outlawed?	all religions and belief except Islam, Christianity and Judaism	S08/data/set2/a6

[[u'Egypt', u'GPE'], [u'Islam', u'ORG'], [u'Christianity', u'NORP'], [u'Judaism', u'ORG']]

What is the poulation of Egypt?	more than 78 million	S08/data/set2/a6

[[u'Egypt', u'GPE'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Kemet', u'PERSON'], [u'Coptic', u'NORP'], [u'  ', u'ORG'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Arab Republic', u'ORG'], [u'North Africa', u'GPE'], [u'the Sinai Peninsula', u'LOC'], [u'Asia', u'LOC']]

What is the poulation of Egypt?	78 million people	S08/data/set2/a6

[[u'Egypt', u'GPE'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Kemet', u'PERSON'], [u'Coptic', u'NORP'], [u'  ', u'ORG'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Arab Republic', u'ORG'], [u'North Africa', u'GPE'], [u'the Sinai Peninsula', u'LOC'], [u'Asia', u'LOC']]

Why does most of Egypt's population live near the Nile?	the only arable agricultural land is found there,	S08/data/set2/a6

About half of Egypt's residents live in urban areas, with the majority spread across the densely populated centers of greater Cairo, Alexandria and other major cities in the Nile Delta.

Why does most of Egypt's population live near the Nile?	The only arable agricultural land is found there	S08/data/set2/a6

About half of Egypt's residents live in urban areas, with the majority spread across the densely populated centers of greater Cairo, Alexandria and other major cities in the Nile Delta.

During what period was Akhenaten a Pharaoh?	The New Kingdom (c.1550&#8722;1070 BC) 	S08/data/set2/a6

The Thirtieth Dynasty was the last native ruling dynasty during the Pharaonic epoch.

During what period was Akhenaten a Pharaoh?	The New Kingdom	S08/data/set2/a6

The Thirtieth Dynasty was the last native ruling dynasty during the Pharaonic epoch.

Is Egypt in Asia?	No.	S08/data/set2/a6

yes

Since when has Egypt been a republic?	June 18 1953.	S08/data/set2/a6

These views and sources for collective identification in the Egyptian state are captured in the words of a linguistic anthropologist who conducted fieldwork in Cairo:  Egypt has been a republic since June 18 1953.

Since when has Egypt been a republic?	June 18 1953	S08/data/set2/a6

These views and sources for collective identification in the Egyptian state are captured in the words of a linguistic anthropologist who conducted fieldwork in Cairo:  Egypt has been a republic since June 18 1953.

When were the Great Sphinx and the Pyramids of Giza built?	During the Old Kingdom.	S08/data/set2/a6

[[u'Pyramids', u'DATE'], [u'Giza', u'GPE'], [u'Egypt', u'GPE']]

When were the Great Sphinx and the Pyramids of Giza built?	During the Old Kingdom	S08/data/set2/a6

[[u'Pyramids', u'DATE'], [u'Giza', u'GPE'], [u'Egypt', u'GPE']]

What countries border Egypt?	Libya, Sudan, the Gaza Strip and Israel.	S08/data/set2/a6

[[u'Egypt', u'GPE'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Kemet', u'PERSON'], [u'Coptic', u'NORP'], [u'  ', u'ORG'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Arab Republic', u'ORG'], [u'North Africa', u'GPE'], [u'the Sinai Peninsula', u'LOC'], [u'Asia', u'LOC']]

What countries border Egypt?	Libya, Sudan, the Gaza Strip and Israel	S08/data/set2/a6

[[u'Egypt', u'GPE'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Kemet', u'PERSON'], [u'Coptic', u'NORP'], [u'  ', u'ORG'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Arab Republic', u'ORG'], [u'North Africa', u'GPE'], [u'the Sinai Peninsula', u'LOC'], [u'Asia', u'LOC']]

What is the estimated population of Egypt?	More than 78 million.	S08/data/set2/a6

[[u'Egypt', u'GPE'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Kemet', u'PERSON'], [u'Coptic', u'NORP'], [u'  ', u'ORG'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Arab Republic', u'ORG'], [u'North Africa', u'GPE'], [u'the Sinai Peninsula', u'LOC'], [u'Asia', u'LOC']]

What is the estimated population of Egypt?	78 million	S08/data/set2/a6

[[u'Egypt', u'GPE'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Kemet', u'PERSON'], [u'Coptic', u'NORP'], [u'  ', u'ORG'], [u'Egyptian', u'NORP'], [u'Arab Republic', u'ORG'], [u'North Africa', u'GPE'], [u'the Sinai Peninsula', u'LOC'], [u'Asia', u'LOC']]

When did organized agriculture appear in the Nile Valley?	6000 BC.	S08/data/set2/a6

[[u'6000', u'CARDINAL'], [u'BC', u'ORG']]

When did organized agriculture appear in the Nile Valley?	About 6000 BC	S08/data/set2/a6

[[u'6000', u'CARDINAL'], [u'BC', u'ORG']]

Can an elephant kill a rhinoceros?	yes	S08/data/set1/a5

In Judeo-Christian accounts, including Midrash on the sixth chapter of the apocryphal book of 1 Maccabees, the youngest of the Hasmonean brothers, Eleazar the Maccabee stuck a spear under the foot of an elephant carrying an important Greek-Assyrian general, killing the elephant, the general, and Eleazar.  

Can an elephant kill a rhinoceros?	yes	S08/data/set1/a5

In Judeo-Christian accounts, including Midrash on the sixth chapter of the apocryphal book of 1 Maccabees, the youngest of the Hasmonean brothers, Eleazar the Maccabee stuck a spear under the foot of an elephant carrying an important Greek-Assyrian general, killing the elephant, the general, and Eleazar.  

How many living species of African Elephants are there?	2	S08/data/set1/a5

[]

How many living species of African Elephants are there?	The African Elephant genus contains two (or, arguably, three) living species.	S08/data/set1/a5

[]

How long may elephants live?	70 years	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'three', u'CARDINAL'], [u'African', u'NORP'], [u'Bush Elephant', u'PERSON'], [u'the African Elephant', u'ORG'], [u'the Asian Elephant', u'ORG'], [u'the Indian Elephant', u'ORG']]

How long may elephants live?	As long as 70 years, sometimes longer.	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'three', u'CARDINAL'], [u'African', u'NORP'], [u'Bush Elephant', u'PERSON'], [u'the African Elephant', u'ORG'], [u'the Asian Elephant', u'ORG'], [u'the Indian Elephant', u'ORG']]

Why does the phrase 'elephants never forget' have no metaphorical meaning?	it refers literally to elephants supposedly having an excellent memory	S08/data/set1/a5

The phrase 'elephants never forget' has no metaphorical meaning, it refers literally to elephants supposedly having an excellent memory. *

Why does the phrase 'elephants never forget' have no metaphorical meaning?	Because it refers literally to elephants supposedly having an excellent memory.	S08/data/set1/a5

The phrase 'elephants never forget' has no metaphorical meaning, it refers literally to elephants supposedly having an excellent memory. *

How many living species of Asian Elephants are there?	1	S08/data/set1/a5

[]

How many living species of Asian Elephants are there?	one	S08/data/set1/a5

[]

How much do elephants weight at birth?	120 kilograms	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'Elephantidae', u'PERSON'], [u'Proboscidea', u'GPE'], [u'Mammalia', u'PERSON']]

How much do elephants weight at birth?	At birth it is common for an elephant calf to weigh 120 kilograms (265 lb).	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'Elephantidae', u'PERSON'], [u'Proboscidea', u'GPE'], [u'Mammalia', u'PERSON']]

What did Aristotle say about elephants?	the beast which passeth all others in wit and mind	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'Aristotle', u'ORG']]

What did Aristotle say about elephants?	Aristotle once said the elephant was "the beast which passeth all others in wit and mind."	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'Aristotle', u'ORG']]

Are elephant populations in West Africa generally small and fragmented?	yes	S08/data/set1/a5

no

Are elephant populations in West Africa generally small and fragmented?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a5

no

Is the Asian elephant larger than the African?	Sometimes	S08/data/set1/a5

no

Is an elephant's skin tough?	yes	S08/data/set1/a5

no

Is an elephant's skin tough?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a5

no

How do elephants communicate over long distances?	by producing and receiving low frequency sound	S08/data/set1/a5

Bruce Bagemihl, Biological Exuberance: Animal Homosexuality and Natural Diversity, St. Martin's Press, 1999; pp.427-430  Elephants communicate over long distances by producing and receiving low-frequency sound (infrasound), a sub-sonic rumbling, which can travel through the ground farther than sound travels through the air.

How do elephants communicate over long distances?	By producing and receiving low-frequency sound (infrasound)	S08/data/set1/a5

Bruce Bagemihl, Biological Exuberance: Animal Homosexuality and Natural Diversity, St. Martin's Press, 1999; pp.427-430  Elephants communicate over long distances by producing and receiving low-frequency sound (infrasound), a sub-sonic rumbling, which can travel through the ground farther than sound travels through the air.

When do African elephants lie down?	when they are sick or wounded	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'African', u'NORP']]

How long is the elephant's gestation period?	22 months	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'22 months', u'DATE']]

How long is the elephant's gestation period?	22 months	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'22 months', u'DATE']]

How many species of African elephants have been proposed?	three	S08/data/set1/a5

[]

How many species of African elephants have been proposed?	three	S08/data/set1/a5

[]

What are the elephant's ears important for?	temperature regulation	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'Elephantidae', u'PERSON'], [u'Proboscidea', u'GPE'], [u'Mammalia', u'PERSON']]

What are the elephant's ears important for?	temperature regulation	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'Elephantidae', u'PERSON'], [u'Proboscidea', u'GPE'], [u'Mammalia', u'PERSON']]

What land animal has the largest brain?	elephant	S08/data/set1/a5

[]

What land animal has the largest brain?	The elephant	S08/data/set1/a5

[]

Are elephants mammals?	yes	S08/data/set1/a5

no

Are elephants mammals?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a5

no

Have elephants been used as working animals?	yes	S08/data/set1/a5

Elephants have been working animals used in various capacities by humans.

Have elephants been used as working animals?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a5

Elephants have been working animals used in various capacities by humans.

Do they prefer forested areas?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a5

no

Do they prefer forested areas?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a5

no

What is the world population of Asian elephants?	60000	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'three', u'CARDINAL'], [u'African', u'NORP'], [u'Bush Elephant', u'PERSON'], [u'the African Elephant', u'ORG'], [u'the Asian Elephant', u'ORG'], [u'the Indian Elephant', u'ORG']]

What is the world population of Asian elephants?	The world population of Asian elephants – also called Indian Elephants or Elephas maximus – is estimated to be around 60,000	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'three', u'CARDINAL'], [u'African', u'NORP'], [u'Bush Elephant', u'PERSON'], [u'the African Elephant', u'ORG'], [u'the Asian Elephant', u'ORG'], [u'the Indian Elephant', u'ORG']]

What part of an elephant is very important for temperature regulation?	Ears	S08/data/set1/a5

[]

What part of an elephant is very important for temperature regulation?	The large flapping ears of an elephant are also very important for temperature regulation.	S08/data/set1/a5

[]

Where was the largest elephant ever recorded shot?	Angola	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'Angola', u'GPE'], [u'1956', u'DATE']]

Where was the largest elephant ever recorded shot?	The largest elephant ever recorded was shot in Angola in 1956.	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'Angola', u'GPE'], [u'1956', u'DATE']]

Is an Asian elephant smaller than an African elephant?	yes	S08/data/set1/a5

no

Is an Asian elephant smaller than an African elephant?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a5

no

What land animal is larger than an elephant?	None	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'Asian', u'NORP'], [u'African', u'NORP']]

What land animal is larger than an elephant?	None, the elephant is the largest land animal.	S08/data/set1/a5

[[u'Asian', u'NORP'], [u'African', u'NORP']]

Has tusklessness become a rare abnormality?	No	S08/data/set1/a5

Tusklessness, once a very rare genetic abnormality, has become a widespread hereditary trait.

Has tusklessness become a rare abnormality?	No, tusklessness has become a widespread hereditary trait. 	S08/data/set1/a5

Tusklessness, once a very rare genetic abnormality, has become a widespread hereditary trait.

Which Russian army general conquered Finland in 1809?	Alexander I	S08/data/set2/a4

On March 29 1809, after being conquered by the armies of Alexander I of Russia in the Finnish War, Finland became an autonomous Grand Duchy in the Russian Empire until the end of 1917.

Which Russian army general conquered Finland in 1809?	Alexander I	S08/data/set2/a4

On March 29 1809, after being conquered by the armies of Alexander I of Russia in the Finnish War, Finland became an autonomous Grand Duchy in the Russian Empire until the end of 1917.

What is the life expectancy for men in Finland?	75 years	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

What is the life expectancy for men in Finland?	75 years	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

In what year were the "Games of the XV Olympiad" held?	1952	S08/data/set2/a4


In what year were the "Games of the XV Olympiad" held?	1952	S08/data/set2/a4


What body of water lies to the south of Finland?	the Gulf of Finland	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Sweden', u'GPE'], [u'Russia', u'GPE'], [u'Norway', u'GPE'], [u'Estonia', u'GPE'], [u'Gulf', u'LOC'], [u'Finland', u'GPE']]

What body of water lies to the south of Finland?	Archipelago Sea	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Sweden', u'GPE'], [u'Russia', u'GPE'], [u'Norway', u'GPE'], [u'Estonia', u'GPE'], [u'Gulf', u'LOC'], [u'Finland', u'GPE']]

Name an animal that is growing in number due to recent conservation efforts	Golden Eagle, Brown Bear, or Eurasian Lynx (Change imperative to interrogative)	S08/data/set2/a4

Tourism is an expanding industry in Finland and in recent years has become a significant aspect of its economy.

Name an animal that is growing in number due to recent conservation efforts	Golden Eagle	S08/data/set2/a4

Tourism is an expanding industry in Finland and in recent years has become a significant aspect of its economy.

Today, are there more cell phone subscriptions than people in Finland?	yes	S08/data/set2/a4

  Finland, officially the Republic of Finland "Republic of Finland", or "Suomen tasavalta" in Finnish and "Republiken Finland" in Swedish, is the long protocol name, which is not defined by the law.

Today, are there more cell phone subscriptions than people in Finland?	Yes	S08/data/set2/a4

  Finland, officially the Republic of Finland "Republic of Finland", or "Suomen tasavalta" in Finnish and "Republiken Finland" in Swedish, is the long protocol name, which is not defined by the law.

Does it have a border with Norway?	yes	S08/data/set2/a4

no

Does it have a border with Norway?	Yes	S08/data/set2/a4

no

What is the life expectancy for men?	75 years	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'82 years', u'DATE'], [u'75 years', u'DATE']]

What is the life expectancy for men?	75 years	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'82 years', u'DATE'], [u'75 years', u'DATE']]

What is the biggest city in Finland?	Greater Helsinki	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

What is the biggest city in Finland?	the cities of the Greater Helsinki metropolitan area	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

Who is the most popular rock group in Finland?	CMX	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

Who is the most popular rock group in Finland?	CMX	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

What is Finland's economy like?	a highly industrialised, free-market economy	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

Where is Finland located?	Northern Europe	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Santa\xe2\x80\x99s Post Office', u'ORG'], [u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Lapland', u'GPE']]

Where is Finland located?	Northern Europe	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Santa\xe2\x80\x99s Post Office', u'ORG'], [u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Lapland', u'GPE']]

What is the weather like in summer?	relatively warm	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

What is the weather like in summer?	relatively warm	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

According to Reader's Digest, is Finland best for living?	Yes	S08/data/set2/a4

Finland is also a place rich in culture for history, tradition and religion.

According to Reader's Digest, is Finland best for living?	Yes	S08/data/set2/a4

Finland is also a place rich in culture for history, tradition and religion.

When did the first verifiable written documents appear?	Twelfth Century	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the twelfth century', u'DATE']]

When did the first verifiable written documents appear?	 The first verifiable written documents appeared in the twelfth century. 	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the twelfth century', u'DATE']]

What is the capital city?	Helsinki	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

What is the capital city?	The capital city is Helsinki. 	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

What is the most extensively celebrated holiday?	Christmas	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

What is the most extensively celebrated holiday?	Christmas is the most extensively celebrated holiday.	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

Do women live longer than men?	Yes	S08/data/set2/a4

no

Do women live longer than men?	Yes	S08/data/set2/a4

no

What is a country with which Finland is involved in an international conflict?	None	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Sweden', u'GPE'], [u'Norway', u'GPE'], [u'Russia', u'GPE'], [u'Estonia', u'GPE']]

What is a country with which Finland is involved in an international conflict?	Finland is not involved in international conflicts or border disputes. 	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Sweden', u'GPE'], [u'Norway', u'GPE'], [u'Russia', u'GPE'], [u'Estonia', u'GPE']]

What is Helsinki?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

What is concentrated in the southern part of the country?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Nordic', u'NORP'], [u'Northern Europe', u'LOC']]

What is spoken natively by a 5.5 percent minority?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

What do jari litmanen and sami hyypiä have in common?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'1995', u'DATE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP']]

Is it true that he composed finlandia in 1899?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

yes

Is it true that it has borders with sweden?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

yes

What did Finland join in 1995?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the European Union', u'ORG'], [u'1995', u'DATE']]

Is finnish culture indigenous?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

yes

Is finnish architecture famous?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

yes

What situated in Northern?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

What arrived in Finland?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

What ceded by Finland?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Finland', u'GPE'], [u'the Republic of Finland', u'GPE'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Republiken Finland', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Swedish', u'LANGUAGE']]

Lunch is what?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

  Finland, officially the Republic of Finland "Republic of Finland", or "Suomen tasavalta" in Finnish and "Republiken Finland" in Swedish, is the long protocol name, which is not defined by the law.

Who is the autonomous Åland Islands , where Finnish is not compulsory due to Swedish being the sole official language of the province . ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

[[u'Islands', u'PERSON'], [u'Finnish', u'NORP'], [u'Swedish', u'NORP'], [u' ', u'GPE']]

The earliest people were what?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

The earliest people were hunter-gatherers, living primarily off what the tundra and sea could offer.

Are Various sporting events popular in Finland ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

yes

Are all official holidays in Finland established by acts of Parliament ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

no

Are the people of Finland accustomed to technology and information services ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

no

Was one of the most productive composers of popular music Toivo Kärki , and the most famous singer Olavi Virta -LRB- 1915 -- 1972 -RRB- ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

no

Do 79 percent of the population not use the Internet ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

no

Did the relationship between the Grand Duchy and the Russian Empire not sour when the Russian government made moves to restrict Finnish autonomy ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

no

Is finland , officially the republic of finland (`` `` republic of finland ('' '' , or (`` `` suomen tasavalta ('' '' in finnish and (`` `` republiken finland ('' '' in swedish , the long protocol name , which is not defined by the law?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

no

Is the capital city helsinki?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

no

Is finland a democratic , parliamentary republic?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a4

yes

For how long was Ford a member of the House of Representatives?	Over eight years.	S08/data/set3/a10

Ford was a member of the House of Representatives for twenty-four years, holding the Grand Rapids congressional district seat from 1949 to 1973.

For how long was Ford a member of the House of Representatives?	Ford served for over eight years as the Republican Minority Leader of the United States House of Representatives	S08/data/set3/a10

Ford was a member of the House of Representatives for twenty-four years, holding the Grand Rapids congressional district seat from 1949 to 1973.

Did ford get an award called "Congressman's congressman"?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a10

no

What positions Ford played in the school football team?	Center and linebacker	S08/data/set3/a10

[[u'1935', u'DATE'], [u'Ford', u'ORG'], [u'the Chicago Bears', u'ORG'], [u'Soldier Field', u'FAC']]

What positions Ford played in the school football team?	Captain	S08/data/set3/a10

[[u'1935', u'DATE'], [u'Ford', u'ORG'], [u'the Chicago Bears', u'ORG'], [u'Soldier Field', u'FAC']]

What did Ford say about his biological father?	He was abusive and had a history of hitting his mother.	S08/data/set3/a10

[[u'Ford', u'ORG'], [u'Watergate', u'EVENT']]

What did Ford say about his biological father?	his biological father was abusive and had a history of hitting his mother	S08/data/set3/a10

[[u'Ford', u'ORG'], [u'Watergate', u'EVENT']]

Who did Ford nominate for Vice President?	Bob Dole	S08/data/set3/a10

[[u'August 20', u'DATE'], [u'Ford', u'ORG'], [u'New York Governor Nelson', u'GPE']]

Who did Ford nominate for Vice President?	Nelson Rockefeller	S08/data/set3/a10

[[u'August 20', u'DATE'], [u'Ford', u'ORG'], [u'New York Governor Nelson', u'GPE']]

Was Ford active about Vietnamese affairs?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a10

no

Had Ford's wife married before?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a10

The Fords on their wedding day, October 15, 1948 On October 15, 1948, at Grace Episcopal Church in Grand Rapids, Ford married Elizabeth Bloomer Warren, a department store fashion consultant.

Had Ford's wife married before?	No	S08/data/set3/a10

The Fords on their wedding day, October 15, 1948 On October 15, 1948, at Grace Episcopal Church in Grand Rapids, Ford married Elizabeth Bloomer Warren, a department store fashion consultant.

Is Ford related with the assassination of John F. Kennedy?	Yes	S08/data/set3/a10

no

Did Gerald Ford serve as the Republican Minority Leader of the House of Representatives?	yes	S08/data/set3/a10

no

Did Gerald Ford serve as the Republican Minority Leader of the House of Representatives?	yes	S08/data/set3/a10

no


[[u'Ford', u'ORG'], [u'1941', u'DATE'], [u'Michigan', u'GPE']]

How many Eagle Scouts were involved in Ford's funeral procession?	400	S08/data/set3/a10

[[u'About 400', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Eagle Scouts', u'ORG']]

How many Eagle Scouts were involved in Ford's funeral procession?	About 400	S08/data/set3/a10

[[u'About 400', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Eagle Scouts', u'ORG']]

Which future Heisman Trophy winner did Ford tackle?	Jay Berwanger	S08/data/set3/a10

Ford did not intervene in Vietamese affairs, but did help extract friends of the U.S.

Which future Heisman Trophy winner did Ford tackle?	Jay Berwanger	S08/data/set3/a10

Ford did not intervene in Vietamese affairs, but did help extract friends of the U.S.

Has another US President been an Eagle Scout?	no	S08/data/set3/a10

He is the only US president who was an Eagle Scout.  

Has another US President been an Eagle Scout?	no	S08/data/set3/a10

He is the only US president who was an Eagle Scout.  

Did Ford need to do extra work to pay for college?	yes	S08/data/set3/a10

no

Did Ford need to do extra work to pay for college?	yes	S08/data/set3/a10

no

Have more than five Presidents lived past the age of 90?	no	S08/data/set3/a10

*Ford is one of only four former Presidents to live to 90 or more years of age.

Have more than five Presidents lived past the age of 90?	no	S08/data/set3/a10

*Ford is one of only four former Presidents to live to 90 or more years of age.

How do kwajalein and eniwetok relate?	The Monterey supported landings at both locations.	S08/data/set3/a10


What did Ford receive on April 13, 1942?	Ford received a commission as ensign in the US Naval Reserve.	S08/data/set3/a10

[[u'Ford', u'ORG'], [u'the U.S. Naval Reserve', u'ORG'], [u'April 13, 1942', u'DATE']]

Did they not claim Ford 's pardon was quid pro quo in exchange for Nixon 's resignation ?	They did claim Ford's pardon was quid pro quo.	S08/data/set3/a10

yes

Did the Dutch build the Elmina Castle?	No	S08/data/set2/a5

yes

Did the Dutch build the Elmina Castle?	no	S08/data/set2/a5

yes


[[u'the United Kingdom', u'GPE'], [u'1957', u'DATE'], [u'Peter N. Stearns', u'PERSON'], [u'William Leonard Langer', u'PERSON']]


[[u'the United Kingdom', u'GPE'], [u'1957', u'DATE'], [u'Peter N. Stearns', u'PERSON'], [u'William Leonard Langer', u'PERSON']]

How many regions is Ghana divided into?	10	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'Ghana Ghana', u'PERSON'], [u'10', u'CARDINAL'], [u'138', u'CARDINAL']]

How many regions is Ghana divided into?	10	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'Ghana Ghana', u'PERSON'], [u'10', u'CARDINAL'], [u'138', u'CARDINAL']]

Who is the head of state of Ghana?	President John Agyekum Kofuor	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'  The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]

Who is the head of state of Ghana?	John Agyekum Kufuor	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'  The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]

What is the dominant religion in Ghana?	Christian	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'  The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]

What is the dominant religion in Ghana?	christian	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'  The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]

What are the two subfamilies of the Native Ghanaian languages?	Kwa and Gur	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'Native Ghanaian', u'NORP'], [u'two', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Niger', u'GPE']]

What are the two subfamilies of the Native Ghanaian languages?	Kwa and Gur	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'Native Ghanaian', u'NORP'], [u'two', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Niger', u'GPE']]

What is the weather like at Lake Volta?	Warm and comparatively dry	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'  The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]

What is the weather like at Lake Volta?	warm and comparatively dry	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'  The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]

Is Ghana's head of state John Agyekum Kufuor?	yes	S08/data/set2/a5

no

Is Ghana's head of state John Agyekum Kufuor?	Yes	S08/data/set2/a5

no

What does the word Ghana mean?	warrior king	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'Ghana', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Warrior King', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Jackson', u'PERSON'], [u'John G. Introduction', u'PERSON'], [u'African', u'NORP'], [u'2001', u'DATE']]

What does the word Ghana mean?	Warrior King	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'Ghana', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Warrior King', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Jackson', u'PERSON'], [u'John G. Introduction', u'PERSON'], [u'African', u'NORP'], [u'2001', u'DATE']]

Who was Kwame Nkrumah?	founder and first president	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'  The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]

Who was Kwame Nkrumah?	founder and first president of the modern Ghanaian state	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'  The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]

Where is old Ghana in relation to present Ghana?	500 miles north	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'  The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]

Where is old Ghana in relation to present Ghana?	500 miles north of the present Ghana, and occupied the area between Rivers Senegal and Niger	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'  The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]

Who makes up Ghana's Parliament?	the New Patriotic Party and National Democratic Congress	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'Parliament', u'ORG'], [u'Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'two', u'CARDINAL'], [u'the New Patriotic Party', u'ORG'], [u'National Democratic Congress', u'ORG']]

Who makes up Ghana's Parliament?	the New Patriotic Party and National Democratic Congress	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'Parliament', u'ORG'], [u'Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'two', u'CARDINAL'], [u'the New Patriotic Party', u'ORG'], [u'National Democratic Congress', u'ORG']]

What European countries established states in Ghana?	The UK	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'European', u'NORP'], [u'Portuguese', u'NORP'], [u'the 15th century', u'DATE'], [u'British', u'NORP'], [u'Gold Coast', u'PERSON'], [u'1874', u'DATE']]

What European countries established states in Ghana?	Portugual, France, Britain, Netherlands	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'European', u'NORP'], [u'Portuguese', u'NORP'], [u'the 15th century', u'DATE'], [u'British', u'NORP'], [u'Gold Coast', u'PERSON'], [u'1874', u'DATE']]

What was Wagadugu?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'  The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]

What was controlled by Sundiata in 1240 AD, and absorbed into the larger Mali Empire?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'Sundiata', u'GPE'], [u'1240', u'DATE'], [u'Mali Empire', u'ORG']]

What connected the Akans to this Empire?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'Akans', u'NORP'], [u'Empire', u'PERSON']]

Is it true that anecdotal evidence connected the akans to this empire?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

no

Is it true that the portuguese came to ghana in the 15th century?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

yes

Is it true that agricultural expansion marked the period before 500?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

yes

What did Ghana capture in 1642?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'1637', u'DATE'], [u'Portuguese', u'NORP'], [u'Axim', u'GPE'], [u'1642', u'DATE'], [u'Fort St Anthony)', u'FAC']]

Is The Parliament of Ghana unicameral?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

no

Is Medieval Ghana (4th- 13th Century): The Republic of Ghana is named after the medieval Ghana Empire of West Africa. named after the medieval Ghana Empire of West Africa?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

no

What was on March?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'  The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]

	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

  The Republic of Ghana is a country in West Africa.

	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

  The Republic of Ghana is a country in West Africa.

The coastline is what?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

The climate is tropical.

Ghana 's spending on education has what?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

Ghana's spending on education has varied between 28 and 40 percent of its annual budget in the past decade.

Who sits at Osu Castle ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'  The Republic of Ghana', u'GPE'], [u'West Africa', u'GPE']]

Is all teaching done in English , Ghana 's official language ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

yes

Are Native Ghanaian languages divided into two linguistic subfamilies of the Niger-Congo language family ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

yes

Are more than 100 languages and dialects spoken in Ghana ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

no

Had the tax regime which started in 1998 a single rate but since September 2007 entered into a multiple rate regime ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

The tax regime which started in 1998 had a single rate but since September 2007 entered into a multiple rate regime.

Did European and other : 0.2 % Religions : Christian 63 % , African beliefs 21 % , Muslim 16 % , Facts on People of Ghana , not access July 13 , 2006 More than 100 languages and dialects are spoken in Ghana ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

no

Does this not allow retailers of taxable goods under Act 546 to charge a marginal 3 % on their sales and account on same to the VAT Service ?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

no

Is the republic of ghana a country in west africa?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

no

What happened with the portuguese in the 15th century?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

[[u'European', u'NORP'], [u'Portuguese', u'NORP'], [u'the 15th century', u'DATE'], [u'British', u'NORP'], [u'Gold Coast', u'PERSON'], [u'1874', u'DATE']]

Is the old ghana 500 miles?	NULL	S08/data/set2/a5

yes

Does the Gray Wolf share an ancestry with the domestic dog?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a6

no

Does the Gray Wolf share an ancestry with the domestic dog?	Yes.	S08/data/set1/a6

no

Do wolf pups tend to have darker fur than adults?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a6

no

Do wolf pups tend to have darker fur than adults?	Yes, They do tend to have darker furs	S08/data/set1/a6

no

Do wolves leave their pack?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a6

no

Do wolves leave their pack?	They leave their birth pack when they reach sexual maturity	S08/data/set1/a6

no

What kinds of coats do wolves have?	bulky coats with two layers	S08/data/set1/a6

[]

What kinds of coats do wolves have?	Tough guard hairs that repel water and dirt, and a dense, water-resistant layer	S08/data/set1/a6

[]

Where do wolves have scent glands?	Helping the woldf to effectively navigate over large expanses while concurrently keeping others informed of its whereabouts.	S08/data/set1/a6

[]

Where do wolves have scent glands?	between a wolf's toes	S08/data/set1/a6

[]

How much do wolves weigh?	typically varies between 32 and 62 kilograms	S08/data/set1/a6

[[u'the Arabian Wolf', u'ORG'], [u'as little as', u'PERCENT']]

How much do wolves weigh?	between 32 and 68 kilograms 	S08/data/set1/a6

[[u'the Arabian Wolf', u'ORG'], [u'as little as', u'PERCENT']]

Why do wolves howl?	Howling helps pack members keep in touch, allowing them to communicate effectively in thickly forested areas or over great distances. Howling also helps to call pack members to a specific location. Howling can also serve as a declaration of territory, as shown in a dominant wolf&apos;s tendency to respond to a human imitation of a "rival" wolf in an area the wolf considers its own. 	S08/data/set1/a6

Howling helps pack members keep in touch, allowing them to communicate effectively in thickly forested areas or over great distances.

Why do wolves howl?	To pack members keep in touch, allowing them to communicate effectively in thickly forested areas or over great distances	S08/data/set1/a6

Howling helps pack members keep in touch, allowing them to communicate effectively in thickly forested areas or over great distances.

What is surplus killing?	Surplus killing is defined as the killing of several prey animals too numerous to eat at one sitting.	S08/data/set1/a6

[[u'Carnivora', u'PERSON']]

What is surplus killing?	the killing of several prey animals too numerous to eat at one sitting	S08/data/set1/a6

[[u'Carnivora', u'PERSON']]

Are Gray Wolves native to North America?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a6

no

Are Gray Wolves native to North America?	No. Current theory suggests that it's from Eurasia	S08/data/set1/a6

no

Are a wolf's teeth its main weapons?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a6

no

Are a wolf's teeth its main weapons?	Yes	S08/data/set1/a6

no

Where is the largest gray wolf population thought to be found?	Kazakhstan	S08/data/set1/a6

[[u'North America', u'LOC']]

Where is the largest gray wolf population thought to be found?	Kazakhstan	S08/data/set1/a6

[[u'North America', u'LOC']]

To what genus does the gray wolf belong?	Canis	S08/data/set1/a6

While wolf predation on livestock does happen, loss of livestock by wolves makes up only a small percentage of total losses in North America.

To what genus does the gray wolf belong?	Canis	S08/data/set1/a6

While wolf predation on livestock does happen, loss of livestock by wolves makes up only a small percentage of total losses in North America.

When do wolves molt?	Late Spring or Early Summer	S08/data/set1/a6

[[u'late spring', u'DATE'], [u'early summer', u'DATE']]

When do wolves molt?	late spring or early summer	S08/data/set1/a6

[[u'late spring', u'DATE'], [u'early summer', u'DATE']]

Why is it beneficial for alpha males and females to forcefully prevent other wolves from mating?	A pack can only suppport one littler per year	S08/data/set1/a6

During this time, in fact, the alpha male and alpha female may be forced to prevent other wolves from mating with one another.   

Why is it beneficial for alpha males and females to forcefully prevent other wolves from mating?	The pack tension rises as each mature wolf feels urged to mate	S08/data/set1/a6

During this time, in fact, the alpha male and alpha female may be forced to prevent other wolves from mating with one another.   

What type of tools do biologists use to capture wolves for tagging?	Darting and Foot hold traps.	S08/data/set1/a6

[]

What type of tools do biologists use to capture wolves for tagging?	Darting and foot hold traps	S08/data/set1/a6

[]

Forward, erect ears and slightly bristle hackles are a sign of what in wolves?	Dominance	S08/data/set1/a6

The ears are erect and forward, and the hackles bristle slightly.

Forward, erect ears and slightly bristle hackles are a sign of what in wolves?	Dominance	S08/data/set1/a6

The ears are erect and forward, and the hackles bristle slightly.

Did Grover Cleveland win the 1884 election?	yes	S08/data/set3/a6

no

Did Grover Cleveland win the 1884 election?	yes	S08/data/set3/a6

no

Did Grover Cleveland support women's suffrage?	No	S08/data/set3/a6

yes

Did Grover Cleveland support women's suffrage?	no	S08/data/set3/a6

yes

Where was Grover Cleveland married?	In the White House	S08/data/set3/a6

[[u'Grover Cleveland', u'PERSON'], [u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the White House', u'ORG'], [u'June 2, 1886', u'DATE'], [u'Cleveland', u'GPE'], [u'Frances Cornelia Folsom', u'PERSON'], [u'Blue Room', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'White House', u'ORG']]

Where was Grover Cleveland married?	in the Blue Room in the White House	S08/data/set3/a6

[[u'Grover Cleveland', u'PERSON'], [u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the White House', u'ORG'], [u'June 2, 1886', u'DATE'], [u'Cleveland', u'GPE'], [u'Frances Cornelia Folsom', u'PERSON'], [u'Blue Room', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'White House', u'ORG']]

What did Cleveland die from?	A heart attack	S08/data/set3/a6

[[u'Grover Cleveland', u'PERSON'], [u'the Cleveland Family Papers', u'ORG'], [u'New Jersey', u'GPE']]

What did Cleveland die from?	a heart attack	S08/data/set3/a6

[[u'Grover Cleveland', u'PERSON'], [u'the Cleveland Family Papers', u'ORG'], [u'New Jersey', u'GPE']]

How many years after Cleveland left office did the U.S. win the Spanish-American War?	One Year	S08/data/set3/a6

[[u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'U.S.', u'GPE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'1898', u'DATE'], [u'one year', u'DATE']]

How many years after Cleveland left office did the U.S. win the Spanish-American War?	one	S08/data/set3/a6
