Did Volta have a passion for the study of electricity?	yes	S09/data/set4/a10

no

Did Volta have a passion for the study of electricity?	yes	S09/data/set4/a10

no

What is the battery made by Volta credited to be?	the first cell	S09/data/set4/a10

[[u'first', u'ORDINAL']]

What is the battery made by Volta credited to be?	the first cell	S09/data/set4/a10

[[u'first', u'ORDINAL']]

What important electrical unit was named in honor of Volta?	the volt	S09/data/set4/a10

[[u'1881', u'DATE']]

What important electrical unit was named in honor of Volta?	volt	S09/data/set4/a10

[[u'1881', u'DATE']]

Where did Volta enter retirement?	Spain	S09/data/set4/a10

[[u'Spain', u'GPE']]

Where did Volta enter retirement?	Spain	S09/data/set4/a10

[[u'Spain', u'GPE']]

Is it a disadvantage for something to be unsafe to handle?	yes	S09/data/set4/a10

no

Is it a disadvantage for something to be unsafe to handle?	yes	S09/data/set4/a10

no

Was Lombardy under Napoleon's rule in 1800?	yes	S09/data/set4/a10

no

Was Lombardy under Napoleon's rule in 1800?	yes	S09/data/set4/a10

no

Was the Italian 10.000 lira banknote created before the euro?	yes	S09/data/set4/a10

no

Was the Italian 10.000 lira banknote created before the euro?	yes	S09/data/set4/a10

no

For how many years did Alessandro Volta live?	53	S09/data/set4/a10

  Count Alessandro Giuseppe Antonio Anastasio Volta (February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827) was an Italian physicist known especially for the development of the first known electric battery in 1800.   

What was Alessandro Volta`s profession?	physisist	S09/data/set4/a10

[[u'Count Alessandro', u'PERSON'], [u'February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'1800', u'DATE']]

How old was Alessandro Volta when he died?	 82	S09/data/set4/a10

  Count Alessandro Giuseppe Antonio Anastasio Volta (February 18, 1745 - March 5, 1827) was an Italian physicist known especially for the development of the first known electric battery in 1800.   

How many years ago was it when Volta married the daughter of Count Ludovico Peregrini , Teresa , with whom he raised three sons?	215	S09/data/set4/a10

[[u'Austria', u'GPE'], [u'Lombardy', u'GPE'], [u'his day', u'DATE'], [u'France', u'GPE']]

Is volta buried in the city  of Como?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a10

no

Before 1796, was Lombardy ruled by Austria?	yes	S09/data/set4/a10

Before 1796, Lombardy was ruled by Austria.

When did lombardy come under Napoleon`s rule?	From 1796 to 1815	S09/data/set4/a10

[[u'1796 to 1815', u'DATE'], [u'Lombardy', u'PERSON'], [u'Napoleon', u'ORG']]

Where did he publish his invention of the Voltaic pile battery?	the Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society	S09/data/set4/a10


Is it true that his passion been always the study of electricity?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a10

no

His passion been always the study of what?	Electricity	S09/data/set4/a10

His passion had always been the study of electricity, and while still a young student he had even written a poem in Latin on this fascinating new discovery.

Did Amedeo Avogadro graduate?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a8

no

Did Amedeo Avogadro graduate?	yes	S09/data/set4/a8

no

Where was Avogadro a professor of physics?	University of Turin	S09/data/set4/a8

[[u'1820', u'DATE'], [u'the University of Turin', u'ORG']]

Where was Avogadro a professor of physics?	University of Turin	S09/data/set4/a8

[[u'1820', u'DATE'], [u'the University of Turin', u'ORG']]

How many children did Avogadro have?	six	S09/data/set4/a8

[[u'Italy', u'GPE'], [u'Avogadro', u'GPE']]

How many children did Avogadro have?	six	S09/data/set4/a8

[[u'Italy', u'GPE'], [u'Avogadro', u'GPE']]

What is Avogadro most noted for?	contributions to the theory of molarity and molecular weight	S09/data/set4/a8

[]

What is Avogadro most noted for?	contributions to the theory of molarity and molecular weight	S09/data/set4/a8

[]

What is Avogadro's number?	6.02214199x10 23	S09/data/set4/a8

[[u'one', u'CARDINAL'], [u'6.02214199x10 23', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Avogadro', u'ORG']]

What is Avogadro's number?	6.02214199x10 23	S09/data/set4/a8

[[u'one', u'CARDINAL'], [u'6.02214199x10 23', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Avogadro', u'ORG']]

In what year did Avogadro stop teaching at Turin University?	1853	S09/data/set4/a8

The unification of Italy did not happen during the life time of Avogadro.

In what year did Avogadro stop teaching at Turin University?	1823	S09/data/set4/a8

The unification of Italy did not happen during the life time of Avogadro.

What subject did Avogadro study first?	ecclesiastical law	S09/data/set4/a8

[[u'Italy', u'GPE'], [u'Avogadro', u'GPE']]

What subject did Avogadro study first?	ecclesiastical law	S09/data/set4/a8

[[u'Italy', u'GPE'], [u'Avogadro', u'GPE']]

What was Amedeo Avogadro`s birthplace?	Turin	S09/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

What was Amedeo Avogadro`s profession?	professor of physics	S09/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

How many years ago was it when he became a professor of physics at the University of Turin?	189	S09/data/set4/a8

[[u'Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Turin', u'GPE'], [u'1833', u'DATE'], [u'another twenty years', u'DATE']]

What is Amedeo Avogadro`s first name?	Amedeo	S09/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

What is Amedeo Avogadro`s last name?	Avogadro	S09/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

Was King Victor  Emmanuel  III there to pay  homage  to Avogadro?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a8

no

In fact, was Avogadro `s  famous  1811  paper written in French . )	Yes	S09/data/set4/a8

In fact, Avogadro's famous 1811 paper was written in French.)

Is avogadro `s  number commonly used to compute  the results  of chemical reactions?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a8

no

Hence, can relative molecular  masses be calculated from the masses  of gas samples?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a8

Hence, relative molecular masses can be calculated from the masses of gas samples.

Did he publish his work?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a8

no

Is it true that loschmidt calculated first the value of Avogadro number?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a8

no

Loschmidt calculated first the value of what?	Avogadro's number	S09/data/set4/a8

During his stay in Vercelli he wrote a concise note (memoria) in which he declared the hypothesis of what we now call Avogadro's law: This memoria he sent to De Lamétherie's Journal de Physique, de Chimie et d'Histoire naturelle and it was published in the edition of July 14, 1811 with the title Essai d'une manière de déterminer les masses relatives des molecules élémentaires des corps, et les proportions selon lesquelles elles entrent dans ces combinaisons .

Hence , can relative molecular masses be calculated from the masses of gas samples ?	yes	S09/data/set4/a8

Hence, relative molecular masses can be calculated from the masses of gas samples.

Can the title of this famous 1811 paper be roughly translated into English as "essay on determining the Relative Masses of the Elementary Molecules of Bodies" ?	Yes.	S09/data/set4/a8

The title of this famous 1811 paper can be roughly translated into English as "Essay on Determining the Relative Masses of the Elementary Molecules of Bodies".

What is Amedeo Avogadro?	A person.	S09/data/set4/a8

[[u'Amedeo Avogadro Lorenzo Romano', u'ORG'], [u'Carlo Avogadro', u'PERSON'], [u'Count', u'PERSON'], [u'Quaregna', u'GPE'], [u'Cerreto', u'PERSON'], [u'August 9, 1776', u'DATE'], [u'1856', u'DATE'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

Where is Amedeo Avogadro from?	Italy.	S09/data/set4/a8

[[u'1821', u'DATE'], [u'Sardinia', u'GPE'], [u'1823', u'DATE']]

When did Anders Celcius publish his observations on the aurora borealis?	1733	S09/data/set4/a5

[[u'Nuremberg', u'GPE'], [u'1733', u'DATE'], [u'316', u'CARDINAL'], [u'1716', u'CARDINAL']]

When did Anders Celcius publish his observations on the aurora borealis?	1733 	S09/data/set4/a5

[[u'Nuremberg', u'GPE'], [u'1733', u'DATE'], [u'316', u'CARDINAL'], [u'1716', u'CARDINAL']]

What did Anders Celsius determine about the boiling of water?	He determined the dependence of the boiling of water with atmospheric pressure.	S09/data/set4/a5

[]

What did Anders Celsius determine about the boiling of water?	dependence with atmospheric pressure	S09/data/set4/a5

[]

Which temperature scale did Celsius propose?	Celcius	S09/data/set4/a5

 Anders Celsius The observatory of Anders Celsius, from a contemporary engraving.

Which temperature scale did Celsius propose?	 the Celsius temperature scale 	S09/data/set4/a5

 Anders Celsius The observatory of Anders Celsius, from a contemporary engraving.

What is the boiling point of water dependent on?	atmospheric pressure	S09/data/set4/a5

[[u' Anders Celsius', u'PERSON'], [u'Anders Celsius', u'GPE']]

What is the boiling point of water dependent on?	atmospheric pressure	S09/data/set4/a5

[[u' Anders Celsius', u'PERSON'], [u'Anders Celsius', u'GPE']]

Where was Celsius born?	Uppsala in Sweden	S09/data/set4/a5

[[u'Celsius', u'DATE'], [u'Uppsala', u'GPE'], [u'Sweden', u'GPE']]

Where was Celsius born?	Uppsala, Sweden	S09/data/set4/a5

[[u'Celsius', u'DATE'], [u'Uppsala', u'GPE'], [u'Sweden', u'GPE']]

Whad did Celsius report in his paper "Observations of two persistent degrees on a thermometer"?	the freezing point is independent of latitude	S09/data/set4/a5

 Anders Celsius The observatory of Anders Celsius, from a contemporary engraving.

How old was Celsius when he died?	42	S09/data/set4/a5

In 1744 he died of tuberculosis in Uppsala, and was buried in the Old Uppsala Church.

How old was Celsius when he died?	42	S09/data/set4/a5

In 1744 he died of tuberculosis in Uppsala, and was buried in the Old Uppsala Church.

What is temperature would water have to be to be halfway between its standard boiling and freezing point?	50	S09/data/set4/a5

[[u' Anders Celsius', u'PERSON'], [u'Anders Celsius', u'GPE']]

What is the difference between Celsius' original temperature scale and the one we use today?	The scale was reversed by Carolus Linnaeus. 	S09/data/set4/a5

[[u' Anders Celsius', u'PERSON'], [u'Anders Celsius', u'GPE']]

What is the difference between Celsius' original temperature scale and the one we use today?	scale was reversed 	S09/data/set4/a5

[[u' Anders Celsius', u'PERSON'], [u'Anders Celsius', u'GPE']]

What was Anders Celsius`s profession?	professor of astronomy	S09/data/set4/a5

[[u' Anders Celsius', u'PERSON'], [u'Anders Celsius', u'GPE']]

How old was Anders Celsius when he died?	42	S09/data/set4/a5

In 1744 he died of tuberculosis in Uppsala, and was buried in the Old Uppsala Church.

What is Anders Celsius`s last name?	Celsius	S09/data/set4/a5

[[u' Anders Celsius', u'PERSON'], [u'Anders Celsius', u'GPE']]

Was celsius born in Uppsala  in Sweden?	yes	S09/data/set4/a5

no

Is The Celsius  crater  on the Moon named after him?	yes	S09/data/set4/a5

no

Was Anders Celsius  ( November 27 ,  1701  April 25 ,  1744  ) a Swedish  astronomer?	yes	S09/data/set4/a5

no

Was Anders Celsius the first  to perform  and  publish  careful experiments  aiming at the definition  of an international  temperature  scale  on scientific grounds?	yes	S09/data/set4/a5

no

He published a collection of what?	observations	S09/data/set4/a5

 Anders Celsius The observatory of Anders Celsius, from a contemporary engraving.

Pronouns in which location are marked for person , number and gender?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a3

Pronouns in Literary Arabic are marked for person, number and gender.

Can syllables begin with a vowel?	no	S09/data/set5/a3

Syllables cannot begin with a vowel.

Have many European languages borrowed numerous words from it?	yes	S09/data/set5/a3

As a result, many European languages have also borrowed numerous words from it.

Are the most active in Damascus and Cairo?	(bad question)	S09/data/set5/a3

yes

Do arabs consider literary Arabic?	(bad question)	S09/data/set5/a3

yes

Was Arabic vehicle in science?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a3

yes

Is it true that the sociolinguistic situation of Arabic provides a prime example of the linguistic phenomenon?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a3

no

The sociolinguistic situation of Arabic provides a prime example of what?	the linguistic phenomenon of diglossia	S09/data/set5/a3

The sociolinguistic situation of Arabic in modern times provides a prime example of the linguistic phenomenon of diglossia, which is the normal use of two separate varieties of the same language, usually in different social situations.

Is arabic source of vocabulary?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a3

yes

Is arabic language of the Qur an?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a3

no

Is it true that most speak Arabic as their native language?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a3

yes

Are pronouns in Literary Arabic marked for person , number and gender ?	yes	S09/data/set5/a3

no

However , are non-human plural nouns grammatically considered to be feminine singular ?	yes	S09/data/set5/a3

However, non-human plural nouns are grammatically considered to be feminine singular.

Is a bee an insect?	yes	S09/data/set1/a8

no

Are bees related to ants?	yes	S09/data/set1/a8

no

Have managed populations of European honey bees experienced substantial declines?	yes	S09/data/set1/a8

Recently, managed populations of European honey bees have experienced substantial declines.

Where do bees live?	in colonies	S09/data/set1/a8

[[u'Dasypodaidae', u'PERSON'], [u'Colletidae', u'PERSON']]

When do bumblebee colonies reach peak population?	mid to late summer	S09/data/set1/a8

[]

What do people commonly call cleptoparasitic bees?	cuckoo bees	S09/data/set1/a8

[[u'Nomadinae', u'ORG']]

How did vespoid wasps evolve?	from predatory ancestors	S09/data/set1/a8

This same evolutionary scenario has also occurred within the vespoid wasps, where the group known as "pollen wasps" also evolved from predatory ancestors.

What do humans use bees for?	honey	S09/data/set1/a8

[[u'One', u'CARDINAL']]

Why do honey bee queens continue to lay eggs during the foraging season?	to replace daily casualties	S09/data/set1/a8

  Bees are flying insects closely related to wasps and ants.

When did Beijing host the Olympic Games?	2008	S09/data/set3/a7

[[u'2008', u'DATE'], [u'Olympic Games', u'EVENT']]

When was the An Shi Rebellion launched?	in 755 AD	S09/data/set3/a7

[[u'Shi Rebellion', u'PERSON'], [u'755', u'CARDINAL']]

In 1949, where did Communist forces enter without a fight?	Beiping	S09/data/set3/a7

Mao Zedong proclaiming the establishment of the People's Republic of China in 1949 A man stands before a column of tanks which were sent to Tiananmen Square earlier to suppress the Tiananmen Square protests of 1989 On 31 January 1949, during the Chinese Civil War, Communist forces entered Beiping without a fight.

When did Yuan Shikai die?	1916	S09/data/set3/a7

[[u'1915', u'DATE']]

Where does air pollution in Beijing come from?	surrounding cities and provinces	S09/data/set3/a7

[[u'Japan', u'GPE'], [u'Korea', u'GPE'], [u'North America', u'LOC'], [u'Europe', u'LOC'], [u'Southeast Asia', u'LOC'], [u'Beijing', u'GPE'], [u'every year', u'DATE']]

As of August 1st, 2006, how many trains stop daily at the Beijing Railway Station or the Beijing West Railway Station?	167	S09/data/set3/a7

As of 1 August 2006, Beijing Railway Station has 167 trains stopping daily, while Beijing West Railway Station has 176 trains.

What is the name of a university (or similar institution for imparting higher education) in Beijing?	Tsinghua University	S09/data/set3/a7

[[u'English', u'LANGUAGE'], [u'Chinese', u'NORP'], [u'Wade-Giles', u'ORG'], [u'Pei-ching', u'PERSON'], [u'English', u'LANGUAGE'], [u'Peking', u'GPE'], [u'China', u'GPE'], [u"the People's Republic of China", u'GPE']]

Are famous middle  schools  in Beijing :?	Yes	S09/data/set3/a7

no

Could Blaise Pascal move without crutches?	He could move without crutches until a paralytic attack in 1647.	S09/data/set4/a4

In 1647, a paralytic attack so disabled him that he could not move without crutches.

Could Blaise Pascal move without crutches?	no	S09/data/set4/a4

In 1647, a paralytic attack so disabled him that he could not move without crutches.

Has the name Pascal been given to the SI unit of pressure?	yes	S09/data/set4/a4

In honor of his scientific contributions, the name Pascal has been given to the SI unit of pressure, to a programming language, and Pascal's law (an important principle of hydrostatics), and as mentioned above, Pascal's triangle and Pascal's wager still bear his name.

Has the name Pascal been given to the SI unit of pressure?	yes	S09/data/set4/a4

In honor of his scientific contributions, the name Pascal has been given to the SI unit of pressure, to a programming language, and Pascal's law (an important principle of hydrostatics), and as mentioned above, Pascal's triangle and Pascal's wager still bear his name.

From what did Pascal suffer throughout his life?	ill health	S09/data/set4/a4

But that didn't stop all of educated France from reading them.

From what did Pascal suffer throughout his life?	poor health	S09/data/set4/a4

But that didn't stop all of educated France from reading them.

What did Pascal argue was as perfect as possible?	the procedure used in geometry 	S09/data/set4/a4

[[u'Pascal', u'PERSON']]

What did Pascal argue was as perfect as possible?	the procedure used in geometry	S09/data/set4/a4

[[u'Pascal', u'PERSON']]

What is the best physician?	Time	S09/data/set4/a4

[[u'Blaise Pascal', u'PERSON'], [u'June 19 1623', u'DATE'], [u'August 19 1662', u'DATE'], [u'French', u'NORP']]

Who was the eldest sibling?	Gilberte	S09/data/set4/a4

[[u'Blaise Pascal', u'PERSON'], [u'June 19 1623', u'DATE'], [u'August 19 1662', u'DATE'], [u'French', u'NORP']]

Aside from the Provincial Letters' religious influence, were they popular as a literary work?	yes	S09/data/set4/a4

Aside from their religious influence, the Provincial Letters were popular as a literary work.

Aside from the Provincial Letters' religious influence, were they popular as a literary work?	yes	S09/data/set4/a4

Aside from their religious influence, the Provincial Letters were popular as a literary work.

Of whose continual poor health was the cause never precisely determined?	Blaise Pascal	S09/data/set4/a4

Despite the autopsy, the cause of his continual poor health was never precisely determined, though speculation focuses on tuberculosis, stomach cancer, or a combination of the two.

Is the purfling just for decoration?	No	S09/data/set2/a9

yes

What does violincello mean?	Violincello means "little violene".	S09/data/set2/a9

[[u'Cello', u'PRODUCT'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

What are the two materials that bows are made of traditionally? 	Traditionally, bows are made from pernambuco or brazilwood.	S09/data/set2/a9

[]

What is used to tune a cello?	Pegs are used to tune a cello.	S09/data/set2/a9

[]

What is used to tune a cello?	the pegs	S09/data/set2/a9

[]

Which harmonics can produce any notes above middle C? 	Artificial harmonics can produce any notes above middle C.	S09/data/set2/a9

Artificial harmonics (also called False harmonics), in which the player depresses the string fully with one finger while touching the same string lightly with another finger, can produce any notes above middle C. They usually appear with the touching note a perfect fourth above the stopped note, which produces a sound two octaves above the stopped note, although other intervals are available.

Which harmonics can produce any notes above middle C? 	Artificial harmonics	S09/data/set2/a9

Artificial harmonics (also called False harmonics), in which the player depresses the string fully with one finger while touching the same string lightly with another finger, can produce any notes above middle C. They usually appear with the touching note a perfect fourth above the stopped note, which produces a sound two octaves above the stopped note, although other intervals are available.

Who referred to the cello as “basso de viola da braccio"?	Monteverdi referred to the cello as "basso de viola da braccio".	S09/data/set2/a9

[]

Who referred to the cello as “basso de viola da braccio"?	Monteverdi	S09/data/set2/a9

[]

Where is the violincello held?	The violincello is held on the shoulder.	S09/data/set2/a9

[[u'Violone', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Italian', u'NORP'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

Where is the violincello held?	on the shoulder	S09/data/set2/a9

[[u'Violone', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Italian', u'NORP'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

Is there cello in performances by Rihanna?	yes	S09/data/set2/a9

no

Is there cello in performances by Rihanna?	Yes	S09/data/set2/a9

no

Are cellos constructed with glue?	yes	S09/data/set2/a9

no

Are cellos constructed with glue?	yes	S09/data/set2/a9

no

What is cello an abbreviation of?	violoncello	S09/data/set2/a9

[[u'Cello', u'PRODUCT'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

What is cello an abbreviation of?	violoncello	S09/data/set2/a9

[[u'Cello', u'PRODUCT'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

What position is used to play the cello?	a gamba	S09/data/set2/a9

[]

What position is used to play the cello?	seated	S09/data/set2/a9

[]

What is a person who plays the cello called?	cellist	S09/data/set2/a9

[]

What is a person who plays the cello called?	cellist	S09/data/set2/a9

[]

Why is there purling on a cello?	to stop cracks from forming ****misspelled****	S09/data/set2/a9

  The violoncello (abbreviated to cello, or 'cello, plural cellos or celliâ€”the c is , as in the ch in "check", thus "chel-lo") is a bowed string instrument.

When did the first educational works appear for the cello?	the 18th century	S09/data/set2/a9

[[u'Italian', u'NORP'], [u'1660', u'DATE'], [u'Bologna', u'GPE']]

When did the first educational works appear for the cello?	18th century	S09/data/set2/a9

[[u'Italian', u'NORP'], [u'1660', u'DATE'], [u'Bologna', u'GPE']]

What cello manufacturer should I buy from if I want to play outside?	Luis & Clark	S09/data/set2/a9

[]

What cello manufacturer should I buy from if I want to play outside?	Luis & Clark	S09/data/set2/a9

[]

Was Charles-Augustin de Coulomb a member of the National Institute?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a6

no

Was Charles-Augustin de Coulomb a member of the National Institute?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a6

no

Was Charles-Augustin de Coulomb's father's family in Montpellier? 	Yes	S09/data/set4/a6

no

Was Charles-Augustin de Coulomb's father's family in Montpellier? 	Yes	S09/data/set4/a6

no

Where did Charles-Augustin de Coulomb die?	Charles-Augustin de Coulomb died in Paris.	S09/data/set4/a6

[[u'Charles Augustin de Coulomb', u'PERSON'], [u'June 14, 1736', u'DATE'], [u'Angoul\xc3\xaame', u'GPE'], [u'France', u'GPE'], [u'August 23, 1806', u'DATE'], [u'Paris', u'GPE'], [u'France', u'GPE'], [u'French', u'NORP']]

Where did Charles-Augustin de Coulomb die?	Paris, France	S09/data/set4/a6

[[u'Charles Augustin de Coulomb', u'PERSON'], [u'June 14, 1736', u'DATE'], [u'Angoul\xc3\xaame', u'GPE'], [u'France', u'GPE'], [u'August 23, 1806', u'DATE'], [u'Paris', u'GPE'], [u'France', u'GPE'], [u'French', u'NORP']]

When was Charles-Augustin de Coulomb permanently stationed in Paris?	Charles-Augustin de Coulomb was permanently stationed in Paris in 1781.	S09/data/set4/a6

[[u'1781', u'DATE'], [u'Paris', u'GPE']]

When was Charles-Augustin de Coulomb permanently stationed in Paris?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a6

[[u'1781', u'DATE'], [u'Paris', u'GPE']]

What contribution did Charles-Augustin de Coulomb make to the field of geotechnical engineering?	Retaining wall design	S09/data/set4/a6

[[u'1789', u'DATE'], [u'two', u'CARDINAL']]

Where did the construction of Fort Bourbon take place?	The construction of Fort Bourbon took place in Martinique.	S09/data/set4/a6

[[u'1761', u'DATE'], [u'British', u'NORP'], [u'1764', u'DATE'], [u'the Fort Bourbon', u'FAC'], [u'Rochemore', u'GPE'], [u'French', u'NORP'], [u'the middle of the English', u'DATE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'Seven', u'CARDINAL']]

Where did the construction of Fort Bourbon take place?	Martinique 	S09/data/set4/a6

[[u'1761', u'DATE'], [u'British', u'NORP'], [u'1764', u'DATE'], [u'the Fort Bourbon', u'FAC'], [u'Rochemore', u'GPE'], [u'French', u'NORP'], [u'the middle of the English', u'DATE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'Seven', u'CARDINAL']]

What is the definition of the electrostatic force of attraction and repulsion? 	Coulomb's law is the definition of the electrostatic force of attraction and repulsion.	S09/data/set4/a6

[[u'Coulomb', u'PERSON']]

What is the definition of the electrostatic force of attraction and repulsion? 	Coulomb's Law	S09/data/set4/a6

[[u'Coulomb', u'PERSON']]

When did Charles-Augustin de Coulomb retire to a small estate he possessed at Blois?	Charles-Augustin de Coulomb retired to a small estate he possessed at Blois on the outbreak of the revolution in 1789.	S09/data/set4/a6

[[u'1789', u'DATE'], [u'Blois', u'ORG']]

When did Charles-Augustin de Coulomb retire to a small estate he possessed at Blois?	1789	S09/data/set4/a6

[[u'1789', u'DATE'], [u'Blois', u'ORG']]

If Charles-Augustin de Coulomb was alive today, how old would he have been?	273	S09/data/set4/a6

  Charles Augustin de Coulomb (born June 14, 1736, AngoulÃªme, France - died August 23, 1806, Paris, France) was a French physicist.

For how many years did Charles-Augustin de Coulomb live?	70	S09/data/set4/a6

On magnetism" (1789) Coulomb explained the laws of attraction and repulsion between electric charges and magnetic poles, although he did not find any relationship between the two phenomena.

How old was Charles-Augustin de Coulomb when he died?	1806	S09/data/set4/a6

  Charles Augustin de Coulomb (born June 14, 1736, AngoulÃªme, France - died August 23, 1806, Paris, France) was a French physicist.

How many years ago did he resign his appointment as intendant de eaux et fontaine ?	220	S09/data/set4/a6

[[u'1789', u'DATE'], [u'two', u'CARDINAL']]

How many years ago did Charles-Augustin de Coulomb die?	203	S09/data/set4/a6

[[u'1789', u'DATE'], [u'two', u'CARDINAL']]

Was The SI  unit  of charge , the  coulomb , named after him?	yes	S09/data/set4/a6

no

Was coulomb born in AngoulÃªme,  France ,  to a well  to do  family?	yes	S09/data/set4/a6

no

Was his father ,  Henri  Coulomb , inspector of the Royal  Fields  in Montpellier?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a6

no

Is coulomb distinguished in the history  of mechanics  and  of electricity and  magnetism?	yes	S09/data/set4/a6

no

Was Charles Augustin  de Coulomb  ( born  June  14 ,  1736 ,  AngoulÃªme ,  France  -  died August 23 ,  1806 ,  Paris ,  France  ) a French  physicist?	yes	S09/data/set4/a6

no

When was Charles-Augustin de Coulomb born?	June 14, 1736	S09/data/set4/a6

[[u'Charles Augustin de Coulomb', u'PERSON'], [u'June 14, 1736', u'DATE'], [u'Angoul\xc3\xaame', u'GPE'], [u'France', u'GPE'], [u'August 23, 1806', u'DATE'], [u'Paris', u'GPE'], [u'France', u'GPE'], [u'French', u'NORP']]

He discovered an inverse relationship of what?	distance and electric force	S09/data/set4/a6

  Charles Augustin de Coulomb (born June 14, 1736, AngoulÃªme, France - died August 23, 1806, Paris, France) was a French physicist.

Where is Charles-Augustin de Coulomb from?	France	S09/data/set4/a6

[[u'Charles Augustin de Coulomb', u'PERSON'], [u'June 14, 1736', u'DATE'], [u'Angoul\xc3\xaame', u'GPE'], [u'France', u'GPE'], [u'August 23, 1806', u'DATE'], [u'Paris', u'GPE'], [u'France', u'GPE'], [u'French', u'NORP']]

What was Chinese language`s profession?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

[[u'Chinese', u'NORP'], [u'the Sinitic language(s', u'LOC']]

What is Chinese language`s first name?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

[[u'Chinese', u'NORP'], [u'the Sinitic language(s', u'LOC']]

What is Chinese language`s last name?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

[[u'Chinese', u'NORP'], [u'the Sinitic language(s', u'LOC']]

How many offspring did Chinese language have?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

[[u'Mandarin', u'LANGUAGE'], [u'Sinitic', u'ORG'], [u'North', u'LOC'], [u'Southwest', u'LOC'], [u'Central or Southeastern', u'NORP']]

The Mandarin dialects in which location have experienced a dramatic decrease in sounds and so have far more multisyllabic words than most other spoken varieties?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

The Mandarin dialects in particular have experienced a dramatic decrease in sounds and so have far more multisyllabic words than most other spoken varieties.

In North Korea, has Hanja been discontinued?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

In North Korea, Hanja has been discontinued.

The most  widespread is the Palladius  system?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

  Chinese or the Sinitic language(s) is a language family consisting of languages mutually unintelligible to varying degrees. *

Is the Vietnamese  term  for Chinese writing HÃ¡n t?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

no

Did the Empire have little success?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

yes

When are most of these groups mutually unintelligible?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

[[u'Chinese', u'NORP'], [u'the Sinitic language(s', u'LOC']]

What is the population of Chinese language?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

[[u'Chinese', u'NORP'], [u'Sino-Tibetan', u'NORP'], [u'Jerry Norman', u'PERSON']]

Is the most widespread the Palladius system?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

no

Are most of these groups mutually unintelligible?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

yes

In what country is Chinese language located?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

BBC NEWS | UK | Magazine | How hard is it to learn Chinese?

Is it true that one-fifth of world population speak some form of Chinese?	yes	S09/data/set5/a7

no

One-fifth of world population speak some form of what?	Chinese	S09/data/set5/a7

About one-fifth of the worldâ€™s population, or over one billion people, speak some form of Chinese as their native language.

Is mandarin spoken Chinese distinguished by its high level?	no, it's distinguished by diversity	S09/data/set5/a7

no

Is standard Mandarin language of People Republic?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

no

Are there many systems of romanization for the chinese languages due to the Chinese`s own lack of phonetic transcription until modern times ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

no

May the idea of Chinese as a language family suggest that the chinese identity is much more fragmentary and disunified than Chinese language actually is and as such is often looked upon as culturally and politically provocative ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

To Chinese nationalists, the idea of Chinese as a language family may suggest that the Chinese identity is much more fragmentary and disunified than it actually is and as such is often looked upon as culturally and politically provocative.

Are most chinese words formed out of native chinese morphemes , including words describing imported objects and ideas ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

yes

May a native of Guangzhou speak Standard Cantonese and putonghua , a resident of Taiwan , both taiwanese and putonghua/guoyu ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

A native of Guangzhou may speak Standard Cantonese and putonghua, a resident of Taiwan, both Taiwanese and putonghua/guoyu.

Refer most chinese and chinese linguists to chinese as a single language and Chinese language`s subdivisions dialects , while others call chinese a language family ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

Most Chinese and Chinese linguists refer to Chinese as a single language and its subdivisions dialects, while others call Chinese a language family.

Are there between 7 and 13 main regional groups of Chinese , of which the most spoken , by far , is about 850 million , followed by 90 million , 70 million and 70 million ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a7

no

Copenhagen is the capital of what country?	Denmark	S09/data/set3/a8

  Copenhagen ( ;  ) is the capital and largest city of Denmark, with a population of 1,161,063.  

Copenhagen is the capital of what country?	Denmark	S09/data/set3/a8

  Copenhagen ( ;  ) is the capital and largest city of Denmark, with a population of 1,161,063.  

What is the population of Copenhagen?	1,161,063	S09/data/set3/a8

[[u'  ', u'GPE'], [u'Copenhagen (', u'LANGUAGE'], [u'Denmark', u'GPE'], [u'1,161,063', u'CARDINAL']]

What is the population of Copenhagen?	1,153,615	S09/data/set3/a8

[[u'  ', u'GPE'], [u'Copenhagen (', u'LANGUAGE'], [u'Denmark', u'GPE'], [u'1,161,063', u'CARDINAL']]

What transnational bridge was completed in 2000?	Oresund Bridge	S09/data/set3/a8

[[u'Christian', u'NORP'], [u'1606', u'CARDINAL']]

What transnational bridge was completed in 2000?	Oresund Bridge	S09/data/set3/a8

[[u'Christian', u'NORP'], [u'1606', u'CARDINAL']]

Why is Copenhagen a regional hub?	Its strategic location and excellent infrastructure	S09/data/set3/a8

Its strategic location and excellent infrastructure with the largest airport in Scandinavia  located 14 minutes by train from the city centre, has made it a regional hub and a popular location for regional headquarters  as well as conventions.

Why is Copenhagen a regional hub?	Its strategic location and excellent infrastructure with the largest airport in Scandinavia[6] located 14 minutes by train from the city centre	S09/data/set3/a8

Its strategic location and excellent infrastructure with the largest airport in Scandinavia  located 14 minutes by train from the city centre, has made it a regional hub and a popular location for regional headquarters  as well as conventions.

What happened to Copenhagen between 1251 and 1255?	a bunch of things	S09/data/set3/a8

[[u'  ', u'GPE'], [u'Copenhagen (', u'LANGUAGE'], [u'Denmark', u'GPE'], [u'1,161,063', u'CARDINAL']]

Copenhagen is ranked number one worldwide for which things?	Most Livable City in the World, 	S09/data/set3/a8

  Copenhagen ( ;  ) is the capital and largest city of Denmark, with a population of 1,161,063.  

Copenhagen is ranked number one worldwide for which things?	Most Livable City, Location Ranking Survey	S09/data/set3/a8

  Copenhagen ( ;  ) is the capital and largest city of Denmark, with a population of 1,161,063.  

Why did German troops occupy Copenhagen?	Because it was WW2	S09/data/set3/a8

During World War II, Copenhagen was occupied by German troops along with the rest of the country from 9 April 1940 until 4 May 1945.

Have cymbals been used historically to suggest bacchanal?	Yes	S09/data/set2/a6

Clash cymbals have traditionally been accompanied by the bass drum playing an identical part.

Have cymbals been used historically to suggest bacchanal?	Yes	S09/data/set2/a6

Clash cymbals have traditionally been accompanied by the bass drum playing an identical part.

Can the origins of cymbals be traced to prehistoric times?	Yes	S09/data/set2/a6

The origins of cymbals can be traced back to prehistoric times.

Can the origins of cymbals be traced to prehistoric times?	Yes	S09/data/set2/a6

The origins of cymbals can be traced back to prehistoric times.

Are cymbals used in moden orchestras?	Yes	S09/data/set2/a6

no

Are cymbals used in moden orchestras?	Yes	S09/data/set2/a6

no

What are the most common Cymbals?	 The most common Cymbals are the Hi-Hats, Crash, Splash, Ride, and China.	S09/data/set2/a6

[]

What are the most common Cymbals?	Hi-Hats, Crash, Splash, Ride, and China	S09/data/set2/a6

[]

What is the second main orchestral use of cymbals?	The suspended cymbal is the second main orchestral use of symbals.	S09/data/set2/a6

[]

What is the second main orchestral use of cymbals?	The suspended cymbal	S09/data/set2/a6

[]

What have clash cymbals traditionally been accompanied by?	Clash cymbals have traditionally been accompanied by the bass drum playing an identical part.	S09/data/set2/a6

[]

What have clash cymbals traditionally been accompanied by?	The bass drum playing an identical part	S09/data/set2/a6

[]

What happens when the center of a Cymbal is hit?	It causes a sound which is in a higher register than the rest of the symbal.	S09/data/set2/a6

[]

What happens when the center of a Cymbal is hit?	It causes a sound which is in a higher register than the rest of the cymbal	S09/data/set2/a6

[]

What is an effective way to accentuate a note?	Playing a bass drum playing an identical part is an effective way to accentuate a note.	S09/data/set2/a6

[[u'two', u'CARDINAL']]

What is an effective way to accentuate a note?	The combination of a clash cymbol being accompanied by a bass drum playing an identical part, played loudly	S09/data/set2/a6

[[u'two', u'CARDINAL']]

From what type of Cymbals can a expert player obtain an enormous dynamic range?	An expert player can obtain an enormous dynamic range from crash cymbals.	S09/data/set2/a6

A skilled player can obtain an enormous dynamic range from such a pair of cymbals.

From what type of Cymbals can a expert player obtain an enormous dynamic range?	Crash cymbals	S09/data/set2/a6

A skilled player can obtain an enormous dynamic range from such a pair of cymbals.

Can the origins of cymbals be traced back to prehistoric times?	yes	S09/data/set2/a6

The origins of cymbals can be traced back to prehistoric times.

Can the origins of cymbals be traced back to prehistoric times?	Yes	S09/data/set2/a6

The origins of cymbals can be traced back to prehistoric times.

Did the modern hi-hat evolve from clash cymbals?	yes	S09/data/set2/a6

no

Did the modern hi-hat evolve from clash cymbals?	Yes	S09/data/set2/a6

no

What is the center of a cymbal called?	Bell	S09/data/set2/a6

[[u'one', u'CARDINAL'], [u'one', u'CARDINAL']]

What is the center of a cymbal called?	bell	S09/data/set2/a6

[[u'one', u'CARDINAL'], [u'one', u'CARDINAL']]

What part of the cymbal gets the best "crash"?	Edge or rim	S09/data/set2/a6

[]

What part of the cymbal gets the best "crash"?	edge or rim	S09/data/set2/a6

[]

What is the second main orchestral use of cymbals?	the suspended cymbal	S09/data/set2/a6

[]

What is the second main orchestral use of cymbals?	the suspended cymbal	S09/data/set2/a6

[]

What two instruments form the modern drum kit?	the cymbals and the drum	S09/data/set2/a6

[[u'one', u'CARDINAL'], [u'two', u'CARDINAL']]

What Greek mythical creatures were depicted holding cymbals?	fauns and satyrs	S09/data/set2/a6

[[u'Greek', u'NORP']]

What Greek mythical creatures were depicted holding cymbals?	fauns and satyrs	S09/data/set2/a6

[[u'Greek', u'NORP']]

What are orchestral crash cymbals technically called?	a pair of clash cymbals	S09/data/set2/a6

[]

What are orchestral crash cymbals technically called?	clash cymbals	S09/data/set2/a6

[]

Is Dhaka located on the eastern banks of the Buriganga River?	Yes	S09/data/set3/a3

no

Is University of Dhaka the largest public university in Dhaka?	Yes	S09/data/set3/a3

no

How much area does Dhaka cover?	1462.60 square kilometers	S09/data/set3/a3

[[u'Dhaka', u'GPE'], [u'Bangladesh', u'GPE'], [u'Dhaka', u'GPE']]

How many people did the 1970 Bhola cyclone kill?	500,000	S09/data/set3/a3

[[u'Dhaka', u'GPE'], [u'Bangladesh', u'GPE'], [u'Dhaka', u'GPE']]

When is the end of the independence war of Bangladesh?	December 16, 1971	S09/data/set3/a3

[[u'Archer', u'PERSON'], [u'Department of State', u'ORG'], [u'United States', u'GPE'], [u'nine months', u'DATE'], [u'Bangladesh Forces', u'ORG'], [u'the Pakistani Army', u'ORG'], [u'the Mitra Bahini', u'ORG'], [u'December 16', u'DATE'], [u'Bangladesh', u'GPE']]

Did the Mughals arrive in Dhaka?	Yes	S09/data/set3/a3

no

What is given for the number of native speakers?	No figure is given for the number of native speakers.	S09/data/set5/a1

[[u'English', u'LANGUAGE'], [u'third', u'ORDINAL'], [u'Mandarin Chinese', u'LOC'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP']]

Is english an intonation  language?	Yes	S09/data/set5/a1

no

Is the stressed  syllable called the nuclear  syllable?	yes	S09/data/set5/a1

no

Are books, magazines, and newspapers written in English available?	yes	S09/data/set5/a1

no

Is the syntax of German different with different rules?	yes	S09/data/set5/a1

no

Is it true that semantics causes a number of false friends?	true	S09/data/set5/a1

yes

Here , are all syllables unstressed , except the syllables/words best and done , which are stressed ?	yes	S09/data/set5/a1

Here, all syllables are unstressed, except the syllables/words best and done, which are stressed.

Are many words describing the navy , types of ships , and other objects or activities on the water of dutch origin ?	yes	S09/data/set5/a1

no

Are local variations in the formal written version of the language quite limited , being restricted largely to the spelling differences between British and American English ?	yes	S09/data/set5/a1

no

What do we refer musicians who play flute?	A flute player, a flautist or a flutist. 	S09/data/set2/a5

[]

What do we refer musicians who play flute?	A flute player, a flautist, or a flutist	S09/data/set2/a5

[]

When was a three-holed flute made from a mammoth tusk discovered?	2004.	S09/data/set2/a5

[[u'three', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Gei\xc3\x9fenkl\xc3\xb6sterle', u'FAC'], [u'German', u'NORP'], [u'30,000', u'CARDINAL'], [u'2004', u'DATE'], [u'two', u'CARDINAL'], [u'a decade earlier', u'DATE'], [u'Germany', u'GPE'], [u'36,000 years ago', u'DATE']]

When was a three-holed flute made from a mammoth tusk discovered?	In 2004	S09/data/set2/a5

[[u'three', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Gei\xc3\x9fenkl\xc3\xb6sterle', u'FAC'], [u'German', u'NORP'], [u'30,000', u'CARDINAL'], [u'2004', u'DATE'], [u'two', u'CARDINAL'], [u'a decade earlier', u'DATE'], [u'Germany', u'GPE'], [u'36,000 years ago', u'DATE']]

When did the tin whistle first appear?	12th century.	S09/data/set2/a5

[[u'Irish', u'NORP'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the 12th century', u'DATE'], [u'the 14th century', u'DATE']]

When did the tin whistle first appear?	In the 12th century	S09/data/set2/a5

[[u'Irish', u'NORP'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'the 12th century', u'DATE'], [u'the 14th century', u'DATE']]

What are the oldest known musical instruments?	A three holed-flute made from a mammoth tusk and two flutes made from swan's bones.	S09/data/set2/a5

[]

What are the oldest known musical instruments?	A three-holed flute made from a mammoth tusk and two flutes made from swans' bones are among the oldest known musical instruments	S09/data/set2/a5

[]

When was the pan flute spread to other parts of Europe?	7th century BC.	S09/data/set2/a5

[[u'Greece', u'GPE'], [u'the 7th century', u'DATE'], [u'Europe', u'LOC']]

When was the pan flute spread to other parts of Europe?	After the 7th century BC	S09/data/set2/a5

[[u'Greece', u'GPE'], [u'the 7th century', u'DATE'], [u'Europe', u'LOC']]

What does the air stream across this hole create?	A Bernoulli, or siphon.	S09/data/set2/a5

[[u'Bernoulli', u'GPE'], [u'Karman', u'NORP']]

Are fennec foxes endangered?	no	S09/data/set1/a6

yes

Are fennec foxes endangered?	No	S09/data/set1/a6

yes

Does the diet of foxes include reptiles?	yes	S09/data/set1/a6

no

Does the diet of foxes include reptiles?	Yes	S09/data/set1/a6

no

How long do most foxes live?	Most foxes live 2 to 3 years, but they can survive for up to 10 years or even longer in captivity.	S09/data/set1/a6

[[u'Skeleton Most', u'PERSON'], [u'2', u'CARDINAL'], [u'3 years', u'DATE'], [u'up to 10 years', u'DATE']]

How long do most foxes live?	2 to 3 years	S09/data/set1/a6

[[u'Skeleton Most', u'PERSON'], [u'2', u'CARDINAL'], [u'3 years', u'DATE'], [u'up to 10 years', u'DATE']]

In what country did fox hunting originate?	the United Kingdom	S09/data/set1/a6

Other fox species do not reproduce as readily as the red fox, and are endangered in their native environments.

In what country did fox hunting originate?	in the United Kingdom	S09/data/set1/a6

Other fox species do not reproduce as readily as the red fox, and are endangered in their native environments.

What is the smallest species of fox?	The Fennec Fox is the smallest species of fox. 	S09/data/set1/a6

[[u'one', u'CARDINAL'], [u'about 27', u'CARDINAL'], [u'only 12', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Vulpes', u'GPE']]

What is the smallest species of fox?	the Fennec Fox	S09/data/set1/a6

[[u'one', u'CARDINAL'], [u'about 27', u'CARDINAL'], [u'only 12', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Vulpes', u'GPE']]

What are female foxes called?	vixens	S09/data/set1/a6

[[u'one', u'CARDINAL'], [u'about 27', u'CARDINAL'], [u'only 12', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Vulpes', u'GPE']]

What are female foxes called?	vixens	S09/data/set1/a6

[[u'one', u'CARDINAL'], [u'about 27', u'CARDINAL'], [u'only 12', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Vulpes', u'GPE']]

What is caching food?	Caching is burying it for later consumption, usually under leaves, snow, or soil.	S09/data/set1/a6

[[u'one', u'CARDINAL'], [u'about 27', u'CARDINAL'], [u'only 12', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Vulpes', u'GPE']]

What is caching food?	burying it for later consumption	S09/data/set1/a6

[[u'one', u'CARDINAL'], [u'about 27', u'CARDINAL'], [u'only 12', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Vulpes', u'GPE']]

How many years ago did African people spread across 31 francophone African countries can speak French either as a first or second language?	2 years ago	S09/data/set5/a5

[[u'Nathan', u'GPE'], [u'Paris', u'GPE'], [u'2007', u'DATE'], [u'French', u'NORP'], [u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u'Africa', u'LOC'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'Abidjan', u'GPE'], [u"C\xc3\xb4te d'Ivoire", u'ORG'], [u'Abidjan', u'GPE'], [u'Katja Ploog', u'PERSON'], [u'CNRS Editions', u'PERSON'], [u'Paris', u'GPE'], [u'2002', u'DATE'], [u'Libreville', u'GPE'], [u'Gabon', u'GPE']]

In Old French, was the plural  for animal animals?	Yes	S09/data/set5/a5

In Old French, the plural for animal was animals.

Is catalan the only  official  language  of Andorra?	Yes	S09/data/set5/a5

no

In Belgium, however, is quatre-vingts universally used?	Yes	S09/data/set5/a5

In Belgium, however, quatre-vingts is universally used.

Where is it an official language?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a5

[[u'French', u'NORP'], [u'90 million', u'CARDINAL'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'190 million', u'CARDINAL'], [u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u'about another 200 million', u'CARDINAL'], [u'54', u'CARDINAL']]

What is widely used by the Lebanese, especially for administrative purposes?	French	S09/data/set5/a5

[[u'French', u'NORP'], [u'Lebanese', u'NORP'], [u'Arabic', u'PERSON']]

Are there also a variety of regional languages In addition?	Yes	S09/data/set5/a5

no

France signed the European Charter for what?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a5

  French (franÃ§ais, ) is a Romance language spoken around the world by around 90 million people as first language, by 190 million as second language, and by about another 200 million people as an acquired tongue, with significant speakers in 54 countries.

Is french language of 20  %?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a5

no

Is French language of Wallonia?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a5

yes

Are the prefixes en- and em- always nasalized ?	Yes	S09/data/set5/a5

no

Are French and German not official languages nor recognised minority languages in the flemish region , although there are a dozen municipalities with language facilities for French-speakers ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a5

no

Can the palatal nasal occur in word initial position ( e.g ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a5

The palatal nasal can occur in word initial position (e.g. gnon), but it is most frequently found in intervocalic, onset position or word-finally (e.g. montagne). *

How many years ago was the Luther Bible by Martin Luther printed?	475	S09/data/set5/a2

[[u'1534', u'DATE'], [u'the Luther Bible', u'ORG'], [u'Martin Luther', u'PERSON']]

Is german an inflected  language?	yes	S09/data/set5/a2

no

In Switzerland, is ÃŸ used at all?	no	S09/data/set5/a2

In Switzerland, ÃŸ is not used at all.

Are there two common  word  orders?	yes	S09/data/set5/a2

no

Are feminines declined in the singular?	no	S09/data/set5/a2

yes

Is german written using the Latin  alphabet?	Yes	S09/data/set5/a2

no

Was the Luther Bible by Martin Luther printed?	Yes	S09/data/set5/a2

no

Does a  tz indicate that the preceding vowel is short?	no	S09/data/set5/a2

yes

Are there 622,650 speakers of German In Canada?	Yes	S09/data/set5/a2

no

Are there also large populations of German ancestry In Mexico?	yes	S09/data/set5/a2

no

Would BundeslÃ¤nder not accept North Rhine Westphalia and Bavaria ?	yes	S09/data/set5/a2

Some state parliaments (BundeslÃ¤nder) would not accept it (North Rhine Westphalia and Bavaria).

Have adverbs of time to appear in the third place in the sentence , just after the predicate ?	Yes	S09/data/set5/a2

Except for emphasis, adverbs of time have to appear in the third place in the sentence, just after the predicate.

Do both sexes of giraffe have horns?	Yes	S09/data/set1/a5

no

Do both sexes of giraffe have horns?	yes	S09/data/set1/a5

no

What areas can giraffes inhabit?	savannas, grasslands, or open woodlands	S09/data/set1/a5

[]

What areas can giraffes inhabit?	inhabit savannas, grasslands, or open woodlands	S09/data/set1/a5

[]

What will a giraffe use to clean off any bugs that appear on its face?	extremely long tongue 	S09/data/set1/a5

[[u'the Roger Williams Park Zoo', u'FAC'], [u'Providence', u'GPE'], [u'Rhode Island A', u'LOC'], [u'about 45', u'CARDINAL']]

What will a giraffe use to clean off any bugs that appear on its face?	It's extremely long tongue	S09/data/set1/a5

[[u'the Roger Williams Park Zoo', u'FAC'], [u'Providence', u'GPE'], [u'Rhode Island A', u'LOC'], [u'about 45', u'CARDINAL']]

How do giraffes defend themselves?	with a powerful kick	S09/data/set1/a5


How do giraffes defend themselves?	With powerful kicks	S09/data/set1/a5


Do male giraffes weigh more than female giraffes?	Yes	S09/data/set1/a5

no

Do male giraffes weigh more than female giraffes?	yes	S09/data/set1/a5

no

Do male giraffes have larger horns than female giraffes?	Yes	S09/data/set1/a5

no

Do male giraffes have larger horns than female giraffes?	Yes	S09/data/set1/a5

no

Are male females generally taller than female giraffes?	Yes	S09/data/set1/a5

no

Is the SI unit for radioactivity named after him?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a9

no

Is the SI unit for radioactivity named after him?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a9

no

In what year did Henri Becquerel die?	1908	S09/data/set4/a9

  Antoine Henri Becquerel (December 15, 1852 ; August 25, 1908) was a French physicist, Nobel laureate, and one of the discoverers of radioactivity.

In what year did Henri Becquerel die?	August 24, 1908	S09/data/set4/a9

  Antoine Henri Becquerel (December 15, 1852 ; August 25, 1908) was a French physicist, Nobel laureate, and one of the discoverers of radioactivity.

Where was Henri Becquerel born?	 Paris 	S09/data/set4/a9

[[u'Becquerel', u'PERSON'], [u'Paris', u'GPE'], [u'Jean', u'PERSON'], [u'four', u'CARDINAL']]

Where was Henri Becquerel born?	Paris	S09/data/set4/a9

[[u'Becquerel', u'PERSON'], [u'Paris', u'GPE'], [u'Jean', u'PERSON'], [u'four', u'CARDINAL']]

In what year did Henri Becquerel win the Nobel Prize in Physics?	1903	S09/data/set4/a9

  Antoine Henri Becquerel (December 15, 1852 ; August 25, 1908) was a French physicist, Nobel laureate, and one of the discoverers of radioactivity.

In what year did Henri Becquerel win the Nobel Prize in Physics?	1903	S09/data/set4/a9

  Antoine Henri Becquerel (December 15, 1852 ; August 25, 1908) was a French physicist, Nobel laureate, and one of the discoverers of radioactivity.

Did Henri Becquerel intentionally discover radioactivity?	He discovered it accidentally	S09/data/set4/a9

no

If Henri Becquerel was alive today, how old would he have been?	157	S09/data/set4/a9

Becquerel was born in Paris into a family which, including he and his son Jean, produced four generations of scientists.

For how many years did Henri Becquerel live?	56	S09/data/set4/a9

Describing his method to the French Academy of Sciences on January 24, 1896, he said, One wraps a LumiÃ¨re photographic plate with a bromide emulsion in two sheets of very thick black paper, such that the plate does not become clouded upon being exposed to the sun for a day.

What was Henri Becquerel`s profession?	physisist	S09/data/set4/a9

[[u'Antoine Henri Becquerel', u'PERSON'], [u'December 15, 1852', u'DATE'], [u'August 25, 1908', u'DATE'], [u'French', u'NORP'], [u'Nobel', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'one', u'CARDINAL']]

How old was Henri Becquerel when he died?	53	S09/data/set4/a9

He died at the age of 55 in Le Croisic.

How many years ago was it when he became the third in his family to occupy the physics chair at the Musum National d`Histoire Naturelle?	117	S09/data/set4/a9

[[u'Becquerel', u'PERSON'], [u'Paris', u'GPE'], [u'Jean', u'PERSON'], [u'four', u'CARDINAL']]

In 1908, the year  of his death, was Becquerel elected Permanent Secretary  of the AcadÃ©mie  des  Sciences?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a9

In 1908, the year of his death, Becquerel was elected Permanent Secretary of the AcadÃ©mie des Sciences.

When was Henri Becquerel born?	December 15, 1852	S09/data/set4/a9

[[u'Becquerel', u'PERSON'], [u'Paris', u'GPE'], [u'Jean', u'PERSON'], [u'four', u'CARDINAL']]

Is it true that Becquerel wrapped a fluorescent substance in photographic plates?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a9

no

Becquerel wrapped a fluorescent substance in what?	photographic plates and black material	S09/data/set4/a9

  Antoine Henri Becquerel (December 15, 1852 ; August 25, 1908) was a French physicist, Nobel laureate, and one of the discoverers of radioactivity.

Is there a Becquerel crater on the Moon for radioactivity?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a9

no

Must â€¦ One conclude from these experiments that the phosphorescent substance in question emits rays which pass through the opaque paper and reduces silver salts ?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a9

â€¦ One must conclude from these experiments that the phosphorescent substance in question emits rays which pass through the opaque paper and reduces silver salts.  

What is Henri Becquerel?	Henri Becquerel was a famous physicist.	S09/data/set4/a9

[[u'Antoine Henri Becquerel', u'PERSON'], [u'December 15, 1852', u'DATE'], [u'August 25, 1908', u'DATE'], [u'French', u'NORP'], [u'Nobel', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'one', u'CARDINAL']]

Where is Henri Becquerel from?	Paris	S09/data/set4/a9

[]

What does Henri Becquerel do?	was a physisist	S09/data/set4/a9

[[u'the French Academy of Sciences', u'ORG'], [u'January 24, 1896', u'DATE'], [u'One', u'CARDINAL'], [u'two', u'CARDINAL'], [u'a day', u'DATE']]

What does Henri Becquerel do?	Henri Becquerel was a physicist.	S09/data/set4/a9

[[u'the French Academy of Sciences', u'ORG'], [u'January 24, 1896', u'DATE'], [u'One', u'CARDINAL'], [u'two', u'CARDINAL'], [u'a day', u'DATE']]

Did Newton reject the church's doctrine of the Trinity?	Newton may have rejected the church's doctrine of the Trinity.	S09/data/set4/a1

yes

Did Newton reject the church's doctrine of the Trinity?	Maybe	S09/data/set4/a1

yes

Was Newton admitted into Havard College?	Maybe, but it doesn't say so in the article	S09/data/set4/a1

no

When was Newton's date of birth recorded?	Christmas Day, Decembeer 25, 1642.	S09/data/set4/a1

[[u'Newton', u'ORG'], [u'England', u'GPE'], [u'Christmas Day', u'DATE'], [u'December 25, 1642', u'DATE']]

When was Newton's date of birth recorded?	his date of birth was recorded as Christmas Day, December 25, 1642	S09/data/set4/a1

[[u'Newton', u'ORG'], [u'England', u'GPE'], [u'Christmas Day', u'DATE'], [u'December 25, 1642', u'DATE']]

How many laws of motion did Netwon have?	Three	S09/data/set4/a1

[[u'the age of', u'DATE'], [u'eighteen', u'DATE']]

How many laws of motion did Netwon have?	Three	S09/data/set4/a1

[[u'the age of', u'DATE'], [u'eighteen', u'DATE']]

Who did Newton see as the master creator?	God	S09/data/set4/a1

[[u'Newton', u'PERSON']]

Who did Newton see as the master creator?	Newton saw God as the master creator whose existence could not be denied in the face of the grandeur of all creation	S09/data/set4/a1

[[u'Newton', u'PERSON']]

When did Netwon investigate the refraction of light	From 1670 to 1672	S09/data/set4/a1

[[u'second', u'ORDINAL']]

When did Netwon investigate the refraction of light	1670-1672	S09/data/set4/a1

[[u'second', u'ORDINAL']]

What principles did Newton explain for mechanics?	The principles of conservation of momentum and angular momentum	S09/data/set4/a1

[[u'Newton', u'PERSON']]

What principles did Newton explain for mechanics?	In mechanics, Newton enunciated the principles of conservation of momentum and angular momentum	S09/data/set4/a1

[[u'Newton', u'PERSON']]

Interaction with what man stirred up Newton's interest in alchemy?	Henry More	S09/data/set4/a1

  Sir Isaac Newton FRS ( ) (4 January 1643 â€“ March 31 1727)   OS: December 25 1642 â€“ March 20 1727   was an English physicist, mathematician, astronomer, natural philosopher, and alchemist.

Interaction with what man stirred up Newton's interest in alchemy?	The contact with the theosophist Henry More, revived his interest in alchemy	S09/data/set4/a1

  Sir Isaac Newton FRS ( ) (4 January 1643 â€“ March 31 1727)   OS: December 25 1642 â€“ March 20 1727   was an English physicist, mathematician, astronomer, natural philosopher, and alchemist.

What was Italian language`s profession?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

[[u'Italian', u'NORP'], [u'about 70 million', u'CARDINAL'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'about 50 million', u'CARDINAL'], [u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u'up to 120 million', u'CARDINAL']]

What is Italian language`s first name?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

[[u'Italian', u'NORP'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'Jacopo', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Italian', u'NORP'], [u'e.g.', u'LAW'], [u'Bajardo', u'GPE'], [u'Bojano', u'GPE'], [u'Joppolo', u'GPE'], [u'Jesolo', u'GPE'], [u'Jesi', u'GPE'], [u'Mar Jonio', u'PERSON'], [u'Mar Ionio', u'PERSON'], [u'the Ionian Sea', u'LOC']]

What is Italian language`s last name?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

[[u'Italian', u'NORP'], [u'about 70 million', u'CARDINAL'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'about 50 million', u'CARDINAL'], [u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u'up to 120 million', u'CARDINAL']]

How many offspring did Italian language have?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

[[u'Turkish', u'NORP'], [u'French', u'NORP'], [u'Italian', u'NORP']]

Where did Italian language die?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

[[u'Italian', u'NORP'], [u'about 70 million', u'CARDINAL'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'about 50 million', u'CARDINAL'], [u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u'up to 120 million', u'CARDINAL']]

Are geminate plosives and affricates realised as lengthened closures?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

no

Where is this letter silent?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

[]

Is Italian one of official four languages?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

no

Is it true that legge sulle fonti del diritto of 7?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

yes

Legge sulle fonti del diritto of what?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

Each of these foreign letters has an Italian equivalent spelling: gi for j, c or ch for k, u or v for w (depending on what sound it makes), s, ss, or cs for x, and i for y. Italian uses the acute accent over the letter E (as in perchÃ©, why/because) to indicate a front mid-closed vowel, and the grave accent (as in tÃ¨, tea) to indicate a front mid-open vowel.

Is it true that Italian retained the contrast between short consonants?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

no

Italian retained the contrast between what?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9


Is stress distinctive in most Romance languages?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

no

Are the speakers who use italian as a second or cultural language estimated at around 110-120 million ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

no

Are front/back vowel rules for C and G similar in French , Romanian , Spanish , and to some extent English ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

no

So can Italian language hear "istÃ nbul " or "ÃŒstanbul" ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

So we can hear "IstÃ nbul" or "ÃŒstanbul".

Will , the vowel sounds be pronounced separately) ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

Italian has few diphthongs, so most unfamiliar diphthongs that are heard in foreign words (in particular, those beginning with vowel "a", "e", or "o") will be assimilated as the corresponding diaeresis (i.e., the vowel sounds will be pronounced separately).  

Can Regional differences be recognized by various factors : the openness of vowels , the length of the consonants , and influence of the local dialect ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

Regional differences can be recognized by various factors: the openness of vowels, the length of the consonants, and influence of the local dialect (for example, annÃ  replaces andare in the area of Rome for the infinitive "to go").  

Give dictionaries the latter as an alternative pronunciation ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a9

Dictionaries give the latter as an alternative pronunciation.  

James Watt's improvements of what were fundamental to the changes wrought by the Industrial Revolution?	The steam engine.	S09/data/set4/a2

  James Watt (January 19 1736  August 19 1819) was a Scottish inventor and engineer whose improvements to the steam engine were fundamental to the changes wrought by the Industrial Revolution.   

James Watt's improvements of what were fundamental to the changes wrought by the Industrial Revolution?	steam engine	S09/data/set4/a2

  James Watt (January 19 1736  August 19 1819) was a Scottish inventor and engineer whose improvements to the steam engine were fundamental to the changes wrought by the Industrial Revolution.   

James Watt was born where?	Greenock, a seaport on the Firth of Clyde	S09/data/set4/a2

James Watt was born on 19th of January, 1736 in Greenock, a seaport on the Firth of Clyde.

What was the name of James Watt's mother?	Agnus Muirhead	S09/data/set4/a2

[[u'James Watt', u'PERSON'], [u'January 19 1736', u'DATE'], [u'August 19 1819', u'DATE'], [u'Scottish', u'NORP'], [u'the Industrial Revolution', u'ORG']]

What was the name of James Watt's mother?	Agnes Muirhead	S09/data/set4/a2

[[u'James Watt', u'PERSON'], [u'January 19 1736', u'DATE'], [u'August 19 1819', u'DATE'], [u'Scottish', u'NORP'], [u'the Industrial Revolution', u'ORG']]

How many of James Watt's children did not live to adulthood?	3	S09/data/set4/a2

[[u'Matthew Boulton', u'PERSON'], [u'Jonathan Hornblower', u'PERSON']]

How many of James Watt's children did not live to adulthood?	3	S09/data/set4/a2

[[u'Matthew Boulton', u'PERSON'], [u'Jonathan Hornblower', u'PERSON']]

James Watt ranked first among how many people in Charles Murray's survey of historiometry?	229	S09/data/set4/a2

Watt was ranked first, tying with Edison, among 229 significant figures in the history of technology by Charles Murray's survey of historiometry presented in his book Human Accomplishments.

James Watt ranked first among how many people in Charles Murray's survey of historiometry?	229	S09/data/set4/a2

Watt was ranked first, tying with Edison, among 229 significant figures in the history of technology by Charles Murray's survey of historiometry presented in his book Human Accomplishments.

In what year did James travel to Lodon to study instrument-making?	1753	S09/data/set4/a2

Watt, with his partner Matthew Boulton, battled against rival engineers such as Jonathan Hornblower who tried to develop engines which did not fall foul of his patents.

For how many years of James Watt's life was his mother alive?	17 years	S09/data/set4/a2

Watt attended school irregularly but instead he was mostly schooled at home by his mother.

What is James Watt most famous for?	Steam engine.	S09/data/set4/a2

[[u'James Watt', u'PERSON'], [u'January 19 1736', u'DATE'], [u'August 19 1819', u'DATE'], [u'Scottish', u'NORP'], [u'the Industrial Revolution', u'ORG']]

What was Japanese language`s profession?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a6

[[u'IPA', u'ORG'], [u'over 130 million', u'MONEY'], [u'Japan', u'GPE'], [u'Japanese', u'NORP']]

What is Japanese language`s first name?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a6

[[u'IPA', u'ORG'], [u'over 130 million', u'MONEY'], [u'Japan', u'GPE'], [u'Japanese', u'NORP']]

Is the basic sentence structure topic-comment?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a6

yes

Where are the circumstances complicated?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a6

[[u'IPA', u'ORG'], [u'over 130 million', u'MONEY'], [u'Japan', u'GPE'], [u'Japanese', u'NORP']]

Does the   form indicate a perfect tense?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a6

yes

Is or a conception that forms the counterpart of dialect?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a6

yes

Japanese borrowed a considerable number of what?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a6

Japanese personal pronouns are generally used only in situations requiring special emphasis as to who is doing what to whom.

Is japanese language in the island?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a6

yes

Is there a form of the language?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a6

yes

Are the several dialects of Kagoshima famous to speakers?	yes	S09/data/set5/a6

no

I.e "yamato words ") , which in scholarly contexts is sometimes referred to as ( or rarely , i.e "yamato words " -rrb- , which in scholarly contexts is sometimes referred to as -lrb- or rarely , vp ? ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a6

The original language of Japan, or at least the original language of a certain population that was ancestral to a significant portion of the historical and present Japanese nation, was the so-called  ( or infrequently , i.e. "Yamato words"), which in scholarly contexts is sometimes referred to as  ( or rarely , i.e. the  words").

Are japanese personal pronouns generally used only in situations requiring special emphasis as to who is doing what to whom ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a6

yes

: give "please Japanese language to Mr ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a6

For example, the  suffix ("Mr" "Mrs." or "Miss") is an example of honorific language.

Will a japanese person use vocabulary and inflections of the honorific register to refer to the in-group superior and Japanese language`s or Japanese language`s speech and actions ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a6

When speaking directly to one's superior in one's company or when speaking with other employees within one's company about a superior, a Japanese person will use vocabulary and inflections of the honorific register to refer to the in-group superior and his or her speech and actions.

Thus , can polite korean speech sound very presumptuous when translated verbatim into Japanese , as in korean Japanese language is acceptable and normal to say things like "our Mr ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a6

Thus, polite Korean speech can sound very presumptuous when translated verbatim into Japanese, as in Korean it is acceptable and normal to say things like "Our Mr. Company-President..." when communicating with a member of an out-group, which would be very inappropriate in a Japanese social context.

Is Lima the capital of Peru?	Yes.	S09/data/set3/a4

no

Is the Museum of Gold in Lima?	Yes.	S09/data/set3/a4

no

Does Lima have volleyball venues?	Yes.	S09/data/set3/a4

no

When was Lima founded?	January 18,1535.	S09/data/set3/a4

[[u'Lima', u'GPE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'Francisco Pizarro', u'PERSON'], [u'January 18, 1535', u'DATE'], [u'La Ciudad de', u'ORG'], [u'The City of Kings', u'GPE']]

Where is the Park of the Reserve located?	Near the downtown area.	S09/data/set3/a4

[[u'the Government Palace', u'FAC'], [u'the Plaza Mayor', u'FAC']]

What is a colectivo?	Automobiles that renders express service on some major roads of the Lima Metropolitan Area.	S09/data/set3/a4

[[u'Lima', u'GPE'], [u'Peru', u'GPE']]

Is the National University of San Marcos in Lima?	Yes.	S09/data/set3/a4

no

Has the San Lorenzo Megaport Project been completed?	No.	S09/data/set3/a4

>  The Lima Metro, a above ground mass transit system, is under construction and  one line has been completed while another six are scheduled for construction.

How many years ago was the Lima Stock Exchange the most profitable in the world?	Three	S09/data/set3/a4

[[u'2006', u'DATE'], [u'the Lima Stock Exchange', u'ORG']]

Is lima the capital  and  largest  city  of Peru?	Yes.	S09/data/set3/a4

no

Is The GDP  per capita in Lima $ 7,600  /  ref )?	Yes.	S09/data/set3/a4

no

The Spanish Crown named Pizarro governor of what?	Hemming.	S09/data/set3/a4

As the Spanish Crown had named Pizarro governor of the lands he conquered, Hemming, The conquest, p. 28.

Is it true that the ideas of the Enlightenment shaped the development of the city?	Yes.	S09/data/set3/a4

no

The ideas of the Enlightenment shaped the development of what?	the city, Lima	S09/data/set3/a4

In the later half of the 18th century, the ideas of the Enlightenment on public health and social control shaped the development of the city.

Is London the capital of the United Kingdom?	Yes	S09/data/set3/a1

no

Is London the capital of the United Kingdom?	Yes	S09/data/set3/a1

no

Does London's population draw from a wide range of religions?	Yes	S09/data/set3/a1

no

Does London's population draw from a wide range of religions?	Yes	S09/data/set3/a1

no

Over how many languages are spoken in London?	Over 300 languages are spoken in london	S09/data/set3/a1

London's population draws from a wide range of peoples, cultures, and religions, and over 300 languages are spoken within the city.  

Over how many languages are spoken in London?	Over 300	S09/data/set3/a1

London's population draws from a wide range of peoples, cultures, and religions, and over 300 languages are spoken within the city.  

What had the Anglo-Saxons created by the 600s?	By the 600s, the Anglo-Saxons had created a new settlement called Lundenwic.	S09/data/set3/a1

[[u'600s', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Anglo', u'NORP'], [u'Lundenwic', u'GPE'], [u'Roman city', u'GPE'], [u'Covent Garden', u'PERSON']]

What had the Anglo-Saxons created by the 600s?	a new settlement called Lundenwic	S09/data/set3/a1

[[u'600s', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Anglo', u'NORP'], [u'Lundenwic', u'GPE'], [u'Roman city', u'GPE'], [u'Covent Garden', u'PERSON']]

What city in the UK has been subjected to bouts of terrorism?	London has been subjected to bouts of terrorism.	S09/data/set3/a1

[[u'UK', u'GPE']]

What city in the UK has been subjected to bouts of terrorism?	London	S09/data/set3/a1

[[u'UK', u'GPE']]

What countries did James VI of Scotland unite?	James VI of Scotland united Scotland and England.	S09/data/set3/a1

[[u'15.8%),', u'PERCENT'], [u'Muslims', u'NORP'], [u'8.5%)', u'PERCENT'], [u'Hindus', u'NORP'], [u'4.1%)', u'PERCENT'], [u'Jews', u'NORP'], [u'2.1%),', u'PERCENT'], [u'Sikhs', u'NORP'], [u'1.5%),', u'PERCENT'], [u'Buddhists', u'NORP'], [u'0.8%)', u'PERCENT'], [u'0.5%)', u'PERCENT'], [u'8.7% of people', u'PERCENT'], [u'2001', u'DATE'], [u'Census', u'ORG']]

What countries did James VI of Scotland unite?	England and Scotland	S09/data/set3/a1

[[u'15.8%),', u'PERCENT'], [u'Muslims', u'NORP'], [u'8.5%)', u'PERCENT'], [u'Hindus', u'NORP'], [u'4.1%)', u'PERCENT'], [u'Jews', u'NORP'], [u'2.1%),', u'PERCENT'], [u'Sikhs', u'NORP'], [u'1.5%),', u'PERCENT'], [u'Buddhists', u'NORP'], [u'0.8%)', u'PERCENT'], [u'0.5%)', u'PERCENT'], [u'8.7% of people', u'PERCENT'], [u'2001', u'DATE'], [u'Census', u'ORG']]

How did civil wars affect England during the Middle Ages?	London remained relatively untouched	S09/data/set3/a1

  London ( ; ) is the capital of both England and the United Kingdom, and the largest urban area in the European Union. {{cite web|url= title=Largest EU City  An important settlement for two millennia, London's history goes back to its founding by the Romans.  

Are the strings of a classical lyre made of gut?	Yes	S09/data/set2/a10

no

Does a classical lyre have a sound-chest?	Yes	S09/data/set2/a10

no

Which part of the strings does the left hand touch?	The lower strings	S09/data/set2/a10

They also agree that neither the overall size of the instrument nor the number of strings on it have anything to do with its classification.

In which place is lyre still played?	North-eastern parts of Africa	S09/data/set2/a10

The instrument is still played in north-eastern parts of Africa.

Does a classical lyre have a fingerboard?	Yes	S09/data/set2/a10

no

Is a guitar played with a plectrum like a lyre?	Yes	S09/data/set2/a10

no

Was Faraday considered a gentleman?	no	S09/data/set4/a7

yes

Was Faraday considered a gentleman?	no	S09/data/set4/a7

yes

Who was a member of the Sandemanian sect of Christianity?	yes	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'James', u'PERSON'], [u'Sandemanian', u'NORP'], [u'Christianity', u'GPE']]

Who was a member of the Sandemanian sect of Christianity?	Faraday	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'James', u'PERSON'], [u'Sandemanian', u'NORP'], [u'Christianity', u'GPE']]

What did Joseph Henry likely discover?	self-induction	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Joseph Henry', u'PERSON'], [u'a few months earlier', u'DATE'], [u'Francesco Zantedeschi', u'PERSON'], [u'Italy', u'GPE'], [u'1829', u'DATE'], [u'1830', u'DATE']]

What did Joseph Henry likely discover?	self-induction	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Joseph Henry', u'PERSON'], [u'a few months earlier', u'DATE'], [u'Francesco Zantedeschi', u'PERSON'], [u'Italy', u'GPE'], [u'1829', u'DATE'], [u'1830', u'DATE']]

What did the University of Oxford grant Faraday?	a Doctor of Civil Law degree (honorary)	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'June of 1832', u'DATE'], [u'the University of', u'ORG'], [u'Oxford', u'GPE'], [u'Faraday', u'ORG']]

What did the University of Oxford grant Faraday?	Doctor of Civil Law degree (honorary)	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'June of 1832', u'DATE'], [u'the University of', u'ORG'], [u'Oxford', u'GPE'], [u'Faraday', u'ORG']]

Who was made to travel outside the coach?	Faraday	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Michael Faraday', u'PERSON'], [u'FRS (', u'ORG'], [u'September 22, 1791 \xe2\x80\x93', u'DATE'], [u'1867', u'DATE'], [u'English', u'LANGUAGE']]

Did Faraday construct the ancestor of modern power generators?	yes	S09/data/set4/a7

no

Did Faraday construct the ancestor of modern power generators?	yes	S09/data/set4/a7

no

Did Faraday lecture on education in 1854?	yes	S09/data/set4/a7

no

Did Faraday lecture on education in 1854?	yes	S09/data/set4/a7

no

Did Faraday discover the chemical substance benzene?	yes	S09/data/set4/a7

no

Did Faraday discover the chemical substance benzene?	yes	S09/data/set4/a7

no

Was Faraday born in England?	yes	S09/data/set4/a7

no

Was Faraday born in England?	yes	S09/data/set4/a7

no

What do some historians of science refer to Faraday as?	the best experimentalist in the history of science	S09/data/set4/a7

[]

What do some historians of science refer to Faraday as?	best experimentalist in the history of science	S09/data/set4/a7

[]

Who was the sponsor and mentor of Faraday?	John 'Mad Jack' Fuller	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Michael Faraday', u'PERSON'], [u'FRS (', u'ORG'], [u'September 22, 1791 \xe2\x80\x93', u'DATE'], [u'1867', u'DATE'], [u'English', u'LANGUAGE']]

Who was the sponsor and mentor of Faraday?	John 'Mad Jack' Fuller	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Michael Faraday', u'PERSON'], [u'FRS (', u'ORG'], [u'September 22, 1791 \xe2\x80\x93', u'DATE'], [u'1867', u'DATE'], [u'English', u'LANGUAGE']]

What did Faraday invent that is used almost universally in science laboratories?	the Bunsen burner	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Bunsen', u'GPE']]

What did Faraday invent that is used almost universally in science laboratories?	Bunsen burner	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Bunsen', u'GPE']]

Does the production of chemical weapons raise an ethical issue?	yes	S09/data/set4/a7

no

What was the Faraday effect first called?	diamagnetism	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Faraday', u'ORG'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL']]

What was the Faraday effect first called?	diamagnetism	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Faraday', u'ORG'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL']]

Can you meet someone through attending a church?	yes	S09/data/set4/a7

They met through attending the Sandemanian church.

What was Michael Faraday`s birthplace?	Newington Butts	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Michael Faraday', u'PERSON'], [u'FRS (', u'ORG'], [u'September 22, 1791 \xe2\x80\x93', u'DATE'], [u'1867', u'DATE'], [u'English', u'LANGUAGE']]

What was Michael Faraday`s profession?	chemist and physicist	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Michael Faraday', u'PERSON'], [u'FRS (', u'ORG'], [u'September 22, 1791 \xe2\x80\x93', u'DATE'], [u'1867', u'DATE'], [u'English', u'LANGUAGE']]

How many years ago did Faraday report on the first synthesis of compound make from carbon and chlorine , c 2 h 6 and c 2 h 4 ?	189	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Faraday', u'ORG']]

How many years ago was it when he discovered the phenomenon that he named diamagnetism , and what is now called the Faraday effect?	164	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'1845', u'DATE'], [u'Faraday', u'ORG']]

How many years ago was it when Faraday wrote a letter to The Times on the subject of the foul condition of the River Thames , which resulted in an oft-reprinted cartoon in Punch?	154	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Davy', u'ORG'], [u'1829', u'DATE'], [u'Faraday', u'ORG']]

How many years ago was it when he discovered that the optical properties of gold colloids differed from those of the corresponding bulk metal?	162	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'two', u'CARDINAL']]

Was education another area  of service  for Faraday?	yes	S09/data/set4/a7

no

Was faraday `s  earliest  chemical  work as an assistant  to Davy?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a7

no

Who died at his house at Hampton Court on August 25, 1867?	Faraday	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Twickenham Museum', u'ORG'], [u'Faraday', u'DATE'], [u'Faraday House', u'ORG'], [u'June 2006', u'DATE'], [u'Faraday', u'ORG'], [u'Hampton Court', u'ORG'], [u'August 25, 1867', u'DATE']]

When was Michael Faraday born?	September 22, 1791	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Michael Faraday', u'PERSON'], [u'John Watkins', u'PERSON'], [u'British Library', u'ORG'], [u'Michael Faraday', u'PERSON'], [u'Newington Butts', u'PERSON'], [u'South London', u'PERSON'], [u'England', u'GPE']]

Where did he serve two terms?	the Church of Scotland	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Michael Faraday', u'PERSON'], [u'FRS (', u'ORG'], [u'September 22, 1791 \xe2\x80\x93', u'DATE'], [u'1867', u'DATE'], [u'English', u'LANGUAGE']]

Who was born in Newington Butts, near present-day South London, England?	Michael Faraday	S09/data/set4/a7

[[u'Michael Faraday', u'PERSON'], [u'John Watkins', u'PERSON'], [u'British Library', u'ORG'], [u'Michael Faraday', u'PERSON'], [u'Newington Butts', u'PERSON'], [u'South London', u'PERSON'], [u'England', u'GPE']]

Is it true that institution formed the foundation of electric motor technology?	no	S09/data/set4/a7

yes

Institution formed the foundation of what?	modern electromagnetic technology	S09/data/set4/a7

He invented an early form of what was to become the Bunsen burner, which is used almost universally in science laboratories as a convenient source of heat.  

Who was Fort Nassau built by?	the Dutch	S09/data/set3/a2

[[u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Princeton', u'GPE'], [u'New Jersey', u'GPE'], [u'U.S.', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Lower Manhattan', u'GPE'], [u'New York City', u'GPE'], [u'U.S.', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Saxony', u'GPE'], [u'Germany', u'GPE'], [u'the Ore Mountains', u'LOC'], [u'the House of Orange-Nassau', u'ORG'], [u'Netherlands', u'GPE'], [u'Adolf', u'PERSON'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Johan Willem Friso', u'PERSON'], [u'Orange-Nassau', u'ORG'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Maurice', u'PERSON'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Sophia', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Willem', u'PERSON'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'William Henry', u'PERSON'], [u'4th', u'ORDINAL'], [u'Earl', u'PERSON'], [u'John Maurice', u'PERSON'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Adolf', u'PERSON'], [u'Nassau-Weilburg', u'ORG'], [u'Adolphe', u'PERSON'], [u'Grand Duke of Luxembourg', u'ORG'], [u'Grand Duke of Luxembourg', u'ORG'], [u'Marie-Ad\xe9la\xefde', u'PERSON'], [u'Grand Duchess of Luxembourg', u'ORG'], [u'Charlotte', u'GPE'], [u'Grand Duchess of Luxembourg', u'ORG'], [u'Jean', u'PERSON'], [u'Grand Duke of Luxembourg', u'ORG'], [u'Henri', u'PERSON'], [u'Grand Duke of Luxembourg', u'ORG'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'William Senior', u'PERSON'], [u'House of Nassau', u'ORG'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Robert Fulton', u'PERSON'], [u'Manhattan', u'GPE'], [u'Brooklyn', u'GPE'], [u'U.S.', u'GPE'], [u'New York', u'GPE'], [u'1814', u'DATE'], [u'Nassau Hall', u'PERSON'], [u'Princeton University', u'ORG'], [u'USA', u'GPE'], [u'Second Continental Congress', u'ORG'], [u'Hesse', u'PERSON'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Germany', u'GPE'], [u'Fort Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Dutch', u'NORP'], [u'the 17th century', u'DATE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'the United States', u'GPE'], [u'the United Kingdom', u'GPE'], [u'US', u'GPE'], [u'Polaris', u'ORG'], [u'the Holy Loch', u'WORK_OF_ART'], [u'Glasgow', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'two-year', u'DATE'], [u'Nassau County', u'GPE'], [u'New York', u'GPE'], [u'USA *', u'ORG'], [u'the United Kingdom', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau Sound', u'PERSON'], [u'U.S.', u'GPE'], [u'Florida', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Uniondale', u'GPE'], [u'New York', u'GPE'], [u'USA *', u'ORG'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'a United States', u'GPE'], [u'Navy', u'ORG'], [u'USS', u'ORG'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'a United States', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'German', u'NORP'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'three', u'CARDINAL']]

What is Nassau Coliseum?	an arena in Uniondale, New York, USA	S09/data/set3/a2

[[u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u' ', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Germany', u'GPE'], [u'Rhineland-Palatinate', u'GPE'], [u'AD 915', u'DATE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'the House of', u'ORG'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Duchy', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'German', u'NORP'], [u'Hesse-Nassau', u'PERSON'], [u'Prussian', u'NORP'], [u'Baarle-', u'GPE'], [u'Netherlands', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Germany', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Bahamas', u'GPE'], [u'Bahamas', u'GPE'], [u'New Providence', u'GPE']]

What was the Dead or Alive 4 fighting arena modeled after?	a Magnetic Accelerator Cannon station from Halo 2	S09/data/set3/a2

[[u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u' ', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Germany', u'GPE'], [u'Rhineland-Palatinate', u'GPE'], [u'AD 915', u'DATE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'the House of', u'ORG'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Duchy', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'German', u'NORP'], [u'Hesse-Nassau', u'PERSON'], [u'Prussian', u'NORP'], [u'Baarle-', u'GPE'], [u'Netherlands', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Germany', u'GPE'], [u'Nassau', u'GPE'], [u'Bahamas', u'GPE'], [u'Bahamas', u'GPE'], [u'New Providence', u'GPE']]

Is Nassau County named after a German town?	yes	S09/data/set3/a2

no

Does the United States have a base near Glasgow?	yes	S09/data/set3/a2

no

Was Tesla hired by Edison?	Yes	S09/data/set4/a3

no

Was Tesla hired by Edison?	yes	S09/data/set4/a3

no

When did Tesla demonstrate wireless communication (radio)?	1893	S09/data/set4/a3

[[u'50th', u'ORDINAL'], [u'1906', u'DATE'], [u'Tesla', u'PERSON'], [u'200', u'CARDINAL'], [u'150', u'CARDINAL'], [u'16,000 rpm', u'MONEY']]

When did Tesla demonstrate wireless communication (radio)?	1893	S09/data/set4/a3

[[u'50th', u'ORDINAL'], [u'1906', u'DATE'], [u'Tesla', u'PERSON'], [u'200', u'CARDINAL'], [u'150', u'CARDINAL'], [u'16,000 rpm', u'MONEY']]

What is the SI unit measuring magnetic flux density or magnetic induction?	the tesla	S09/data/set4/a3

[[u'SI', u'ORG'], [u'B\\', u'ORG'], [u'the Conf\xc3\xa9rence G\xc3\xa9n\xc3\xa9rale des Poids', u'ORG'], [u'Mesures', u'GPE'], [u'Paris', u'GPE'], [u'1960', u'DATE']]

What is the SI unit measuring magnetic flux density or magnetic induction?	the tesla	S09/data/set4/a3

[[u'SI', u'ORG'], [u'B\\', u'ORG'], [u'the Conf\xc3\xa9rence G\xc3\xa9n\xc3\xa9rale des Poids', u'ORG'], [u'Mesures', u'GPE'], [u'Paris', u'GPE'], [u'1960', u'DATE']]

What type of current did Tesla invent?	AC	S09/data/set4/a3

[[u'Tesla', u'GPE']]

Who was the victor of the "War of Currents"?	Tesla	S09/data/set4/a3

[[u'Times of Nikola Tesla', u'ORG'], [u'1893', u'DATE'], [u'the "War of Currents"', u'EVENT'], [u'America', u'GPE']]

Who was the victor of the "War of Currents"?	Nikola Tesla	S09/data/set4/a3

[[u'Times of Nikola Tesla', u'ORG'], [u'1893', u'DATE'], [u'the "War of Currents"', u'EVENT'], [u'America', u'GPE']]

Where did Tesla study electrical engineering?	the Austrian Polytechnic in Graz 	S09/data/set4/a3

[[u'the Austrian Polytechnic', u'ORG'], [u'1875', u'DATE']]

Where did Tesla study electrical engineering?	Austrian Polytechnic in Graz	S09/data/set4/a3

[[u'the Austrian Polytechnic', u'ORG'], [u'1875', u'DATE']]

Does Ottawa sit on the Ottowa River?	Yes	S09/data/set3/a5

no

What is Ottawa's population?	1,190,982	S09/data/set3/a5

[[u'1,190,982', u'CARDINAL'], [u' Ottawa is', u'QUANTITY'], [u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u'Ontario', u'GPE']]

What are Ottawa's primary industries?	Logging and lumber	S09/data/set3/a5

[[u'  ', u'GPE'], [u'Ottawa', u'GPE'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'fourth', u'ORDINAL']]

What is Ottawa's junior ice hockey team?	the Ottawa 67's	S09/data/set3/a5

[[u'Ottawa', u'GPE'], [u"the Ottawa 67's", u'ORG'], [u'the Ontario Hockey League', u'ORG']]

What is Ottawa's major league hockey team?	the Ottawa Senators	S09/data/set3/a5

[[u'  ', u'GPE'], [u'Ottawa', u'GPE'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'fourth', u'ORDINAL']]

What are Carleton University's athletic teams called?	Carleton Ravens	S09/data/set3/a5

[[u'Odawa', u'ORG'], [u'Algonquin', u'ORG'], [u'the Kichi Sibi', u'FAC'], [u'Kichissippi', u'ORG'], [u'Great River', u'LOC']]

Is Ottawa colder than Moscow in January?	Yes	S09/data/set3/a5

no

Is Ottawa on a river?	yes	S09/data/set3/a5

no

Is Ottawa on a river?	yes	S09/data/set3/a5

no

Who is the mayor of Ottawa?	Larry O'Brien	S09/data/set3/a5

[[u'  ', u'GPE'], [u'Ottawa', u'GPE'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'fourth', u'ORDINAL']]

Who is the mayor of Ottawa?	Larry O'Brien	S09/data/set3/a5

[[u'  ', u'GPE'], [u'Ottawa', u'GPE'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'fourth', u'ORDINAL']]

How many townships are in Ottawa?	eleven	S09/data/set3/a5

[[u'Ottawa', u'GPE'], [u'the Ottawa Fury', u'ORG'], [u'W-League', u'ORG'], [u'USL Premier Development League', u'ORG']]

How many townships are in Ottawa?	eleven	S09/data/set3/a5

[[u'Ottawa', u'GPE'], [u'the Ottawa Fury', u'ORG'], [u'W-League', u'ORG'], [u'USL Premier Development League', u'ORG']]

What's the main highway in Ottawa?	Highway 417, The Queensway	S09/data/set3/a5

[[u'  ', u'GPE'], [u'Ottawa', u'GPE'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'fourth', u'ORDINAL']]

What's the main highway in Ottawa?	provinical Highway 417	S09/data/set3/a5

[[u'  ', u'GPE'], [u'Ottawa', u'GPE'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'fourth', u'ORDINAL']]

What was Ottawa's name in 1850?	Bytown	S09/data/set3/a5

[[u'  ', u'GPE'], [u'Ottawa', u'GPE'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'fourth', u'ORDINAL']]

What was Ottawa's name in 1850?	Bytown	S09/data/set3/a5

[[u'  ', u'GPE'], [u'Ottawa', u'GPE'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'fourth', u'ORDINAL']]

Based on the average, in what year will the next small tremor occur in Ottawa?	2009	S09/data/set3/a5

  Ottawa ( or sometimes ) is the capital of Canada and the country's fourth largest municipality.

Based on the average, in what year will the next small tremor occur in Ottawa?	2009	S09/data/set3/a5

  Ottawa ( or sometimes ) is the capital of Canada and the country's fourth largest municipality.

Where were immigrants from in the 1800s?	Irish	S09/data/set3/a5

[[u'  ', u'GPE'], [u'Ottawa', u'GPE'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'fourth', u'ORDINAL']]

Where were immigrants from in the 1800s?	Ireland	S09/data/set3/a5

[[u'  ', u'GPE'], [u'Ottawa', u'GPE'], [u'Canada', u'GPE'], [u'fourth', u'ORDINAL']]

Does the giant otter live in South America?	Yes	S09/data/set1/a7

no

Does the giant otter live in South America?	yes	S09/data/set1/a7

no

Do otters have claws?	Yes	S09/data/set1/a7

no

Do otters have claws?	yes	S09/data/set1/a7

no

Do otters eat fish?	Yes	S09/data/set1/a7

no

Do otters eat fish?	yes	S09/data/set1/a7

no

What is an otter's den called?	A holt	S09/data/set1/a7

[]

What is an otter's den called?	holt	S09/data/set1/a7

[]

Where do sea otters live?	Beside water	S09/data/set1/a7

[]

Where do sea otters live?	Pacific coast of North America	S09/data/set1/a7

[]

Why are otters vulnerable to prey depletion?	Prey-dependence	S09/data/set1/a7

Prey-dependence leaves otters very vulnerable to prey depletion.

Why are otters vulnerable to prey depletion?	prey-dependency	S09/data/set1/a7

Prey-dependence leaves otters very vulnerable to prey depletion.

Do otters enjoy playing?	Yes	S09/data/set1/a7

no

Do otters enjoy playing?	yes	S09/data/set1/a7

no

Is the otter in the same family as the badger?	Yes	S09/data/set1/a7

no

Is the otter in the same family as the badger?	yes	S09/data/set1/a7

no

Are there any cities named Santiago in the United States?	yes	S09/data/set3/a6

no

Are there any cities named Santiago in the United States?	Yes	S09/data/set3/a6

no

Was Santiago the name of an indie/punk band?	yes	S09/data/set3/a6

no

Was Santiago the name of an indie/punk band?	Yes	S09/data/set3/a6

no

Is Santiago a name in Spanish?	yes	S09/data/set3/a6

no

Is Santiago a name in Spanish?	Yes	S09/data/set3/a6

no

What is the origin of the name Santiago?	Spanish for St. James	S09/data/set3/a6

[[u' ', u'GPE'], [u'Santiago', u'GPE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'St. James', u'FAC'], [u'James', u'PERSON']]

What is the origin of the name Santiago?	sanit + iago, James	S09/data/set3/a6

[[u' ', u'GPE'], [u'Santiago', u'GPE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'St. James', u'FAC'], [u'James', u'PERSON']]

Who has released an album or song named Santiago?	The Chieftains; Loreena McKennitt	S09/data/set3/a6

[[u' ', u'GPE'], [u'Santiago', u'GPE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'St. James', u'FAC'], [u'James', u'PERSON']]

Who has released an album or song named Santiago?	The Chieftains and Loreena McKennitt	S09/data/set3/a6

[[u' ', u'GPE'], [u'Santiago', u'GPE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'St. James', u'FAC'], [u'James', u'PERSON']]

What is the Order of Santiago?	a Spanish knightly order	S09/data/set3/a6

[[u' ', u'GPE'], [u'Santiago', u'GPE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'St. James', u'FAC'], [u'James', u'PERSON']]

What is the Order of Santiago?	a Spanish Knightly order	S09/data/set3/a6

[[u' ', u'GPE'], [u'Santiago', u'GPE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'St. James', u'FAC'], [u'James', u'PERSON']]

What notable people have been named Santiago?	Benito Santiago, Hugo Santiago, Joey Santiago, Liliana Santiago, Rafael Santiago Maria, Santiago Caballero, Santiago Cabrera; James, son of Zebedee	S09/data/set3/a6

[[u' ', u'GPE'], [u'Santiago', u'GPE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'St. James', u'FAC'], [u'James', u'PERSON']]

What notable people have been named Santiago?	Benito, Hugo, and others	S09/data/set3/a6

[[u' ', u'GPE'], [u'Santiago', u'GPE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'St. James', u'FAC'], [u'James', u'PERSON']]

What fictional stories include a main character named Santiago?	Gears of War, Rainbow Six: Covert Operations Essentials, Death Foretold by Gabriel GarcÃ­a MÃ¡rquez, Ernest Hemingway's The Old Man and the Sea, the television series Babylon 5, Anne Rice's novel Interview with the Vampire, aulo Coelho's The Alchemist (novel), the television show Friday Night Lights	S09/data/set3/a6

[[u' ', u'GPE'], [u'Santiago', u'GPE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'St. James', u'FAC'], [u'James', u'PERSON']]

What fictional stories include a main character named Santiago?	Interview with the Vampire, The Alchemist, and others	S09/data/set3/a6

[[u' ', u'GPE'], [u'Santiago', u'GPE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'St. James', u'FAC'], [u'James', u'PERSON']]

Is Santiago the national capital of a country?	Yes	S09/data/set3/a6

no

Is santiago Spanish for St. James  ( from santo ,  saint  +  iago ,  James  )?	Yes	S09/data/set3/a6

no

What is Santiago?	Santiago is Spanish for St. James. It is also the name of places in Argentina, Brazil, Cape Verde, Chile, Colombia, Costa Rica, Cuba, the Dominican Republic, Ecuador, Guatemala, Jamaica, Mexico, Nicaragua, Panama, Paraguay, Peru, the Philippines, Portugal, Spain, the United States, Venezuela, and the Amazon. It is also the name of a baseball catcher, a film director, a guitarist, an economist, a footballer, a DJ, an actor, and James, son of Zebedee. Fictional people with this name include a character from Gears of War, a character from Chronicle of a Death Foretold, a character in Old Man and the Sea, a character in Babylon 5, a character in Interview with the Vampire, the main character of The Alchemist, and a character on Friday Night Lights. There has also been a battle of Santiago de Cuba, a couple of bands named Santiago, an Order of Santiago, and "Santiago" as a shortened form of the Reconquista battle cry.	S09/data/set3/a6

[[u' ', u'GPE'], [u'Santiago', u'GPE'], [u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'St. James', u'FAC'], [u'James', u'PERSON']]

Are countries without in red?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

no

However, is English the official  language?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

  Spanish ( ) or Castilian (castellano) is a Romance language that originated in northern Spain, and gradually spread in the Kingdom of Castile and evolved into the principal language of government and trade.

Are most Spanish  speakers in Latin America?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

yes

Are countries where is a regionalism in green?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

no

The deeper  the blue  is, is the more  predominant?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

  Spanish ( ) or Castilian (castellano) is a Romance language that originated in northern Spain, and gradually spread in the Kingdom of Castile and evolved into the principal language of government and trade.

Are these marked with an asterisk  ( *  )?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

no

Did the language lose its official status?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

yes

Where do about 400 million people speak Spanish?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

[[u'about 400 million', u'CARDINAL'], [u'Spanish', u'LANGUAGE'], [u'second', u'ORDINAL'], [u'third', u'ORDINAL']]

What kind of instrument is the spanish language?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

[[u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'the European Union', u'ORG']]

Is the lexical similarity with Italian estimated at 82%?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

no

Is spanish an official language of the European Union?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

yes

What is an official language of the European Union?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

[[u'Spanish', u'NORP'], [u'one', u'CARDINAL'], [u'the United Nations', u'ORG'], [u'the European Union', u'ORG'], [u'the Organization of American States', u'ORG'], [u'the Organization of Ibero-American States', u'ORG'], [u'the African Union', u'ORG'], [u'the Union of South American Nations', u'ORG'], [u'the Latin Union', u'ORG'], [u'Caricom', u'ORG'], [u'the North American Free Trade Agreement', u'ORG'], [u'the Antarctic Treaty', u'ORG']]

Is it true that mexico contains the largest population of Spanish speakers?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

yes

Mexico contains the largest population of what?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

When it was presented to Isabel de Castilla, she asked, "What do I want a work like this for, if I already know the language?", to which he replied, "Your highness, the language is the instrument of the Empire."

Is this phenomenon notable in Brazil?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

yes

Is spanish one of the official languages?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

no

Is universidad de MÃ©xico Instituto Cervantes Spanish language of Spain?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

no

Is spanish language of the European Union?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

yes

Pasan en consecuencia , las palabras que comienzan por estas dos letras , o que las contienen , a alfabetizarse en los lugares que les corresponden dentro de la c y de la l , respectivamente ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

En consecuencia, las palabras que comienzan por estas dos letras, o que las contienen, pasan a alfabetizarse en los lugares que les corresponden dentro de la c y de la l, respectivamente.

Allow the common features of the writing systems of the Romance languages for a greater amount of interlingual reading comprehension than oral communication would ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a8

The common features of the writing systems of the Romance languages allow for a greater amount of interlingual reading comprehension than oral communication would

What was Swahili language`s profession?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a4

[[u'Swahili', u'GPE'], [u'Kiswahili', u'PERSON'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'Swahili', u'GPE'], [u'Waswahili', u'GPE'], [u'the Indian Ocean', u'LOC'], [u'Somalia', u'GPE'], [u'Mozambique', u'GPE'], [u'the Comoros Islands', u'ORG']]

How many years ago was an interterritorial conference held at Mombasa ?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a4

[[u'June 1928', u'DATE'], [u'Mombasa', u'GPE'], [u'Zanzibar', u'GPE'], [u'Kiunguja', u'PERSON'], [u'Swahili', u'GPE']]

What is Swahili language`s last name?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a4

[[u'Swahili', u'GPE'], [u'Kiswahili', u'PERSON'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'Swahili', u'GPE'], [u'Waswahili', u'GPE'], [u'the Indian Ocean', u'LOC'], [u'Somalia', u'GPE'], [u'Mozambique', u'GPE'], [u'the Comoros Islands', u'ORG']]

How many years ago was it when the rulers of Zanzibar organized trading expeditions into the interior of the mainland , up to the various lakes in the continent `s Great Rift Valley?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a4

[]

What is Swahili language`s first name?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a4

[[u'Swahili', u'GPE'], [u'Kiswahili', u'PERSON'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'Swahili', u'GPE'], [u'Waswahili', u'GPE'], [u'the Indian Ocean', u'LOC'], [u'Somalia', u'GPE'], [u'Mozambique', u'GPE'], [u'the Comoros Islands', u'ORG']]

Where did Swahili language die?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a4

[[u'Pleiades', u'ORG']]

Has swahili no diphthongs?	No	S09/data/set5/a4

Swahili has no diphthongs; in vowel combinations, each vowel is pronounced separately.

Is a third  prefix the object  prefix?	Yes	S09/data/set5/a4

no

When is /ref>	NULL	S09/data/set5/a4

[[u'Swahili', u'GPE'], [u'Kiswahili', u'PERSON'], [u'first', u'ORDINAL'], [u'Swahili', u'GPE'], [u'Waswahili', u'GPE'], [u'the Indian Ocean', u'LOC'], [u'Somalia', u'GPE'], [u'Mozambique', u'GPE'], [u'the Comoros Islands', u'ORG']]

Swahili unusual?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a4

  Swahili (Kiswahili) is the first language of the Swahili people (Waswahili), who inhabit several large stretches of the Indian Ocean coastline from southern Somalia to northern Mozambique, including the Comoros Islands.

Where does swahili grammar arrange nouns?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a4

[[u'Swahili', u'GPE'], [u'Bantu', u'GPE'], [u'Swahili', u'GPE']]

What was the only good candidate in these two colonies?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a4

[[u'Swahili', u'GPE'], [u'two', u'CARDINAL']]

Do some writers mark aspirated consonants?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a4

yes

Was one key step in spreading Swahili to create a standard written language?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a4

no

Are there today more speakers in Kenya of the Somali coast?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a4

no

The pronunciation of the phoneme / u / stands between what?	NULL	S09/data/set5/a4

The pronunciation of the phoneme /u/ stands between International Phonetic Alphabet u and oâ†’ ~Éµ (as found in Italian, for example).

Does the Australian Black Swan have white feathers on its wings?	yes	S09/data/set1/a10

no

Does the Australian Black Swan have white feathers on its wings?	Yes	S09/data/set1/a10

no

Do swans belong to the family Anatidae?	yes	S09/data/set1/a10

no

Do swans belong to the family Anatidae?	Yes	S09/data/set1/a10

no

Can black swans swim with only one leg?	yes	S09/data/set1/a10

  Swans are birds of the family Anatidae, which also includes geese and ducks.
